--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://www.cmct.cc
影片压制：死亡骑士
字幕调校：死亡骑士 小石头 悠悠 协调：死亡骑士　招募Q号：76846146
投资理财的世界
The world of investing
可会像原始丛林一样
can be a jungle.
牛市 熊市
Bulls. Bears.
转角就遇风险
Danger at every turn.
正因为如此 我们斯特拉顿·奥克蒙公司
That's why we at Stratton Oakmont
很骄傲地宣布 我们是最好的
pride ourselves on being the best.
训练精良的职业经理人 引领您
Trained professionals to guide you
安全穿越这理财的丛林猛兽
through the financial wilderness.
斯特拉顿·奥克蒙
Stratton Oakmont.
稳定
Stability.
廉明
Integrity.
自豪
Pride.
一
One!
二
Two!
三
Three!
第一个丢中靶心的混蛋 可以领走这两万五
Twenty-five grand to the first cocksucker to nail a bull's-eye!
好了 开始
Come on! Let's go!
一
One!
二
Two!
三
Three!
我叫乔丹·贝尔福特
My name is Jordan Belfort.
不是那家伙
Not him.
这边 这才对
Me. That's right.
以前我是中产阶级的一份子
I'm a former member of the middle class
在皇后区海湾边碧沙区的小公寓长大 父母都是会计师
raised by two accountants in a tiny apartment in Bayside,Queens.
26岁那年
The year I turned 26,
我作为自己成立的 股票经理公司的老总
as the head of my own brokerage firm,
一年挣了4900万
I made $49 million,
这说来还挺窝火的 因为还差300万就正好一礼拜一百万了
which really pissed me off because it was three shy of a million a week.
不对 不对 我的法拉利是白色的
No,no,no. My Ferrari was white,
就跟《迈阿密风云》里面唐·约翰逊的一样 不是红的
like Don Johnson's in Miami Vice. Not red.
看见那大到无边的别墅了没？
See that humongous estate down there?
我的房子
That's my house.
我老婆 娜奥米
My wife,Naomi,
她是布鲁克林湾岭的公爵夫人
the Duchess of Bay Ridge,Brooklyn,
以前是模特 做过米勒清啤广告的
a former model and Miller Lite girl.
没错
Yeah.
刚才在法拉利里帮我口交的 就是她
She was the one with my cock in her mouth in the Ferrari.
所以 把你刚从裤子里掏出的鸡巴 收回去吧
So put your dick back in your pants.
除了娜奥米和我们倆的 两个可爱的孩子
In addition to Naomi and my two perfect kids,
我坐拥一座豪宅 一架私人飞机
I own a mansion,private jet,
六辆车 三匹马
six cars,three horses,
两处度假屋
two vacation homes,
以及一艘170尺长的游艇
and a 170-foot yacht.
并且我还豪赌成性
I also gamble like a degenerate.
豪饮成瘾
I drink like a fish.
一个礼拜招妓五六次
I fuck hookers maybe five,six times a week.
三所不同的联邦机构都盯着我准备起诉
I have three different federal agencies looking to indict me.
噢 没错 我爱死嗑药了
Oh,yeah,and I love drugs.
好
Okay.
- 再来一次 - 爽
- One more round. - Oh,yeah.
- 哦 你喜欢这样 - 是的
- Oh,you like it? - Yeah.
当天晚些时候
拉起来 拉起来 这样会坠机的我的天哪 快拉起来
Pull up. Pull up! We're gonna crash,for Christ sake!
放松
Relax!
放 轻松
Just relax.
- 你还好吧？- 啊 我没事
- You okay? - Yeah,I'm all right.
干得漂亮
Good job.
进门注意安全啊
You get in there safe,all right?
下次咱继续 老兄
Till the next time,brother.
下回见啊
Till next time.
没错 我每天都要吃海量各种药
Yup,on a daily basis I consume enough drugs
这些药简直都够 整个曼哈顿 长岛 皇后区吃一个月了
to sedate Manhattan,Long Island and Queens for a month.
好了 乔丹先生
Okay,Mr. Jordan.
安眠酮我一天吃个10到15次 治背痛嘛（催眠药 类似K粉）
I take Quaaludes 10 to 15 times a day for my "back pain,"
吃苯丙胺 帮助集中注意力 （一种精神兴奋药物）
Adderall to stay focused,
吃点阿普唑仑抗焦虑 抽点大麻来放松
Xanax to take the edge off,pot to mellow me out,
再来点可卡因把自己再叫醒 最后是吗啡
cocaine to wake me back up again and morphine,well,
因为它简直就是赞
because it's awesome.
早上好 布雷克
Good morning,Nathan.
但这世界上所有的药里
But of all the drugs under God's blue heaven,
有一种绝对是我的最爱
there is one that is my absolute favorite.
看
You see,
抽够这玩意 会让你战无不胜
enough of this shit'll make you invincible.
足以征服世界
Able to conquer the world,
把敌人生吞活剥
and eviscerate your enemies.
我说的还不是这个
And I'm not talking about this.
我说的是这个
I'm talking about this.
你看 金钱不仅仅可以买来更好的生活
See,money doesn't just buy you a better life,
更好的食物 车子 妹子
better food,better cars,better pussy.
它还能让你成为更好的人
It also makes you a better person.
你可以捐大笔钞票 给自己喜欢的政党和教堂
You can give generously to the church or political party of your choice.
花钱甚至能挽救濒危动物 比如斑点猫头鹰
You can save the fucking spotted owl with money.
我一直都想当个有钱人倒回去一点说吧
I always wanted to be rich. So let me go back.
当时我22岁 新婚不久
I'm 22 years old,newly married,
已经是个视财如命的小混账了
and already a money-crazed little shit.
那么我该怎么办呢？
So what do I do?
当然是去这世上唯一一个
I go to the one place on Earth
跟我志同道合野心勃勃的地方了
that befit my high-minded ambitions.
我爱你
I love you.
你的位置比池塘里的烂泥还下贱
You are lower than pond scum.
有问题吗？
You got a problem with that,
乔丹？
Jordan?
没有 完全没问题
No. No problem at all.
很好 因为你就会是这样
Good. Because that is what you are.
池塘里的泥
Pond scum.
你的职位叫"联系员"
Your job is connector,
也就是说 你一天要打至少500个电话
which means that you'll be dialing the phone over 500 times a day
努力把我和有钱老板们联系住
trying to connect me with wealthy business owners.
并且 在你通过证券执照考试之前
And until you pass your Series 7,
你就得整天干这个 坐
that is all you're gonna fucking be doing. Sit.
坐下
Sit!
顺便告诉你 去年我年薪超过了30万
Now just so you know,last year I made over $300,000.
而你的顶头上司 他年薪超过百万
The other guy you'll be working for,he made over a million.
一百万美元？
A million dollars?
想都不用想这家伙肯定是个蠢货
I could only imagine what a douchebag that guy must be.
- 乔丹·贝尔福特？- 是我
- Jordan Belfort. - Yes,Sir.
- 我是马克·汉纳 - 很高兴见到你
- Mark Hanna. - A pleasure to meet you.
幸会啊 看得出来你已经见过我们部门的混蛋头了
And you as well. I see you've already met the village asshole.
微笑 拨电话去
Smile and dial.
不到一点钟不要抬头
And don't pick up your fucking head until 1:00.
嘿 去他的
Hey,fuck him.
我是高级经理人 他只是个小卒
I'm the senior broker here. He's just a worthless piker.
你怎么不帮我吹箫呢 汉纳？
Why don't you blow me,Hanna?
说 你在面试的时候是不是真的 卖出了支股票？
Now did you really pitch a stock in your job interview?
我总得做点什么来脱颖而出啊 没错 先生
I had to do something to stand out. Right,Sir?
这我太他妈的喜欢了
I fucking love that.
- 今天午饭我们一起 - 好
- Lunch. Today. - Yeah.
我们不能在九点半整开始打电话
We don't start dialing at 9:30
是因为 我们的客户已经开始接别人的了
because our clients are already answering the phone.
三 二 一
Three. Two. One.
干起来吧
Let's fuck!
想知道钱的声音是怎样的吗？
You want to know what money sounds like?
去华尔街的交易现场看看
Go to a trading floor on Wall Street.
操这个干那个的
"Fuck" this,"shit" that.
婊子 鸡巴 屁眼
"Cunt," "cock," "asshole. ".
真不敢相信这帮人是怎么说话的
I couldn't believe how these guys talked to each other.
几秒钟我就不可自拔了
I was hooked in seconds.
简直像直接注射肾上腺素
It was like mainlining adrenaline.
白痴 看今天的股价涨了多少了
Yeah. Fuckface,look at where the stock's at today,huh?
你这混蛋 你不可能买到股价44
You motherfucker,you can't get any at 44...
- 狗日的快给我打电话 - 抱歉
- Pick up the cocksucking phone! - Sorry...
你这混账 汉纳
You are such a fucking douchebag,Hanna.
我们他妈的才不管 什么科技到底怎么回事
We don't give two shits about how technology works
因为 我们只关心怎么发财
because all we care about is getting fucking rich.
- 成交 两千 - 乔丹·贝尔福特
- Solid,2,000. - Jordan Belfort.
成交
Done!
该哄抬股价了 哇
Time to paint the tape. Whoo!
两千股 微软 进洞里去吧
2,000. Microsoft. Going in the hole!
过来
Come on.
拿着 还是热的呢
Live. Live. Hold on,that is hot.
放进去 关上
In. In. Shut that motherfucker.
快关上 关上 关上
Shut it! Shut it! Shut it!
成交
Sold!
来点可卡因？
Tootski?
不用了 谢谢
Oh,no. Thank you,though.
汉纳先生 这个美好的下午 您要来点什么呢？
Mr. Hanna,what can I bring for you on this glorious afternoon?
赫克特 今天我们规则是这样的
Well,Hector,here's the game plan.
先来两杯绝对马天尼鸡尾酒
You're gonna bring us two Absolut Martinis.
你知道我喜欢怎样的 调好不加冰
You know howl like them. Straight up.
然后七分半钟之后
And then precisely seven and one half minutes after that,
再上两杯 再然后
you're gonna bring us two more.
每五分钟上两杯
Then two more after that every five minutes
直到有人喝倒为止
until one of us passes the fuck out.
这上法很不错 您呢？
Excellent strategy,Sir.
我暂时喝水就行了
I'm good with water for now.
谢谢你
Thank you.
这是他第一天来华尔街上班 给他点时间
It's his first day on Wall Street. Give him time.
- 谢谢 - 嗯
- Thank you. - Thank you.
汉纳先生
Mr. Hanna?
你可以 在白天就开始嗑药
You're able to do drugs during the day
同时还能保持工作的状态？
and then still function,still do your job?
要不然还有别的方法可以做这工作？
How the fuck else would you do this job?
当然要有可卡因和妓女了 朋友
Cocaine and hookers,my friend.
是啊
Right.
我必须说 我十分激动
Well,I got to say,I'm incredibly excited
能成为这间公司的一员
to be a part of your firm. I mean...
公司的各位客户都
The clients you have are absolutely...
去他的客户
Fuck the clients.
你唯一的义务就是端肉上桌
Your only responsibility is to put meat on the table.
你有女朋友吗？
You got a girlfriend?
我结婚了
I'm married. I have a wife.
我妻子叫特瑞莎 她是发型师
Her name is Teresa. She cuts hair.
- 恭喜你啊 - 谢谢
- Congratulations. - Thank you.
想想特瑞莎吧
Think about Teresa.
这游戏什么规则？
Name of the game.
把客户口袋里的钱 转移到自己的口袋里
Move the money from your client's pocket into your pocket.
是
Right.
但如果同时也能让客户有钱挣
But if you make your clients money at the same time,
那每个人都能有所获利 对吗？
it's advantageous to everyone. Correct?
错
No.
华尔街规则第一条
Number one rule of Wall Street.
没人
Nobody...
就算你是沃伦·巴菲特 或者吉米·巴菲特也一样
I don't care if you're Warren Buffett or if you're Jimmy Buffett.
没人能知道这股票要涨
Nobody knows if a stock is gonna go up,
还是跌 侧身翻还是转圈玩
down,sideways,or in fucking circles.
- 至少所有股票经纪人都是这样 - 嗯
- Least of all stockbrokers,right? - Mmm-hmm.
都是"甲"的 知道是什么吗？
It's all a fugazi. You know what a fugazi is?
知道 是"假"的
Uh. Fugayzi. It's a fake.
是啊 管他甲的假的 都一样
Fugayzi,fugazi,it's a whazy,it's a woozy,it's...
都是尘埃 不存在的
Fairy dust. It doesn't exist.
从来都不是真的 都是空的
It's never landed. It is no matter.
元素周期表里找不到的
It's not on the elemental chart.
他妈的从不是真的
It's not fucking real.
- 对吗 - 对
- Right? - Right.
- 继续听我说 - 嗯
- Stay with me. - Mmm-hmm.
我们从不创造什么 建造不出什么来的
We don't create shit. We don't build anything.
不是
No.
于是 如果有个客户 他在股价是8块的时候买入
So if you got a client who bought stock at 8
然后涨到了16块 他给高兴坏了
and it now sits at 16,he's all fucking happy.
想马上兑换现钞结账走人
He wants to cash in,liquidate,
拿着钱回家去
take his fucking money and run home.
- 而你不能让他这么做 - 知道了
- You don't let him do that. - Okay.
- 因为 那样挣钱就成真了吧 - 是
- 'Cause that would make it real. - Right.
那该怎么办？
No. What do you do?
你冒出个绝妙的主意
You get another brilliant idea.
特别定制的
A special idea.
换个情形 引进另一支股票
Another "situation." Another stock
把挣来的钱重新拿去投资 然后再继续
to reinvest his earnings and then some.
他每次都会这么做的
And he will,every single time.
因为他上瘾了
'Cause they're fucking addicted.
然后你就一直继续这么做 一次一次又一次
And you just keep doing this,again and again and again.
与此同时 他觉得自己变得超有钱了
Meanwhile,he thinks he's getting shit rich,
话是没错 在账面上
which he is,on paper.
但你我 这些经纪人
But you and me,the brokers,
我们拿到的佣金可是
we're taking home cold hard cash
实打实的现钞啊 狗崽子们
via commission,motherfucker.
是啊
Right.
太不可思议了
That's incredible,Sir.
我真无法形容自己此刻多么激动
I can't tell you how excited I am.
就该如此
You should be.
有两个关键 让你在股票经济行业中成功
There's two keys to success in the broker business.
首先
First of all...
- 你得过轻松点儿 - 对
- You gotta stay relaxed. - Yeah.
你打飞机吗？
Do you jerk off?
打飞机？
Do I... Do I jerk off?
啊 是啊 我打飞机
Yeah. Yeah,I jerk off. Yeah.
一个礼拜几次？
How many times a week?
可能大概三四次吧
Like,um,three or four.
三四次 说不定还五次
Three or four times,maybe five.
这数目得提升啊
Gotta pump those numbers up.
三四次那是菜鸟的数字
Those are rookie numbers in this racket.
就我自己 我打飞机至少 一天两次
I myself,I jerk off at least twice a day.
- 哇 - 一次在早上
- Wow. - Once in the morning
健身结束以后 另一次在午饭后
right after I work out,then once right after lunch.
- 真的？- 嗯
- Really? - Mmm-hmm.
我这么做不是我想啊
I want to. That's not why I do it.
完全是因为有这需要
I do it 'cause I fucking need to.
想想看吧 你一整天都在对着各种数字
Think about it. You're dealing with numbers.
什么小数点啊 高频啊
All day long,decimal points,high frequencies.
砰 砰 砰
Bang,bang,bang.
该死的数字啊
Fucking digits.
都很有腐蚀性的 压在身上喘不过气
All very acidic above-the-shoulders mustard shit.
- 对吧？- 嗯
- All right? - Mmm-hmm.
这样很多人会压力过大无法工作吧
It kind of wigs some people out.
- 嗯 - 对
- Mmm-hmm. - Right.
所以要照顾一下老二 促进血液循环
You got to feed the geese to keep the blood flowing.
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
保持腰带以下的节奏感
I keep the rhythm below the belt.
行
Done.
这不是什么诀窍 这是疗法
This is not a tip,this is a prescription.
- 相信我 - 嗯
- Trust me. - Mmm-hmm.
如果不这样 你就会失去平衡
If you don't,you will fall out of balance,
微积分算着算着 昏过去了吧
split your differential and tip the fuck over.
或者更惨的
Or worse yet,
我见过的 猝死
I've seen this happen,implode.
我可不想猝死
No,I don't want to implode,Sir.
那是当然
No. No,you don't.
我是准备长久做下去的
I'm in it for the long run,you know?
- 是啊 猝死多难看 - 是
- Implosions are ugly. - Yeah.
跑去厕所 想打就打
Pop off to the bathroom,work one out any time you can.
等你打得熟练了
When you get really good at it,
会感觉非常顺滑的 打的时候想的那可都是钱
you'll fucking be stroking it and you'll be thinking about money.
第二 成功的秘诀
Second key to success in this racket
这个小瓶子里装着的宝贝
is this little baby right here.
叫可卡因
It's called cocaine.
对
Right.
它能让你脑袋十分清醒
It'll keep you sharp between the ears.
还能帮你拨号更快
It'll also help your fingers dial faster.
猜猜还能怎样？
And guess what?
对我很有好处
That's good for me.
可以了
Yes,Sir.
旋转 明白吗？
Revolutions. You follow?
旋转
Revolutions.
把客户放在摩天轮上
Keep the clients on the Ferris wheel.
然后转起来 游乐场开门了 全年营业24小时无休
And it goes. The park is open 24/7,365,
几十年 上百年
every decade,every goddamn century.
就是这样
That's it.
游戏就是这样
The name of the game.
我掌握着关键
Halkidiki?
- 嗯 - 谢谢
- Hmm. - Thank you.
来
Come on.
多来点统领一切的气势
We're the common denominator.
帮我继续哼
Keep it up for me.
你听到声音了
You've seen the echo.
带着钱来了
And the money comes in.
猎物们进城了
The parade comes to town.
去逛百老汇
Going down Broadway.
那是单行道
It's a one-way street.
往哪儿走我说了算
Whichever way I go
接下来半年
The next six months,
我已经了解了华尔街所有的"进出"
I got to know the ins and outs of Wall Street.
挣着大笔的钱 同时准备证券执照考试
Earning shit money as I geared up to take my Series 7.
然后 我终于拿到了股票经纪人执照
Then I was a licensed broker at last,
准备要大干一笔
ready to make my fortune.
以未来宇宙之王的身份开始了第一天
My first day as a future Master of the Universe.
1987年10月19日
半年前埃克森的股价是86块
I have Exxon at 86 1/4 six months ago.
现在36块就能买到了
Today it is trading at 36 1/2.
等等
Mr...
那天被称作"黑色星期一"
They called it Black Monday.
不骗人
No shit.
到下午4点 股指已经跌了508点
By 4:00 P.M.,the market had dropped 508 points.
是1929年大萧条以来最大的跳水
The biggest plummet since the crash of '29.
我认识你家人 你也认识我家人
I know your family,you know mine.
我不知道 什么鸟不拉屎的乡下地方吧
No,I don't know. Some fucking country in Europe took a shit.
他们爱干吗就干吗
Let them do what they want to fucking do.
我们的股票还是坚挺的
Our market's solid.
你不会想卖这支股票的
This is not something that you want to sell.
知道发生什么了吗？海啸了
You know what happened? A fucking Tsunami.
你这是犯了大错了
I think you're making a big mistake.
是 我会跟你妻子谈
Yes,I will talk to your wife.
相信我 不要接电话
Trust me,do not answer the phone.
很多人会给你打电话来
A lot of people are gonna be calling you,
试图刺探你的私密事务
trying to get your dirty laundry.
你不知道发生了什么
We don't know what's going on here.
我知道 知道
I know. I know.
天
Holy
我了个操
fucking shit!
难以置信
Unbelievable.
我第一天当股票经理人就碰这烂事
My first shitty day as a broker.
一个月之内 L.F.罗斯柴尔德公司
Within a month,L.F. Rothschild,
1899年就建立了的 就这样关门大吉了
an institution since 1899,closed it's doors.
华尔街把我吞没
Wall Street had swallowed me up
又迅速把我赶了出来
and shit me right back out again.
如果需要的话我可以把订婚戒指给当了
We could pawn my engagement ring if we needed to.
- 宝贝 - 我无所谓的
- Babe... - Because I don't mind.
如果需要的话
If we needed to,I'm saying...
- 我真的无所谓 - 你听我说
- Will you listen to me? - Okay.
我们什么都不用拿去当铺 好吗？
You're not pawning anything. Okay?
- 好 - 我怎么告诉你的？
- Okay. - What do I always tell you?
你会成为百万富翁
You're gonna be a millionaire.
这就对了 好吗？让我好好看看
That's right. Okay? Just let me look.
会找到活儿的
We'll find something.
- 这个怎样？- 什么？
- How about this? - What?
"奇才天下第一" 电子器材行
Nobody Beats the Wiz,the electronics store.
库存帮工 你觉得呢？
Stock boy. What do you think?
你不会去那种地方上班的
You're not gonna work at that place.
是啊 但总有个开始
Yeah,but,you know,you start off...
乔丹 你要是做这个
Jordan,you're gonna be miserable at that place
- 会感到特悲哀的 - 我知道
- if you go there. - I know.
可那是零售业 总有升职机会
It's sales. You work your way up,
之后可以成为经理
you'll be a general manager.
- 你不会愿意做库存帮工的 - 为什么？
- You're not gonna be a stock boy. - Why not?
因为你是股票经纪人
'Cause you're a stockbroker.
你也明白 现在没有地方在招聘股票经纪人
You understand that nobody's hiring stockbrokers right now?
你明白的对吧？
You understand that?
懂吗
Okay?
啊 这里有一家在招
Ah. This place is.
- 什么 - 上面写什么？
- What? - What's that say?
股票经理人
"Stockbrokers."
长岛？长岛的股票经理人？
In Long Island? Stockbrokers in Long Island?
太好了
Yeah.
在长岛也可以
It's in Long Island. So what?
你好 请问投资者中心在哪？
Hey,uh,I'm looking for Investor's Center.
我们就是 你要投资吗？
What's that? You want to invest?
不是 是投资者中心
No. Investor's Center.
我是来找投资者中心的
I'm looking for Investor's Center.
没错 就是我们 这里就是
Yeah,yeah,that's us. Hey. This is it. This is it.
噢
Oh.
- 我是道恩 是啊 - 你就是道恩？
- I'm Dwayne. Yeah. - You're Dwayne?
你好道恩 我们之前通过电话
Hi,Dwayne. We spoke on the phone.
我叫乔丹·贝尔福特
I'm Jordan Belfort.
是纽约罗斯柴尔德那边来的经理人
I'm the broker from Rothschild in New York.
噢是啊 请坐 你好吗？
Yes,yeah. Have a seat. How are you?
我们聊过天
We had a conversation...
我们之前通过电话对吧？
We spoke on the phone earlier,right?
- 两小时前 - 是的
- Two hours ago. - Right.
嗯
Yeah.
那是因为他们从不管股票 就是这个意思
They're up and comers. That's what that means.
三分钱一股 就是三块钱
It's 3 cents a share,that's $3!
你骗鬼呢
You cheap fuck!
那
So,uh...
你们的交易机在哪？
So where are your Quotrons here?
- 什么机？- 就是电脑
- Quotrons? - Yeah. Your computers.
哦 我们这里不需要电脑
No,no. We don't even need computers here.
用这个粉色的纸条记录交易就可以了
We just trade right off the pink sheets here.
- 粉色纸条？- 是啊 这些都是细价股
- Pink sheets? - Yeah,they're Penny stocks.
那些无法在纳斯达克上市的公司
You know,uh,companies that can't get listed on NASDAQ,
他们资产不够？
they don't have enough capital?
于是他们的股票在这里交易
Their shares trade here.
- 细价股？- 是啊
- Penny stocks? - Yeah.
比如这个 阿洛坦 真的挺有意思
This one,uh,Aerodyne,is a really interesting...
阿罗
Or Aerotyne...
阿洛坦 嗯
Aerotyne,yeah.
阿罗 阿洛坦
Aero... Aerotyne...
阿洛坦 嗯
Aerotyne. Yeah.
是正红的股票
Very hot stock right now.
是吗？
Oh,yeah?
是两兄弟 他们在自家车库
They're just a couple of brothers that are making
造雷达探测器
radar detectors out of their garage.
他们俩住在爱荷华州的德比克
They're out in Dubuque.
也有可能造的是微波炉吧 我不确定
Maybe it's microwaves. I'm not sure.
你要是给公司主线打电话去
But you call the company's main line,
会是他们的妈妈桃乐丝接电话 她人可好了
their mom,Dorothy,answers and she is so sweet.
- 好公司 - 其实我也不知道该说什么
- Good company. - I actually don't know what else to...
除了这些我也不知道了
I don't know anything else about them other than that.
六分钱一股？
Six cents a share?
拜托 谁会买这种破烂货？
Hey,come on. Who buys this crap?
那个
Well,I mean...
老实说 大多都是笨蛋
Honestly,mostly schmucks.
邮递员什么的 可总有邮递员来买
Postmen,there's always postmen.
水管工
Uh,plumbers. Um...
他们在《皮条客》背面看到我们的广告
They see our ads in the back of,uh,
还有《流行机械》杂志
Hustler and Popular Mechanics.
我们的广告会说 可以让他们快速致富
Our ads actually say they can get rich quick.
- 《皮条客》？- 是啊
- Hustler? - Yeah.
你知道的吧 那个封面是女的的
You know,those girlie magazines.
是啊 都是裸体
Yeah,yeah. Nudie mag.
- 那是相当多 - 是啊
- A lot. - Yeah.
我们帮助他们解决房屋贷款
We're helping them finance houses,
帮他们给老婆买钻戒
we're helping them buy their wife a Diamond ring...
甚至买船什么的
A boat maybe.
这玩意正规吗 还是
Is this... Is this stuff regulated or are you guys...
你们主要都干嘛的？
What are you doing here?
呃
Uh...
算是吧
Sort of.
算是？
Sort of?
天哪 交易量惊人啊
Jesus Christ,the spread on these is huge.
没错 这才是关键
Yeah. And that's the point,that's...
你叫什么来着？
What's your name again?
乔丹·贝尔福特
Mine... Jordan Belfort.
乔丹 你在以前那公司做蓝筹股吧 佣金如何？
Jordan,what do you get on that blue chip stock?
佣金是百分之一 应该说 曾经有百分之一
I make one percent. Or I did make one percent.
这粉红单子佣金百分之五十
Pink sheets,it's 50.
百分之五十？
It's 50%?
佣金率百分之五十？
50% commission?
- 是 - 为什么？
- Yup. - For what?
这是对我们工作的回报
It's our markup for our services.
所以如果我
And so if I... If I...
卖一支股票卖出去一万块 我能拿走五千块？
if I sell a stock at $10,000,my commission is 5,000 bucks?
如果这股票你能卖出一万块
If you sell $10,000 worth of this stock,
我本人 愿意给你免费吹
I will personally give you a blowjob for free.
并且我真心希望能这样
And I hope it happens.
你好 约翰 今儿感觉如何？
Hello,John,how are you doing today?
几个礼拜之前你给我们公司 寄回了张明信片
You mailed in my company a postcard a few weeks back
询问关于这些细价股的信息
requesting information on Penny stocks
它们上升潜力巨大
that had huge upside potential
风险又低
with very little downside risk.
- 想起来我们了吗？- 噢可能是寄过吧
- Does that ring a bell? - Yeah,I may have sent something.
那太好了 约翰 今天我给你打电话来是因为
Okay,great. The reason for the call today,John,is,
我手头刚好拿到了这个
something just came across my desk,John.
这大概是我过去半年内见过的最好的了
It is perhaps the best thing,I've seen in the last six months.
如果你有六十秒的时间
If you have 60 seconds,I'd like to share
我愿意跟你分享一下
the idea with you. You got a minute?
你有时间吗？
Actually,I'm really very...
这家公司叫阿洛坦国际集团
The name of the company,Aerotyne International.
是中西部的一家高端科技企业
It is a cutting edge high-tech firm out of the Midwest
正在等待马上到来的专利审批
awaiting imminent patent approval
他们即将推出全新一代的雷达探测器
on the next generation of radar detectors
既能运用到军事领域 也能平日给普通人使用
that have both huge military and civilian applications now.
现在
Right now,John,
现在的股票价格是10分钱一股
the stock trades over-the-counter at 10 cents a share.
并且 顺带一提 我们的分析师指出
And by the way,John,our analysts indicate
之后的股价会比这高得多
it could go a heck of a lot higher than that.
你的获益将会 如果只投六千块
Your profit on a mere $6,000 investment
那都能升值到六万
would be upwards of $60,000!
天哪 那可是我全部的贷款额度
Jesus! That's my mortgage,man.
没错 你就可以还贷了
Exactly. You could pay off your mortgage.
这支股票很安全吧？
This stock will pay off my house?
约翰 有件事我可以向你保证
John,one thing I can promise you,
就算在现在这市场条件下
even in this market,
我都从不要求客户去关注我的成功投资案例
is that I never ask my clients to judge me on my winners.
我让他们关注那些失败了的 因为实在少之又少
I ask them to judge me on my losers because I have so few.
这次对阿洛坦的投资
And in the case of Aerotyne,
是绝对有据可循很有保障的 约翰
based on every technical factor out there,John,
我们正需要一个盛大的开盘
we are looking at a grand slam home run.
好 买吧 我买四千块
Okay,let's do it. I'll do 4 grand.
四千那就是四万股 约翰
$4,000? That'd be 40,000 shares,John.
我现在先帮你锁定这笔交易
Let me lock in that trade right now
之后会让我的秘书
and get back to you with my secretary
给你发正式的确认函件 怎样 约翰？
with an exact confirmation. Sound good,John?
- 听上去不错 - 很好
- Yeah,sounds good. - Great.
嘿 约翰？
Hey,John.
谢谢您以信心来支持
Thank you for your vote of confidence.
欢迎加入投资者中心
And welcome to the Investor's Center.
嗯 多谢了 再见
Yeah,thanks a lot,man.
再见
Bye-bye.
你他妈怎么做到的？
How'd you fucking do that?
就这样 我一下子就挣了两千块
Just like that,I made 2 grand.
其他人看我的眼神 就好像我刚发现了火种
The other guys looked at me like I'd just discovered fire.
好 这样更好
Great! Even better!
我能把垃圾卖给收垃圾的人
I was selling garbage to garbage men
实打实的钞票滚滚而来
and making cash hand over fist.
你唯一会有的问题就是 以后会后悔自己没多买一点
The only problem you're gonna have is that you didn't buy more.
搞定
Boom shocka locka!
我卖给他们的都是破烂货
So I was selling them shit.
在我看来 他们的钱还是交给我保管比较好
But the way I looked at it,their money was better off in my pocket.
我更懂怎么花钱
I knew how to spend it better.
打扰一下 停车场里那辆是你的车？
Excuse me. Is that your car in the lot?
是啊
Yeah.
- 真是好车啊 - 谢了
- It's a nice ride. - Thanks,man.
我叫丹尼·阿佐夫
Donnie Azoff.
我叫乔丹·贝尔福特
Hey. I'm Jordan Belfort.
- 幸会 - 你好吗
- Nice to meet you. - How you doing?
其实我见过你的车
You know,actually,I see that car around.
- 经常见到 - 是吗 在哪里？
- I see it around a lot. - Oh,yeah,where?
我觉得我们是住同一幢公寓楼的
I think we live in the same building.
- 不会吧 - 嗯 没错
- No shit? - Yeah,yeah.
- 你在12楼吧？- 是啊 你住几楼？
- Twelfth floor? - Yeah. What floor are you on?
四楼
Fourth floor.
- 就是那个老婆挺丑的人家 带个两个小孩的 - 对
- I have two little kids. Ugly wife. - Right.
你是做什么的呢 老兄？
What do you do,bro?
做什么的？什么意思
What do you mean,what do I do?
职业啊 你是做什么工作的？
For work,what do you do?
我是股票经纪人
I'm a stockbroker.
- 股票经纪人？- 是啊
- Stockbroker? - Yeah.
我做儿童家具的
Children's furniture.
哦 挺好嘛
Oh,good for you.
还行吧
It's all right.
你挣很多钱吧？
You make a lot of money?
还行 自己过得还不错吧
Yeah,I do all right for myself.
我 搞不太懂啊
I'm trying to put it together.
你开那么好的车
You got your fucking nice car,
竟然跟我住同一幢楼 我有点
we live in the same building. I just...
实在是不明白 你到底挣多少？
I'm not understanding... How much money do you make?
不知道 上个月有七万块吧
I don't know. $70,000 last month.
我操
Get the fuck...
开玩笑呢吧
Get the fuck out of here.
我认真的
No,I'm serious.
我也是认真的
Yeah,no,I'm serious,too.
说真的啊 你到底挣多少？
Seriously,how much money do you make?
说过了啊 七万
I told you. $70,000.
准确的说是七万二
Well,technically,$72,000.
上个月 差不多这样
Last month. Something like that.
你一个月挣七万二？
You made 72 grand in one month?
是啊
Yeah.
这么说吧
I'll tell you what.
如果你能给我看看写着七万二的工资条
You show me a pay stub for $72,000 on it,
我立马辞职跟你干
I quit my job right now and I work for you.
嘿 保利 还好么你
Hey,Paulie,what's up?
没 我好着呢
No,yeah,yeah. No,everything's fine.
嘿 听我说 我不干了
Hey,listen,I quit.
于是他真的辞职了
And he did quit his job.
我还是觉得有点奇怪的
Which I thought was a little weird.
毕竟我们才刚认识
I mean,I just met this fucking guy.
别他妈告诉苏珊 这不关她的事
Don't fucking tell Susan. It's none of her business.
他这人还有别的特点
There were other things about him,too.
比如他的牙齿闪着磷光白色
Like his phosphorescent white teeth.
老婆？我跟你老婆有什么关系
Wife! I gotta fucking deal with your wife?
戴着一副角质框架的平光眼镜
The fact that he wore horn rims with clear lenses
想要看上去更有型
just to look more WASP-y.
然后 还有一些传言
And then,there were these rumors.
我听说了一些蠢极的传言 我也不知道
I heard some stupid shit. I don't know.
妈的 我都不想提 这
Fuck,I didn't even want to bring it up. It's just...
- 太蠢了 - 是说我的？
- it's stupid. - Shit with me?
大家总是喜欢嚼舌根
You know,people say shit. I don't even know.
我半数时候都根本不听
I don't even listen to it half the time.
他们说什么了？
What are they saying?
该死 说你上了你表妹什么的
Shit about you and your cousin or something like that.
我根本都不想听的
I don't even listen to it.
老兄 不是这样的
Oh,bro,it's not like that.
不是这样的
It's not like that.
他们说你娶了你表妹什么的 之类的蠢话
Like you married your cousin or some stupid shit. No?
是啊 我老婆
Yeah,my wife. Yeah.
我老婆是我表妹 之类的
My wife is my cousin,or whatever.
可是情况跟你想象的不一样
But it's not like what you think,or whatever,you know.
她是 直系的表妹吗？还是
Is she like a first cousin,or is she...
我懂 她不是
Yeah,no,she's,you know...
她爸是我妈的亲弟弟
Her... Her father is the brother of my mom.
可是 你懂的
It's not like,what... You know.
我们是一起长大的那种
Look,we grew up together.
她后来变得超正啊 相当火辣
And she grew up hot,you know. She fucking grew up hot.
我的朋友都想要上她
And all my friends were trying to fuck her,you know.
我不能允许
And I'm not gonna let someone...
我那些狐朋狗友上我表妹
You know,one of these assholes fuck my cousin,
所以我就做了表哥应该做的事情
so,you know,I used the cousin thing as like an in with her.
我不能允许其他任何人上我表妹
I'm not gonna let someone else fuck my cousin.
如果一定得有人上她
You know,if anyone's gonna fuck my cousin,
那只能是我 我是很尊重她的
it's gonna be me,out of respect. You know?
不 不 我懂
No,I get it. Yeah.
你不担心生孩子方面的问题吗？
I mean,you're not afraid of like the whole kid thing,right?
- 什么？跟她生孩子吗？- 是啊
- What? Having kids with her? - Yeah.
不担心啊 我们有两个小孩
No. We have two kids.
而且 他们
And they're... I mean...
我不想 问得太过分 但 他们都还好吧？
I don't want to get personal,but they're okay?
当然 他们没有弱智什么的
No,they're not retarded or anything like that.
但 几率很大 对吧？
But there's a big chance,right,if...
是啊 大概 百分之60吧
Yeah,there's like a 60%,you know,
百分之60 65的概率这小孩会是弱智
60 to 65% chance the kid's gonna be fucking retarded or whatever.
这概率 能把我吓死啊
That'd scare the shit out of me,buddy.
小孩子经常有这种事的
Look,man,a lot of having a kid,or whatever,takes risk,
不管你上的是不是你表妹
whether you're fucking cousins or not.
如果真那样怎么办？
What if something like that happened?
我是说 如果小孩是弱智的话
Basically,you know,if the kid was retarded,
那我会开车载他去乡下
I would,you know,drive it up to the country
然后 就像 开门
and just,like,you know,open the door and say,
把他放生 就像放生宠物
"You're free now." You know,like,"Run free."
懂吗
You know?
你逗我玩呢吧
You're completely fucking with me.
那太残忍了
That's horrible. You're not gonna...
你不能 不
You look like you've... No.
我们会送孩子去相关机构的或其他什么地方
We would take it to,like,an institution or somewhere
反正是专门的那种
that's handled to,like,you know,
专门照顾这种小孩的
raise the kid or whatever.
如果你们非常幸福 那上帝会继续保佑的
You know what? If you're happy,God bless you,buddy.
没 我才没过得幸福
No,I'm not fucking happy.
所有结婚了的都他妈的不幸福
No one who's married is fucking happy.
听到这个那我很遗憾啊
Well,I'm sorry to hear that,buddy.
听着 我真的
Listen,I'm really,you know...
很感激能得到这工作
I'm really appreciative for this fucking job.
我很喜欢
I'm really enjoying it.
我也很高兴你能做得不错
I'm really happy with what you're doing.
其实吧 我给你带了件小礼物
Actually,I got you a little present.
- 给我的礼物？- 是啊
- You got me a present? - I got you something.
你很贴心嘛
Oh,fuck. You're sweet.
不过在后面外头
Yeah. It's in the back though.
- 说什么呢？- 我们得从后门出去拿
- What do you mean? - You gotta go out back.
啊 还是包装好的吗？
Like it's wrapped up or something?
那是啊 包得可好了
It's wrapped up. Yeah.
- 我不明白 - 我也是
- I don't get it. - Neither do I.
你在车里都能做的
Let's fucking go. Come on.
你 先来
Your turn.
我才不要抽
I'm not fucking doing this.
你他妈的疯了吗
You're out of your fucking mind.
- 抽一口啊 - 不
- Smoke this shit,bro. - No.
这边没人啊
No one's fucking here,bro.
进来
Get the fuck...
跟我一起抽啊 老兄
Fucking smoke crack with me,bro.
我才不呢
I'm not fucking doing it.
一起抽吧 和我一起抽吧 老兄
Smoke crack. Smoke some fucking crack with me,bro.
- 就抽一口 就一口 - 好
- One hit. One hit. That's it. - Okay.
真是疯了
Fucking nut job.
我们去跑跑
Let's go run,huh?
我们得走了
We gotta get out of here,buddy.
赶紧的 我们得狂奔啊
We gotta get out of here. Let's go fucking run.
像狮子和老虎一样狂奔
Let's run like we're fucking lions and tigers and bears!
狂奔去 狂奔
Let's run! Let's fucking run!
狂奔 跑
Let's fucking run! Go!
跑 跑
Go,go,go,go!
这里是弗兰克的车行
You've reached Frank's Best Auto Body.
现在没有营业
We're closed right now.
请留言
So please leave us a message.
你好 我叫乔丹·贝尔福特
Hello. My name is Jordan Belfort.
我和我的搭档 有兴趣租下你的车库
My partner and I are very interested in renting out your garage.
丹尼和我离职打算单干
Donnie and I were going out on our own.
首先就需要找些经理人
And the first thing we needed was brokers.
有销售经验的人
Guys with sales experience.
所以我招来了老家的几个小伙伴
So I recruited some of my hometown boys.
海獭 卖肉
Sea Otter,who sold meat
和大麻的
and weed.
切斯特 卖轮胎
Chester,who sold tires
和大麻的
and weed.
还有罗比 手头有什么就卖什么
And Robbie,who sold anything he could get his hands on.
主要还是大麻
Mostly weed.
你能给我一些番茄酱 好吗？
Can you bring me some ketchup? Okay?
这位是布拉德
This is Brad.
我真正想招的就是他
And Brad's the guy I really wanted.
但他跟我们并不是一伙的
But he didn't go along with us.
他已经靠卖安眠酮挣了很多钱
He was already making so much money selling Quaaludes,
已经是碧沙区的安眠酮大王了
he'd become the Quaalude King of Bayside.
你这样能泡到妞子吗？
Getting any pussy with that thing or what?
是啊 当然
Yeah,man,of course.
下次带几个来我这边
Bring some of them chicks around here sometime,huh?
让他们看看
Let 'em watch.
让他们看看 懂我说的意思吗？
Let 'em watch. Know what I mean?
嘿 小齐 跟你姐姐说一声 我问她好
Hey,Zip! You tell your sister I was asking about her.
下次过来的时候给我带两条她的内裤
Why don't you bring me a pair of her panties next time you come through.
行啊 但她说了 不想理你
Yeah,man. She said she don't want to talk to you anymore,man.
那赶紧滚
Get the fuck out of here.
嘿 妈 我们今天是吃鸡吗？
Hey,Ma,we got chicken or what?
妈
Ma!
在听么？这活儿比你们想象得简单
You listening? It's easier than you think.
每个跟你通电话的人
Every person you're on the phone with,
他们都想发财 快速发财
they want to get rich and they want to get rich quickly.
全都想不劳而获
They all want something for nothing.
有一次 我朝一个阿米什人卖大麻（基督教的一个信徒分支）
There was this one time that I was selling pot to this Amish dude.
就那种留大胡子的
You know those guys who got like the beard
但又没有上面的小胡子的
with like no mustache or some bullshit?
知道 他告诉我说他只想造家具为生
Well,he says that he only wants to make furniture.
我不懂了
I don't understand.
这两件事有关系吗？
What's that got to do with anything?
你他妈说什么呢
What the fuck are you talking about?
我没想曲解你的意思
I'm not putting words in your mouth or nothing,
但你刚才在说 人人都想发财
but you just said that everybody wants to get rich.
我操 你确实是这么说的
Holy fuck,you did just say that.
你们说什么？
What the fuck are you talking about?
是啊 比如佛教徒
Yeah,like Buddhists.
他们才不喜欢钱
They don't give a shit about money.
穿的都是床单 都不用买东西吧
They're wrapped in sheets. They're not buying shit.
我不是在说 什么佛教徒 阿米什人
I'm not talking about Buddhists or Amish.
我是说普通人
I'm talking about normal people,
工薪阶层 普通人
working-class,everyday people.
这些人都想发财 我没说疯话吧？
Everyone wants to get rich. Am I crazy?
"阿米什佛教徒"肯定是不存在的
There's no such thing as an Amish Buddhist.
- 这个我敢肯定 - 我没有
- I'm pretty fucking sure. - There could be.
能再来点番茄酱吗？
Can we get some ketchup,please?
你们不想挣点钱吗？
Do you guys not want to make money?
我想挣点钱
I want to make some money.
我他妈的想挣钱 好吗？
I want to make some fucking money,okay.
我什么都能卖
I can sell anything.
我可以卖润滑油给修道院
Shit,I can sell ludes to a convent full of nuns,
好让修女们互相干
and get them so horny they'd be fucking each other.
这态度就对了 你什么都能卖？
That's the attitude. You can sell anything?
那把这支笔卖给我
Sell me this fucking pen right here.
什么都能卖 那试试这个
You can sell anything. Sell that. Go ahead.
把笔卖给我
Sell me the pen.
我能先吃完吗？今天都没吃饭
Can I finish eating first? I haven't eaten today.
布拉德 给他们看看怎么卖的
Brad,show them how it's done. Boom.
来 把笔卖给我 你们看着
Sell me that pen. Watch. Go on.
你要我把笔卖给你？
You want me to sell this fucking pen?
这才是我的好伙伴 什么都能卖
That's my boy right there. Can fucking sell anything.
帮我个忙吧
Why don't you do me a favor.
在这餐巾纸上写一下你的名字？
Write your name down on that napkin for me.
我没有笔
I don't have a pen.
没错 有需就有供 朋友
Exactly. Supply and demand,my friend.
见鬼
Holy shit.
看见没？他这是在制造需求
See what I'm saying? He's creating urgency.
让你想要买这支股票
Get them to want to buy the stock.
把它变成他们需要的东西 懂吗？
Convince them it's something they need,you know what I mean?
真相是
And that's the thing.
修女都是同性恋
All nuns are lesbians.
你他妈的在说什么呢
What the fuck are you talking about,Otter?
想想看啊 她们没法
Think about it. They can't keep a dude
跟男的在一起
so they're gonna start fucking chicks.
都喊了四次了
Four fucking times,Kimmie! Four times.
- 还不给我们拿 - 罗比·费伯格
- He's not with us. - Friggin' Rambo.
她这才过来
Now she runs.
我知道这些人不是哈佛的工商管理硕士
But look. I knew these guys weren't like Harvard MBAs.
罗比·费伯格这蠢货
Robbie Feinberg,the pinhead,
高中就念了5年
took five years to finish high school.
奥尔登·卡夫伯格 外号海獭
Alden Kupferberg,the Sea Otter,
甚至都没毕业
didn't even graduate.
切斯特·明 这个堕落的中国人
Chester Ming,the depraved Chinaman,
以为柔道是以色列的
thought jujitsu was in Israel.
这群人里最聪明的是尼基·科斯科夫
Smartest of the bunch was Nicky Koskoff.
他上过法学院
He actually went to law school.
我叫他"光头" 因为他头上那顶假发
I called him Rugrat because of his piece of shit hairpiece.
不过 他们现在这么年轻 饥渴又愚蠢
Still,give them to me young,hungry and stupid
用不了一阵子我就会让他们发大财
and in no time,I'll make them rich.
我的天哪
Oh,my God.
乔丹 那个
Jordan,that...
喜欢吗 宝贝？
You like it,baby?
哦 天呀 太美了
Oh,my God,it's beautiful.
这些宝石不是世界上最大的
They're not the biggest stones in the world,
但我保证它们成色很好
but I promise they're really high quality.
太美了
It's beautiful.
They're so beautiful.
噢 天哪
Oh,boy.
怎么了？
What?
这脸色很眼熟啊 怎么了？说吧
I know that look. What is it? Go ahead.
我不知道
I don't know,it's... You know...
这些股票和公司
These stocks... These companies...
它们都很烂吧？
They're like crappy companies.
- 是啊 没错 - 好吧
- Well,yeah. - Okay.
烂到不行
Yeah,they're terrible.
别担心 听我说
Don't worry about it. I told you,
我们做的是完全合法的
what I'm doing is completely legal.
嗯 我知道
Yeah,I know.
但他们是没法挣到钱的对吧？
But they're not gonna make anyone money though,right?
有时候能 有时候不能
Well,sometimes they do,sometimes they don't.
事情都是这样
You know how it goes.
可是对你来说 如果你把这些卖给有钱人
Wouldn't you feel better if you sold that stuff to rich people
他们就算亏了也不心疼 这样你不会更好过点吗
who can,like,afford to lose all that money?
当然了
Of course.
但有钱人是不会买细价股的
But rich people don't buy Penny stocks.
他们肯定不会买
They just don't.
为什么不会？
Why not?
因为他们太聪明了
Because they're too smart,
这就是不会买原因
that's why not.
我是说 一个有大学学历的人
I mean,what person with a college education
怎么可能相信这帮草包？
would trust this bunch of jerk-offs?
把电话挂了 告诉他你稍后回打他电话
Hang up the phone. Tell him you'll call him back.
电话上有人要下五千的单子
I got 5 fucking grand on the phone right now!
嘿
Hey!
但如果他们听上去不像是草包呢？
But what if they didn't sound like a bunch of jerk-offs?
如果我能教他们怎样把股票卖给有钱人呢？
What if I could teach them how to sell to people with money?
真正的有钱
Real money.
所以我决定把公司回炉重造
So I decided to reinvent the company.
先生们 欢迎
Gentlemen,welcome
来到斯特拉顿·奥克蒙
to Stratton Oakmont.
你们现在要把目标定为最有钱的人
You schnooks will now be targeting
那百分之一的美国人
the wealthiest 1% of Americans.
我这说的可是大鲸鱼啊
We're talking about whales here.
莫比·迪克那种的
Moby fucking Dicks.
然后 有了这个剧本 也就是你们的"鱼叉"
And with this script,which is now your new harpoon,
我会把你们每个人都教成
I'm gonna teach each and every one of you
亚哈船长
to be Captain fucking Ahab.
懂了吗？
Get it? Huh?
什么船长？
Captain who?
亚哈船长啊 就是
Captain Ahab. From the fucking...
你这草包 书没看过啊
The book,motherfucker. From the book.
用点脑子啊
Turn your fucking brain on.
- 去死 - 说什么呢 罗比
- Fuck you. - Jesus fuck,Robbie.
听我说 我们现在有新名字了 是新公司
Listen to me. We're a new company with a new name.
一个我们的客户能信得过的公司
A company that our clients can believe in.
值得客户信赖的公司
A company that our clients can trust.
一个深深扎根于 华尔街的公司
A firm whose roots are so deeply embedded into Wall Street
公司的创立者们 乘着五月花号而来
that our very founders sailed over on the Mayflower
刻下了斯特拉顿·奥克蒙这个名字
and chiseled the name Stratton Oakmont
刻在岩石上
right into Plymouth fucking Rock!
懂吗？
You got it?
我们要做的是这样
What we're gonna do is this.
首先我们要用迪士尼 AT&T IBM等
First we pitch 'em Disney,AT&T,IBM,
蓝筹股吸引他们
blue chip stocks exclusively.
这些人求之不得的股票
Companies these people know.
一旦他们上钩了 就可以把狗屎端出来了
Once we've suckered them in,we unload the dog shit.
粉红小纸条 细价股
The pink sheets,the Penny stocks,
真正赚钱的家伙
where we make the money.
- 百分之五十的佣金啊 - 哦
- 50% commission,baby. - Ooh.
现在这情况下 想挣钱的关键在于
Now the key to making money in a situation like this
就是在消息定下来之前就出手
is to position yourself now before the settlement.
因为 等你在《华尔街日报》里看到的时候
Because by the time you read about it in The Wall Street Journal,
那就已经太晚了
it's already too late.
然后你就等
Then you wait.
等
You wait.
谁先开口说话 谁就输了
And whoever speaks first loses.
对不起
Sorry,uh...
谢谢你打来
I appreciate the call.
我真的要再考虑考虑
I really have to give this some thought
还要告诉我老婆一声
and talk to my wife about it.
我能再打给你吗？
Can I call you back?
他们不知道了 对吧？他们要考虑考虑
They don't know,right? They gotta think about it,
要跟老婆说 或者找牙仙说
they gotta talk to their fucking wives,or the fucking Tooth Fairy.
重点就是 他们说什么不重要
Point is,it doesn't matter what the fuck they say.
他们唯一拒绝的理由就是不相信你们
The only real objection that they have is that they don't trust you guys.
他们干嘛要相信你们呢？看看你们
And why should they trust you? I mean,look at you.
你们是一群低贱的售货员啊
You're a bunch of fucking sleazy salesmen,right?
你要告诉我的是
So,what do you say?
如果我让你7块买入联合碳化物公司
You mean to tell me that if I put you in at Union Carbide at 7
32块卖出
and took you out at 32...
11块买入德州仪器 47块卖出
Texas Instruments at 11 and took you out at 47...
16块买入 41块抛出
U.S. Steel at 16,took you out at 41...
你不会说 切斯特
You wouldn't be saying to me right now,"Chester",
"给我买几千股迪士尼"
"pick me up a few thousand shares of Disney"
就现在 就现在
"on the spot,right now. Come on."
老实说吧 凯文 真的？
Honestly,Kevin? Honestly? Seriously?
我不认识你啊
I don't know you.
你主动打来的 还是陌生人吧
You cold-called me. You're a total stranger.
这一点我完全同意
I am in complete agreement with you.
你不熟悉我 我也不熟悉你
You don't know me,I don't know you.
请允许我自我介绍一下
Let me introduce myself to you.
我叫奥尔登·卡夫伯格
My name is Alden Kupferberg.
- 罗比·费伯格 - 我叫切斯特·明
- Robbie Feinberg. - Chester Ming.
我是斯特拉顿的高级副总
I'm Senior Vice President at Stratton Oakmont...
而且我正打算成为
and I plan on being one of the...
我们公司明年的最佳经理人
top brokers in my firm next year.
所以要是卖错了的话 这想法就泡汤了吧 斯坦
And I'm not gonna get there by being wrong,Stanley.
我确实想说
I do wanna say that you sound like a...
你听上去很真诚
You sound like a pretty sincere guy.
我们不会让你暴富
It's not gonna make you rich
也不会让你亏钱
and it's not gonna make you poor.
但我们斯特拉顿会做到的是
But what this trade will do is serve as...
成为未来商业的标杆企业 凯文
a benchmark for future business,Kevin.
现在跟我说话轻松多了吧 斯科特？
You feel comfortable with me now,Scotty?
到时候你就可以肯定
And then you'll know for sure
自己终于在华尔街找到了
that you finally found a broker on Wall Street
值得信任的经理人
that you can trust,
能持续不断地让你有钱挣
and who can consistently make you money.
听上去还行吧？
Sound fair enough?
你知道 对
You know what... Yeah.
是啊 我必须承认 自己很动心
I gotta say,I'm pretty impressed.
那么 你怎么想？
What are you thinking?
凯文？
Kevin.
你给我一次试水机会
You give me one shot here
买一支蓝筹股 比如柯达
on a blue chip stock like Kodak,
然后 相信我吧 凯文
and believe me,Kevin,
你唯一可能有的问题
the only problem you're gonna have
就是后悔自己当初没有多买
is that you didn't buy more.
听上去如何？
Sound fair enough?
该死
Shit. My...
我老婆估计是要跟我离婚了 不过
My wife might divorce me,but...
好吧 买吧
Yeah,let's do it.
明智的选择啊 凯文
Excellent choice,Kevin.
这次要买多少？
How much do you want to go for this time?
我们 买五千块钱的吧
Let's do 5... $5,000.
干嘛不直接买八千呢？
Can we try 8,000,Kevin?
行吧 买一万
All right. Let's do 10.
- 一万？- 你觉得怎样？
- Ten. - You want to do that?
明智之举
Excellent choice!
凯文 现在我先帮你确认交易
Kevin,let me lock in that trade right now
一会儿再跟你联系
and get back to you in a few minutes
发给你具体的确认函
with an exact confirmation,Kevin.
凯文 欢迎来到 斯特拉顿·奥克蒙
And welcome to Stratton Oakmont.
谢了 我得喝点啤酒了看来
Thanks,man. I'm gonna have a beer.
这真挺有意思
This is fun.
回聊了 凯文
Take it easy,Kev.
谢了 乔丹 多谢
Hey,thanks,Jordan. Thanks a...
搞定
Fuck that motherfucker!
这就是我要说的
That's what I'm talking about!
这蠢货啊
What a fucking idiot.
我本人 最熟悉的就是航空公司了
The one thing I know about in this world is airlines.
库申航空就是航空行业的未来
And Cuchon Airlines is the future of airlines.
现在买入
Get in now or...
- 我叫尼基·科斯科夫 - 我是切斯特·明
- I'm Nicky Koskoff... - Chester Ming...
我是斯特拉顿·奥克蒙的高级副总
And I'm a Senior Vice President with Stratton Oakmont.
我真的为您的遭遇感到遗憾
Judy,I am so,so,so sorry for your loss.
他是什么时候去世的？
When did he pass?
就算我说错了
Just say I'm wrong,right.
股票跌了
And the stock goes down a couple points...
我以我爷爷的名义起誓
and it makes you,in the words of my grandfather,
上帝保佑他的灵魂在钞票里游泳
God rest his soul,"A shit ton of money."
这就好比没有太阳之前
It's like getting in on fucking sunlight
就看到了阳光 懂吗？
before there was fucking sunlight. You understand?
我们能买进8000股？
Can we do 8,000 shares?
好吧 2.5万股
Okay,25,000.
这真是非常明智的决定
That's a very intelligent decision.
我会把线路转交给我们的销售助理
I'm gonna transfer you to my sales associate.
荣达
Rhonda!
- 荣达？- 把你转接到安德列
- Rhonda! - ...put you through to Andrea.
有人见到荣达吗？
Has anybody fucking seen Rhonda?
大家这一礼拜都过得还好吧？
Everybody have a good week?
太棒了
Yeah!
月底了
The end of the month.
佣金收入达到了2870万美元
$28.7 million in gross commissions,
全是来自粉红单子的股票
all from pink sheet stock,boys!
然后以我们每周一次的疯狂行为来庆祝
And to celebrate with our weekly act of debauchery,
我给我们可爱的销售助理
I have offered our lovely sales assistant,
丹妮尔拉·哈里森
Danielle Harrison,here,
开出了一万块整 条件是剃个光头
$10,000 to shave her fucking head!
想来吗？
Yeah,you want this?
You want this?
见头皮 见头皮
Let's scalp her! Scalp her!
剃头现在开始
Let the scalping begin!
见头皮 见头皮
Scalp! Scalp! Scalp!
顺便一说 丹妮尔拉答应
FYI,boys,Danielle has promised
会用这一万块钱来隆胸
to use this $10,000 for breast implants!
她已经是C罩杯了
She's already got C cups,
但她还要两个D
but now she wants fucking double D's!
这公司是不是太棒了
Is this a great fucking company or what?
这简直是全世界最棒的公司
Is this the greatest company in the world?
多米尼克
Donnie!
咱们把屋顶掀了吧
Blow the roof off this motherfucker!
- 香槟？-喔
- Champagne? - Whoo!
辣妹上场
Send in the stripees!
我的
Mine!
我们的事传遍了华尔街
Word about us spread throughout Wall Street.
甚至传到了我不太乐意的地方
Even the places I didn't want it to.
没过多久 《福布斯》杂志
It wasn't long before Forbes magazine,
这家华尔街的旗舰媒体 过来给我做个人物专题
the flagship of Wall Street,called to do a profile on me.
还有个问题 你觉得斯特拉顿·奥克蒙的未来会是如何
Let me ask you,how do you see the future for Stratton Oakmont?
一个词
One word?
多样化
Diversification.
这词不错 非常感谢 我已经采访到了足够的信息了
Sounds good. Thank you so much. I have more than enough.
- 非常感谢你抽出的宝贵时间 - 那太好了
- I appreciate your time. - Fantastic.
我们能快速合个影吗
Can we get a quick picture?
这写的什么狗屁
A total fucking hatchet job.
这贱人太放纵了吧 看看这个
This conniving little twat! Look at this!
《华尔街之狼》？他们写 看啊
"The Wolf of Wall Street" they call me. Look.
你发型看上去不错啊
Your hair looks good.
- 哦 发型不错 - 对
- Well,my hair looks good. - Yeah.
乔丹·贝尔福特
"Jordan Belfort,"
名字念起来像变了音的罗宾汉
"sounding like a kind of twisted Robin Hood"
从富人攫取财富 归为己有
"who takes from the rich and gives to himself"
以及他手下的一帮经理人
"and his Merry little band of brokers."
- 你看啊 - 听着
- Read that. Read it. - Listen.
负面宣传 是不存在的 亲爱的
There is no such thing as bad publicity,sweetheart.
你自己看文章
Read the article,babe.
乔丹 你看上去很棒 你这上的可是大杂志
Jordan,you look great! You're in a huge magazine.
我看上去什么样才不是重点
Big fucking deal I look great.
贝尔福特先生 请你看一下我的简历
Mr. Belfort! Can you look at my resume,please?
打扰一下 先生
Excuse me,excuse me,Sir!
给我冷静
Calm the fuck down!
这都是些什么人？
What the hell's all this?
因为那篇《福布斯》的文章 这帮人都想来这里找工作了
It's the Forbes article. They all want to work for you now.
嘿 我刚才说什么了？
Hey! What did I say?
我是想好一点
I'm just trying to be nice.
来找工作的吗？跟我谈
Hey,you want a job,you talk to me!
- 贝尔福特先生 - 给我一分钟时间
- Mr. Belfort! - Give me one minute.
《福布斯》让我成为了大明星
Forbes made me a superstar.
每天都有几十个掉进钱眼的年轻人 在我门口争得头破血流
Every day,dozens of money-crazed kids beat a path to my door.
如果我雇了他们 他们第二天就会从大学退学
If we hired 'em,they dropped straight out of college overnight
把自己的补助金全部花在
and spent whatever allowance they had
我们斯特拉顿自己的裁缝上买套新西装
on a new suit from our Stratton tailor.
你们是认真的吗
Are you fucking serious right now?
我们是在给这些年轻人穿衣服啊
I mean,we were literally putting clothes on these kids' backs.
然后这个混蛋出现了 四处打探
And here comes this jerk-off sniffing around.
每次这个世界上有人取得了成功
But,you know,every time someone rises up in this world,
总会有混账跳出来拉他下水
there's always gonna be some asshole trying to drag him down.
几个月之内 我们规模扩大了一倍
Within months,we doubled in size,
搬入了更大的办公室
moved to even bigger offices.
那简直是疯人院
It was a madhouse.
贪婪盛会
A greed-fest,
充斥着可卡因 睾酮和体液
with equal parts cocaine,testosterone,and body fluids.
情况之糟 我不得不在办公室划出一个"性爱禁区"
It got so bad,I had to declare the office a fuck-free zone
在早9点到晚7点之间
between the hours of 9:00 and 7:00.
但相信我 这都没用
But I'm telling you,even that didn't help.
其实这疯狂从第一天就开始了
Actually,the madness started on our very first day,
其中一个经理人 本·杰纳
when one of our brokers,Ben Jenner,
他在电梯里让销售助理帮他吹箫 名声大振
christened the elevator by getting a blowjob from a sales assistant.
那个女的叫帕姆 说到她
Her name was Pam,and to her credit,
她的确技术过人
she did have this amazing technique,
动作狂野 高潮奔放
with this wild twist and jerk motion.
大概一个月之后
About a month later,
丹尼和我决定和她3P
Donnie and I decided to double-team her
那是个礼拜六下午
on a Saturday afternoon
我们俩的老婆正出门做圣诞购物
while our wives were out shopping for Christmas dresses.
最终 本和她结婚了
Eventually,Ben married her,
考虑到她几乎吹遍了整个公司
which was pretty amazing considering she blew
这事儿还是很惊奇的吧
every single guy in the office.
然后本就患了抑郁症 三年后自杀了
Then he got depressed and killed himself three years later.
总之吧 我雇了自己的老爸麦克斯 来管账 作为切实的实施人
Anyway,I hired my dad,Max,to maintain order as the Enforcer.
斯特拉顿的盖世太保
Stratton's very own Gestapo.
我们都叫他"疯狂的麦克斯" 因为他的火爆脾气一触即发
We called him Mad Max because of his hair-trigger temper,
有时候只是电话铃响这么无辜的事
which could be set off by something
他都会怒发冲冠
as innocuous as a ringing telephone.
谁他妈的
Who the fuck has the goddamn gall
礼拜二晚上打电话来啊
to call this house on a Tuesday night?
该死啊
God damn it!
你会错过的
You're gonna miss it!
噢 拜托如果错过了要告诉我啊
Ooh,please,tell me something I don't know.
我等《私家侦探》等了他妈的一个礼拜了
I wait all week for the fucking Equalizer
然后现在 喂？
and they have to fucking... Hello.
但是 只要他一接起电话
But as soon as he picked up the phone...
吉恩 你好吗？吉恩
Gene. How are you,Gene?
他就会操着这么一口诡异的英腔
He'd affect this weird British accent.
没错 吉恩 那太好了
Right-o,Gene,that'd be great.
再见
Cheerio.
这蠢货
It was absolutely bizarre.
太奇怪了
The fucking halfwit!
- 他只要一挂电话 - 你错过了
- He'd hang up... - You missed it!
然后他又变回疯狂的麦克斯了
And then he's Mad Max all over again.
见鬼
Damn it!
好吧 快告诉我发生了什么
All right,tell me what happened. What happened?
他发现 是他母亲的妹妹
Well,he discovered it was the mother's sister.
他是谁？谁？告诉我
Who's he? Who? Tell me who...
男主角啊 你知道的
The main guy. You know who the main...
男主角啊
The main guy...
是他母亲的妹妹 被发现死掉了
it was his mother's sister. She showed up dead.
当然了 疯狂的麦克斯是不必知道
Of course,Mad Max didn't have to know
斯特拉顿具体都发生了些什么的
everything we were doing at Stratton.
然后会有个巨大的靶子
And then there's a big target and we...
架起来 贴好标签
They get launched at the target. They stick.
中间有个靶心 靶心上是个钱的标志
There's a bull's-eye and the bull's-eye's a dollar sign.
丢得离靶心最近的人
Whoever gets closer to the dollar sign...
拿走最高奖
gets the most points.
我肯定会使劲仍
I'm gonna throw the shit out of this little fucking thing.
那如果他受伤怎么办？
So if it gets hurt,what happens?
那我们要疯了
'Cause we're gonna get fucking nuts.
我不觉得他会受伤啊
I don't think he's gonna get hurt. They're like...
他们本来就有超过常人的力道吧
They got like superhuman strength.
我觉得会没事
I think he's gonna be fine.
你不能直视他的眼睛
You can't look him right in the eyes.
你不能直视他的眼睛？
You can't look him in the eye?
说的没错 PBS播过这节目
That's a fact. I saw it on PBS.
那样他们会很困惑 脑子不好使
They get confused and their wires get crossed.
你只能看着下巴
You gotta look at their Chin.
就好像 我是在看你
Like it looks like I'm looking at you
但我其实看的是你的下巴
but I'm looking at your Chin.
感觉你在跟我说话其实不是
I feel like you're addressing me right now,but you're not,are you?
就像蒙娜丽莎 他们都在寻找眼睛的直视
They're like the Mona Lisa. They find eye contact,
不管你站在房间的哪里
like,wherever you are standing in the room.
然后就锁定住
And they lock in.
但我们能对他做的事情也是有规定的吧
No,but there is a limit to what we can do with them?
我们可以朝他扔大便
We're allowed to throw shit at 'em.
还可以扔 食物 香蕉
We're allowed to throw food? Bananas.
任何食物 对
Any food. Correct.
但我不会做的事情也有 比如
But,for example,what I wouldn't do is
让他把鸡巴掏出来
maybe like tell him to pull his cock out
让几个女的
and like get some of the girls to,you know,
抚摸他什么的
fondle him and shit like that.
那会是 不可接受的？
That would be... That's unacceptable?
这个我们可以留做备用
Let's keep that in our back pocket.
这家伙应该主要还是用来扔靶子的
This guy is more about throwing at the dartboard.
对 对 没错
Correct. Yes,yes,yes.
关键是 他们有这天赋
The thing is,this is their gift,okay.
他们天生就是用来被扔的 就像飞镖
They're built to be thrown like a lawn dart.
头比较重 比如草坪飞镖
They're top heavy like a lawn dart.
造成那样才扔得准
So they're built for accuracy.
哦 上帝呀 我们可以把他当球扔吗
Oh,my God. Can we bowl with this guy?
罗比 那是他哥
That's his fucking brother,Rob.
他哥才是那个保龄球
His brother's the bowling ball.
他哥哥你把他绑在个滑板上面
The brother,you put a skateboard on him,
你带他去滑板
you strap him to a skateboard,
然后让他在走廊里面滑
you toss him down an alley at some pins.
- 不会吧 蛮好玩啊 - 向上帝发誓
- No shit. That's interesting. - Swear to fucking God.
- 这人能找来吗？- 我们会找来的
- Can we get that guy? - Yeah,we'll get that guy,too.
但这里写了 这人喜欢露阴
But it says here this guy will show his cock. Yeah.
- 就是不起立 对 - 他会？
- Instead of growing up. Yeah. - He will?
顺便一说 他们都很喜欢刁难
They are very ornery by the way,
所以你们玩的时候要小心点好吗？
so you gotta be very careful with these little guys.
安全第一
Safety first.
安全第一 好吗？
Safety is first,all right?
镇定剂注射器要准备好
I want somebody with a fucking tranquilizer gun
以准备随时射晕他们
ready to knock this fucker out.
- 我们是不是要带点像 - 迷药 电击枪？
- Do we want to get like a... - Mace. Taser guns.
或者气枪？
A pellet gun maybe?
气枪会伤人的
No,a pellet gun is gonna hurt him.
我只是想赶人走而已
I just want him out. Knocked out cold.
我觉得我们就玩靶子就行了
But I say we stick with the loophole. Right? Okay?
我们不要把他们当人看
If we don't consider him a human,
当成个表演这样就清楚了
we just consider it an act,I think we're in the clear.
就像飞天瓦伦达的空中飞人表演
Like The Flying Wallendas.
你们也知道 经常有人死 但也没人告过他们啊
You know,a lot of those guys died but they never sued anybody.
重要的是 必须记住这一点
The important thing you guys gotta keep in mind
就是这种事会传出去
is that these things gossip.
这帮人喜欢聚在一起嚼舌根
They get together and they gossip.
- 这说得有道理啊 - 我们最不想见到的就是
- That's a good point. - And the last thing
就是他们聚在一起 说
that we need is them getting together and saying,
"哦 他们拿我们开玩笑"
"Oh,they made fun of us."
那会让斯特拉顿名声受损
Like,it's gonna make Stratton look bad.
要不我怎么这么爱你呢 这种破事就你想得到
That's why I love you. You think of shit like that.
当他们来时 我们待他们就像待自己人一样吧
When they come in,we treat it just like one of us. Okay?
自己人 自己人
One of us. Gooble gobble,one of us.
我们待他们自己人 自己人
We accept them,one of us!
自己人 自己人
Gooble gobble,one of us.
我们待他们自己人 自己人
We accept them,one of us.
自己人 自己人
Gooble gobble,one of us!
乔丹 你爸来了
Jordan! Your dad's coming.
关于美国运通的账单的
Something about the American Express bill.
能让他走吗？
Can you get him out of here?
行啊 你帮我舔啊
Yeah. Lick my twat.
我说真的啊
No,I'm serious!
好了兄弟们 假装我们在讨论公事
Fuck. Guys,act like we're working.
你们有股票表格吗
You got any fucking stock forms?
好了 他来了 他来了
He's coming,he's coming.
快编点什么说着
Make some shit up.
我觉得咱们的屏幕还不够
I think if we short Pfizer...
43万 一个月花43万？乔丹？
$430,000 in one month,Jordy,huh?
他妈的43万美元啊 才一个月
Four hundred and fucking 30,000 fucking dollars in one fucking month!
都是商务开销 放轻松点
Good morning. They're business expenses. Relax.
- 商务开销 - 对
- Business expenses? - Yes.
- 乔丹 看看这里 - 什么
- Jordy,look what you got here. - What?
看看这 一顿晚饭吃了两万六
Look at this. $26,000 for one fucking dinner!
好吧 不是这样 这个我可以解释
Okay. No,no. This could be explained.
我们是来了客户 辉瑞制药那边来的
Dad,we had clients. The Pfizer clients.
没错 在阿根廷那个大露台别墅
Right. The porterhouse from Argentina.
很贵的香槟酒 红酒 香槟我们得买吧
Expensive champagne and... We had to buy champagne.
小菜是你们买的吧
And you ordered all the fucking sides.
- 跟他说说小菜啊 - 小菜是我买的
- Tell him about the sides. - I ordered sides,so...
小菜？两万六都是小菜？
Sides? $26,000 worth of sides?
什么小菜啊？能治癌症的吗？
What are these sides? They cure cancer?
那小菜确实能治癌症啊 这就是问题所在
The sides did cure cancer. That's the problem.
摆在那儿呢 要不怎么那么贵
That's why they were expensive.
- 给我闭嘴 - 我说真的
- Shut the fuck up. - I'm serious.
- 闭嘴 - 然后还有EJ娱乐公司
- Stop. - And EJ Entertainment?
EJ娱乐他妈的是什么玩意？
What the fuck is EJ Entertainment?
那个
Well,that's,uh...
说啊 EJ娱乐是什么？
Yeah,Jordy,what's EJ Entertainment?
我该怎么说？
How do I describe this?
是什么啊 乔丹？
Jord,what is that?
- 那他妈的是个妓院啊 - 我知道
- It's a fucking prostitution ring,Jordy! - I know.
- 没错吧 - 的确
- That's what it is! - That is what it is.
这词是不是再恰当不过了
Isn't that the perfect description for it?
没错 但是 这里的钱都不是我花的
That is what it is. But none of these were charged to me.
都是他们花的
This is all of them.
- 哦 都是我们啊？- 反正不是我
- Oh,that was all us? - It wasn't me though.
赶紧解释啊
Fucking explain this shit to him!
这可都是你们的账单
These are all of your fucking charges right here!
国税局允许T&A的 没关系（差旅娱乐支出 这里讲错了）
The IRS,they allow for T&A. It's fine.
是T&E
T&E!
我是说T&E啊
Yeah. I said T&E.
- 你说的是T&A - 我没有
- No,no. You said T&A. - No,I didn't.
你就是那么说的
Yeah,you did.
- 什么时候说过的？- 你说的T&A 是T&E好吗？
- When did I say that? - You said T&A. It's T&E.
我知道你因为那顿晚饭很不爽 可以理解
I know you're upset about the dinner,
因为我们花了太多了 但我真的说的是T&E
and that makes sense because we did spend too much money. But I said T&E.
别跟我说这个 你说了什么我听见了
Don't tell me what you said. I heard what you said.
- 爸 他说的的确是T&A - 就是说的T&A
- Dad. He said T&A. - He did?
绝对的 没错
Absolutely,no question.
乔丹 我是想
I'm trying to...
我就差那么点
I'm getting this close!
- 老爸 放松 - 我还差这么点就要爆发了
- Dad,relax. - I'm getting this close.
我就是这么说的啊 你得把情绪释放出来 麦克斯
That's what I'm saying. I want you to open up more,Max.
他会杀了你的
He's gonna fucking kill you.
你干嘛憋着？
Why do you hold it in? Why do you...
麦克斯 你为什么要忍着呢
Max,why do you hold it in?
够了 给我滚出去
That's it. Get the fuck out of here!
- 不 不 不 - 混蛋 滚出去
- No,no,no! - Asshole,get out of here.
什么样的妓女啊 还收信用卡？
What kind of hooker takes credit cards?
有钱的
A rich one.
在斯特拉顿 妓女分三种
At Stratton,there were three kinds of hookers.
最好的 蓝筹股级别 模特材质
The Blue Chips,top of the line,model material.
她们收费300到500块之间
They cost between $300 and $500
并且你必须戴套
and you had to wear a condom
除非你给丰厚的小费
unless you gave them a hefty tip,
我当然是每次都给
which,of course,I always did.
然后是纳斯达克股 漂亮 但不够特别好
Then came the NASDAQs,who were pretty,not great.
收费在两百到三百之间
They cost between 200 and 300 bucks.
最后是粉红条子 糟烂货
Finally,there were the Pink Sheets. Skanks.
收费在100块以下 而且如果你没戴套
They cost about 100 or less. If you didn't wear a condom,
第二天就必须得打青霉素了
you'd have to get a penicillin shot
并且赶紧祈祷自己的鸡巴不要断
the next day and pray your dick didn't fall off.
不过这不代表我们就不上她们了
Not that we didn't fuck them,too.
相信我 都上过的
Believe me,we did.
又是椎间盘突出的疼了
Ow! It's that slipped disc thing again.
我知道原因所在
I know what it is. You know,too much...
太多的EJ娱乐公司活动了
with EJ Entertainment.
家里日子过得如何？
How are things at home?
不太好啊
Well,not the best.
不太 你知道我的意思
She just doesn't... You know what I'm saying?
就像那个味道
It's like the smell...
那个味道 那个吸引力
There's a smell,there's an attraction thing.
过了一阵之后 有点淡薄了
After a while it kind of fades away a little bit.
当然了 本来就会变淡的
Yeah,well. It's supposed to fade away.
- 本来？- 婚姻嘛
- Supposed to? - That's marriage. You know...
你妈和我 我们结婚很长时间了
Your mother and I,we've been married a long,long time.
你觉得呢？我们
What do you think? We're,we're...
会每两分钟上次床？
We're jumping into bed every two minutes?
- 事情不会那样的 - 我真的很爱她
- It doesn't work that way. - I love her to death.
我想要维持婚姻 爸 但是
I want to stay married,Dad,but...
外面的世界太疯狂
It's crazy out there.
有些姑娘啊 你真该看看的
Some of these girls... You should see them.
我的天哦
Oh,my God!
这些姑娘
They're fucking...
她们干的事啊 老爸
The things they're doing now,Pops.
完全到了新的层次了
I mean... I mean,it's on a whole other level.
- 真的？- 而且她们全都刮得干干净净
- Really? - And they're all shaved,too.
- 唬我呢 - 全都刮得干干净净的
- Get out of here! - All shaven.
- 你开玩笑么？- 嗯
- Are you kidding me? - Yeah.
- 跟瓷娃娃一样干净 - 啥都没有
- Bald as a China doll. - No bush?
- 啥都没有 - 我的天
- No bush. - Oh,my God!
一夜之间 所有的人下面都干干净净的
All of a sudden,one week,nobody had anything down there anymore.
真是全新的世界啊
It's a new world.
她们眉毛以下全都干干净净
They're bald from the eyebrows down.
- 哇 - 啥都没有 连根刺都没 跟激光过似的
- Wow. - Nothing. Not a stitch. It's like lasers.
哇 新世界啊
Wow. A new world.
我真是出生得太早了
I was born too... Too early.
老实说呢 我从来也不怎么喜欢阴毛
I've never been a fan of the bush,to be honest.
- 是吗？- 是啊
- Really? - Yeah.
我不介意
I don't mind it.
爸
Dad.
我不希望这些事把你搞得压力太大
I don't want you stressing out about any of this.
我怎么能没有压力？
How can I not get stressed out?
看看你手下都是些什么傻逼
Look at the knuckleheads you got working for you.
我知道他们都是傻逼
I know they're knuckleheads
但我需要他们想要跟我过一样的日子 明白吗？
but I need them to want to live like me,you get it?
像我一样
To live like me.
乔丹
Jordy.
总有一天 你必须面对这些坏事带来的后果
One of these days,the chickens are gonna come home to roost.
你看我这样子好像我发疯了一样
You're looking at me like I'm crazy.
发疯？这简直是猥琐淫荡
Crazy? This is obscene.
对于正常人来说那确实很猥琐淫荡
It was obscene.In the normal world.
但谁要过正常人日子？
But who the fuck wanted to live there?
神奇吧 爱死了吧
Go party your fucking cocks off!
我们正成为传奇
We are about to become fucking legends
在华尔街
on Wall Street!
我们只要敢想 就可以把整个公司
We got plans up here that's gonna take this company
捧上平流层去
into the fucking stratosphere!
华尔街之狼 华尔街之狼
Wolfie! Wolfie!
去他妈的美林证券吧
Fuck Merrill Lynch. Fuck them.
凭什么钱都给他们赚了 每次都这样
Why should they be taking all our fucking money all the fucking time?
我们可以成为保险公司
This way we become the underwriters.
这是我们下一步的重大计划
It was our next big move.
找到公司来公开募股 搞搞IPO（首次公开募股）
Finding companies to take public. IPOs.
只有这样 这些华尔街的混蛋们
It was the only way these Wall Street pricks
才不敢小瞧我们 现在他们都觉得我们是一群娘炮的废物
would ever stop thinking of us as some shitkicker bucket shop.
我们现在有安可利夫国际集团
We got Arncliffe International.
你看 我们还是很不一样的
See,we were a little different.
我们喜欢嗑药嗑得越脱线越好 就在这些工作讨论过程里
We liked to get as fucked up as possible during our business powwows
可以刺激思维的流动发散
in order to stimulate our free-flowing ideas,
这就是为什么我们吞这些安眠酮药片 像吃彩虹糖一样
which is why we were popping these ludes like they were M&M's.
史蒂夫·马登
Steve Madden.
这公司他妈的是我们的
We own the fucking companies...
是我们的
We own the companies...
不知道安眠酮是什么？我来告诉你们
Don't know what a lude is? I'll tell you.
啊 等一等 等一等
Oh. Wait. Wait,wait,wait,wait.
看上去 这些药片 开始在丹尼身上产生奇效了
Looks like those ludes are working their magic on Donnie right now.
安眠酮
The Quaalude,
通常又叫安眠酮
or lude,as it is commonly referred to,
是由一位印度医生在1951年首次制成的
was first synthesized in 1951 by an Indian doctor,
这可不是普通药
that's dots,not feathers,
它是用作镇静剂
as a sedative,
主要是开给压力过大导致失眠的家庭主妇的
and was prescribed to stressed-out housewives with sleep disorders.
但很快地有人发现
But pretty soon someone figured out
如果你能撑住15分钟不睡着
that if you resisted the urge to sleep for just 15 minutes,
会获得相当的快感
you got a pretty kick-ass high from it.
当然没过多久人们就开始滥用此药了
Didn't take long for people to start abusing ludes,of course.
1982年美国政府封禁此药
And in 1982,the U-S. Government Schedule 1'd them.
世界上其他国家也一样
Along with the rest of the world.
也就是说它们所剩的数量已经十分有限
Which meant there was only a finite amount of these things left.
没错 买都买不到了
No shit,you can't even buy 'em anymore.
你们啊 太不走运了
You people are all shit out of luck.
你说什么呢 怎么了？
What are you saying? What is it?
史蒂夫·马登
Steve Madden.
"斯弟夫·马丁"
斯蒂夫
Steve.
还记得这些广告吗？
You remember those ads?
一群大脑袋 眼神迷离的姑娘
Those giant-headed girls with the bug eyes
穿着笨重的鞋
wearing those big clunky shoes?
我学生时期的好友史蒂夫·马登
My friend from school,Steve Madden.
他学校的好友史蒂夫·马登
His friend from school,Steve Madden.
史蒂夫·马登现在是女鞋界响当当的名字
Steve Madden was the name in women's shoes at the moment.
全华尔街都在排队抢着把它公开募股
And all of Wall Street was begging to take his company public.
继续 继续 这是什么？
Go ahead,go ahead,what is it?
不过 猜猜他和谁从小一起玩大的？
Except,guess who grew up with him?
- 女鞋 - 女士的鞋
- Women's shoes. - Women's shoes.
我们自家的副总
My very own Vice President.
女鞋
Women's shoes!
宝贝儿丹尼·阿佐夫
Diamond Donnie Azoff.
- 史蒂夫·马登 - 史蒂夫
- Steve Madden. - Steve.
斯蒂夫
Steve.
嘿 你 你 你
Hey,JB,JB,JB,JB.
乔丹 赶紧出来看
You gotta come check this fucking chick out.
看啊 有个妞子
Look at this. Look.
她就算是我亲妹妹我也会上她
I would fuck that girl if she was my sister.
就算她把艾滋病传我
I would let that girl give me fucking AIDS.
我也心甘情愿
You want to see the Wolf handle this?
辣妹啊
She's hot.
克丽丝蒂
Cristy.
乔丹 这位是我的朋友娜奥米
Jordan,this is my friend Naomi.
- 你好 很高兴见到你 - 娜奥米啊
- Hi. Nice to meet you. - Naomi.
很高兴见到你 娜奥米
Naomi,nice to meet you.
你这屋子真不错
You got an awesome place here.
我以前还从没到过这么大的房子
I've don't think I've ever been in a house this big before.
- 是吗？- 嗯
- Oh,really? - Yeah.
外面海滩很美
Beautiful beach out there.
我叫布莱尔·霍林沃斯
Blair Hollingsworth.
你好啊 老兄 幸会
Hi,Blair. Nice to meet you.
- 叫布莱尔对吗？- 是啊
- Your name's Blair,right? - Yeah.
你喜欢开摩托艇吗？
You like to Jet Ski?
我没开过
I've never done it before.
你这辈子还从没开过摩托艇？
You've never Jet Ski'd in your life?
没 我没开过摩托艇
No,I've never Jet Ski'd.
你从没开过摩托艇
You've never been on a Jet Ski?
你到底要问她多少遍
How many times are you gonna ask her?
她都说了没开过
She's never been on a Jet Ski.
我不知道 可能还得再问两次吧
I don't know. Might ask her a couple more times.
好吧
Okay. Sure.
嗨 我是希尔蒂 很高兴见到你
Hi. I'm Hildy. Nice to meet you.
- 你好 - 乔丹 特瑞莎想找你帮忙
- Hi. - Jordan,Teresa needs your help.
好 等我两分钟 马上去
Yeah,I'll be out in a couple of minutes.
告诉她我两分钟就到
Just tell her I'll be out in a couple of minutes.
你怎么不自己告诉你老婆啊？
Why don't you tell your wife that?
怎么告诉啊 我正在
I might do that,but I'm having
- 跟别人说话 - 怎么的 当我是你秘书啊？
- a conversation right now. - What am I,your secretary?
我觉得我们该走了
You know what,I think we should get going.
等等 你们这是要去哪？
Wait,wait. Where you guys going?
我们得走了 还有两个派对要去
We gotta go. We got two other parties to go to.
- 我们可以留下来喝一杯 - 是啊 喝一杯
- We can stay for a drink. - Yeah,stay for a drink.
不了 还有两个派对我们要去
No. We got two other parties we're supposed to get to.
干嘛不让她留下呢
But we can stay for a drink...
她很
She's
完美
perfect.
- 喜欢喝香槟吗？- 喜欢
- You like champagne? - I do.
她很完美
She's perfect.
丹尼 你他妈的干什么呢
Donnie,what the fuck are you doing?
人渣
You piece of...
还请二位原谅我朋友 他有点
You're gonna have to excuse my friend. He gets...
赶紧给我滚
Get the fuck out!
乔丹 你一定得上她 她太正了
Jordan,you gotta fuck her,bro. She's so hot!
丹尼
Yeah,Donnie!
好歹让他撸完啊 希尔蒂
Let him fucking finish,Hildy.
太粗鲁了吧
That's fucking rude.
没一点礼貌
Have some fucking manners.
湾岭区啊 离斯泰登岛很近的对吧？
So,Bay Ridge,that's near Staten Island,right?
在布鲁克林 韦拉扎诺大桥下面
Brooklyn,across the Verrazano Bridge.
《周末夜狂热》就那里拍的啊
Saturday Night Fever territory.
没错 帮派聚集地
That's right. Guinea Gulch.
韦拉扎诺大桥被称作黑帮定点
We call the Verrazano Bridge the Guinea Gangplank.
对
Right.
那我猜 你是有意大利血统？
So I presume you're Italian?
父亲那边是的
On my dad's side.
另外还有荷兰 德国 英国血统
I'm also Dutch,German,English.
我是混血儿
I'm a mutt.
噢 混血儿啊
Yeah. You're a mutt.
是啊 我在伦敦还有家人呢
Yeah,I still have family over there though,in London.
我的阿姨 艾玛 她最好了
My Aunt Emma. She's the best.
非常英式 那种优雅贵妇
Very British,you know. She's a classy lady.
那怪不得了
That explains it then.
怪不得什么？
Explains what?
我是说你 你是公爵夫人嘛
It explains you. I mean,you're a duchess,right?
湾岭区公爵夫人
The Duchess of Bay Ridge.
不好意思
Excuse me.
能帮我拿支吸管吗？
Could I get a straw,please?
谢谢
Thank you.
以我 听说你跟克里斯蒂要了我的号码 还挺吃惊的
So I was,um,a little surprised you asked Cristy for my number.
为什么？
Why is that?
你已经结婚了吧？
Aren't you married?
这个 是啊 但怎么呢
Well... Yeah,but what?
已婚人士就不能交朋友了？
Married people can't have friends?
那我们会是朋友了？
We're gonna be friends?
是啊 你不想跟我交朋友吗？
Yeah. You don't want to be my friend?
你我是做不成朋友的
We're not gonna be friends.
晚上的时候 我做设计
And at night I work on my designs.
我设计了一系列女士内衣
I have an entire line of lingerie.
小背心 紧身胸衣 内裤
You know,camisoles,bustiers,panties.
她竟然还会设计内裤？
She designs women's panties,too?
老天爷啊
Oh,my God!
乔丹 赶紧想个法子 上去她家里
Come on,Jordan,think of a way to get up to her apartment.
想上来喝杯茶什么的吗？
You wanna come up for some tea or something?
茶？好啊
Tea? Yeah.
- 泡杯热茶？- 好
- Like hot tea? - Yeah.
好 那不错啊 好
Oh,yeah. That sounds nice. Yeah.
我操 喝茶 我太想上去喝茶了
Tea. Fuck,yeah,I wanted to come up for tea.
大吉岭红茶 玫瑰花茶 什么的
Like Darjeeling or Rose hip,something nice like that?
对
Sure.
洛基
This is Rocky.
看看这是谁 打个招呼 洛基
Oh,who's this? Say hi,Rocky.
嗨 小可爱
Hi,sweetheart.
好了
Okay.
你可以去把壁炉点上 我马上出来
Why don't you light a fire or something and I'll be right out.
- 这个壁炉吗 - 当然
- Yeah. Fire,here? - Sure.
我喜欢这幅画
I like your painting here. It's,uh...
上帝 帮帮我吧 怎样才能上她
God,help me. How do I fuck this girl?
你没事吧？
You all right?
没事没事 正在点火呢
Yeah,yeah. Just trying to light the fire here.
行了 行了 走吧
That's it. That's it,you're leaving.
别搅合下去了 回家回老婆身边去
Don't get involved. Go home to your wife.
你们大概也猜到了
As you can probably guess,
我操她操了个天崩地裂
I fucked her goddamn brains out...
上天呀
Jesus Lord!
操了11秒
For 11 seconds.
你刚才是来了吗？
Did you just come?
是啊 我来了
Oh,yeah,I just came.
那 你呢？
Did you? Did you come?
- 没有 - 没有？
- No. - No?
好吧
Okay.
我还硬着 给我点时间我们再来
I'm still hard so just give me a sec.
行
Sure.
快点 宝贝 快点
Come on,baby,come on.
哦 耶
Oh,yeah. Oh,yeah.
天呐
Oh,God!
滚开 洛基 坏狗狗
Fuck off,Rocky! Bad dog.
给他吃点饼干什么的？
You have a biscuit or something like that?
没关系的
It's okay.
- 我们继续 - 洛基 来呀
- Just keep going. - Rocky,go play.
一边玩去 洛基 一边去
Go play,Rocky. Go,go,go,go.
你这疯子
You're crazy.
我真是永不满足
I couldn't get enough.
上她就像海洛因一样致瘾
I mean,her pussy was like heroin to me.
而且这也不仅仅因为性爱
And it wasn't just about the sex,either.
娜奥米和我很合得来
Naomi and I got along. I mean,we...
我们有很多共同爱好之类的
We had similar interests and shit.
唔 小火车啊
Ooh. Choo-choo train.
耶
Yeah.
我认为你可以 我认为你可以
I think I can. I think I can. I think I can. I think I can.
这儿都是啥
Yeah,yeah. Let's toke it all on there,huh?
喔呼
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
爽
Oh,shit!
你
You!
给我滚下车
Get out of the fucking car!
老天爷
Jesus Christ.
你这恶心的杂种
Son of a bitch! Oh,fuck!
别激动 亲爱的
Relax,sweetheart. Relax.
- 他妈的狗杂种 - 够了 天啊
- Son of a fucking bitch! - Okay,okay... Geez!
住手 拜托了
Okay,babe,stop!
- 够了 - 婊子
- Please. - Bitch!
- 你怎么就回家来了 - 上次派对上那个贱人？
- What are you doing... - That whore from the party?
老天爷啊
Jesus Christ!
你他妈的脑子什么毛病啊？
What the fuck is wrong with you?
我以为你去海边了啊
I thought you were at the fucking beach!
我不知道你在这儿
I didn't know you were here!
原来你都是上她那去了？
That's where you've fucking been?
上次派对上那个贱人？
With that fucking whore from the party?
你来这里干吗 我以为你在海边
I thought you were at the beach house.
你怎么能这么对待我？
How could you do this to me?
- 亲爱的 来吧 - 你到底是谁啊 乔丹？
- Sweetie,come on... - Who the fuck are you,Jordan?
你他妈已经完全变了个人
You're like a completely different fucking person!
是我犯了错 我不知道怎么解释
I made a mistake. I don't know what to tell you,babe. I...
对不起
I'm sorry.
- 对不起 - 这是你想要的吗？
- I'm sorry. - Is that who... Is that what you want?
你爱她吗？
Do you love her?
回答我
Answer me.
我感觉糟透了
I felt horrible.
三天之后 我提出了离婚
Three days later,I filed for a divorce
让娜奥米搬来同住
and moved Naomi into the apartment.
不管你们怎么说
Say what you will,
公爵夫人确实还是很有范儿的
but the Duchess did have style.
她请来设计师 给房子看好风水
She brought in a decorator,feng shui'd the whole place.
甚至还雇了个同性恋管家
She even hired a gay Butler.
这家伙很聪明 成熟 专业
This guy was smart,sophisticated,professional.
真的 真的很不错
Really,really great.
是茉莉花？
Is that Jasmine?
是的 我本想今晚还能难倒你
Yes,Sir. I tried to stump you this evening. Very good.
真厉害 鼻子灵
Very good. Great nose.
除了有一次
Except for that one time.
老天爷啊
Oh,my God!
噢 嘿
Oh,hey.
今天已经礼拜三了吗？
Is it Wednesday already?
- 额 - 不要停
- Uh... - Oh,don't stop.
搞什么
What the fuck!
他妈的太乱了
That is fucked up!
他肯定是以为我们
He must have thought we were still
这周末还在安普顿
at the Hamptons this weekend,you know.
他们在哪做的 卧室里吗？
Where were they doing it,sweetheart? In the bedroom?
到处都是 那边桌上坐了两个
They were everywhere. There were two guys over there on the table.
这边还有更多
There were more over here.
- 就这里 坐了四个 - 噢天哪
- There were four right here. - Ugh!
没开玩笑吧 这里？
Are you fucking serious? Right there?
- 你为什么不告诉我？- 宝贝 这还不是最差的
- Why didn't you tell me? - Oh,baby,it gets worse.
他们走了以后 我检查了公寓
After they left,I checked the apartment.
怎么？
Right. What?
然后发生了什么事 宝贝
What is it,babe? What?
我的钱呢？
Where's my money?
我不知道在哪里
I don't know where your money...
操 我的钱在哪儿 在哪儿？
Where is my fucking money? Where is it?
我真不知道 贝尔福特先生
I don't know where your money is,Mr. Belfort.
- 我什么都没做 - 他在撒谎 乔丹
- I didn't do anything. - If you don't get...
嘴里没一句真话
He's lying through his fucking teeth.
我们从头理一遍
Let's start from the beginning.
从头理一遍 怎样？
Let's start from the beginning,all right?
是你请了朋友过来 对吧？
You invited some friends over,right?
事情一件件地 就失控了
One thing led to another. Things got out of hand.
这个我们十分理解
We understand that,we do.
我们每次都这样 一群败类
We do blow all the time. We're fucking degenerates ourselves.
看看我们吧
Look at us,right?
我公寓里的钱被偷走了
But money was stolen from my apartment.
就放在我放袜子的抽屉里 对吧？
Right from my sock drawer. All right?
我说过了 我不知道你的钱在哪儿
Like I said,I don't know where your money is.
从头开始说 都有谁来了？
Just start from the beginning. Who came over?
真只是很普通的一天
It was just a normal day.
我知道你们第二天就要回来了
I knew you were coming home the next day.
一切都会完好如初 打扫干净
So everything would be fine. It'd be cleaned up.
早餐之后我就有点高了
I got a little high at breakfast.
心情不错 吃了点鸡蛋
So I got a little happy. I had some eggs,
还吃了点冰激凌
I had a little bit of ice cream.
我还有朋友也喜欢冰激凌
And then I said,"Who do I know that likes ice cream?"
就是我的朋友鲁迪 于是我叫来了鲁迪
It's my friend,Rudy. So I called Rudy.
- 鲁迪是谁？- 鲁迪是谁？
- Who's Rudy? - Yeah,who's Rudy?
- 你认识鲁迪的啊 快来 - 我？我不
- You know who Rudy is. Come on. - Me? I don't...
- 你知道 - 谁他妈的是鲁迪啊？
- You know... - Who the fuck is Rudy?
我认识的人没有叫鲁迪的
I don't know anyone named Rudy.
上个月 在棒棒糖俱乐部
Last month. The Lollipop Club.
你认识鲁迪的 那个跳舞的
You know who Rudy was. Dancing...
你认识鲁迪？
You know who Rudy is?
我他妈才不认识呢
I don't fucking know any...
你什么意思？
What do you mean?
他去过棒棒糖俱乐部？
So he went to The Lollipop Club?
没错肯定是他 在舞台上
Oh,he was at The Lollipop Club for sure.
跟大家贴着身子跳舞
On the stage,grinding with everybody.
我喝高了 我喜欢跳舞
I got fucked up. I like to dance.
我不知道 我可能见过他吧 也可能没见过
I don't know. Maybe I met him,maybe I didn't.
我他妈见过的人那么多
I meet a lot of fucking people.
- 你在说什么？- 五万没了
- What are you saying? - $50,000 was stolen
放在我袜子抽屉里的
from my fucking sock drawer!
还有我女朋友的首饰
All my girlfriend's jewelry is gone.
- 怎么回事？- 你那该死的同性恋朋友
- Where the fuck is it? - ...Rudy. What the fuck?
鲁迪你他妈的偷了我的钱？
Did your fucking little faggot friend Rudy take my shit?
对吧？说话
Did he? Answer me!
好吧 我懂了 我明白为什么了
Okay. Now I get it. Now I get why I'm...
- 是关于同性恋的人 - 噢
- This is a gay thing. - Oh!
你看 大家
See,all of you...
你觉得这事儿是因为你是同性恋？
You think this is 'cause you're a fag?
我表哥就是同性恋
My cousin's a fucking faggot.
我还跟他和他男朋友一起去度假呢 我爱死同性恋了
And I go on vacation with him and his boyfriend. I love fags.
你的负责 对吧？
You were in charge,right?
我的钱不是好偷的 你懂了吗？
I will not be stolen from. You get that?
我爱死同性恋了 但我就是讨厌你
I fucking like gay people. I don't like you.
雇一个傻逼墨西哥人
He should've hired a fucking Mexican
你该和我一样
like I have in my fucking house.
妈的
Shit! What the fuck...
招吧 杂种 说
Talk,you fuck,talk!
不然扔你下去
I'm gonna drop you,you faggot!
钱在哪？
Where is it?
切斯特和托比对尼古拉斯实施了黑帮教育
Chester and Toby,they went all yakuza on Nicholas.
手段疯狂
You know,they got crazy.
我不知道
I don't know!
我不得不叫来警察 以防他们真弄死那家伙
I had to call the cops just to keep them from killing the poor guy.
我给了俩警察一人一千块
I gave them each 1,000 bucks
告诉他们尼古拉斯都干了些什么
and told them what Nicholas had done.
于是由他们去教训了
Then they kicked his ass.
再次感谢 警官们
Thanks again,Officer.
其实我也不在意这五万块钱
It's not like I cared about the 50 grand anyway.
我每天跟打地鼠似的打一下
I was making that much almost every day
就有这么多
through one rathole or another.
现在"地鼠"是指朋友 比如 布拉德
Now a rathole is a friend,like Brad here,
帮我以自己的名字炒股
who held stock in his name for me.
你认为是谁 嗯？杰克·尼克？
Who are you supposed to be,huh? Jack Nickle-Jew?
我抬高股价
I'd drive the price up then he'd sell
然后他就抛出 于是大多数利润
and kick most of the profits back to...
猜得没错 归我了
You guessed it,me.
全是现钞 全都不在账上
All cash. None of it's on the books.
当然法律规定这是绝对不行的
A big no-no,of course,in the eyes of the law.
于是我们有了新的证券律师 曼尼·利斯金
Enter our new securities attorney,Manny Riskin.
时薪七百美元 并且专门说的是各种坏消息
700 bucks an hour to be the voice of doom.
你听我说 你要是惹了证交委员会不爽
Listen to me. You piss up the SEC's leg,
最后还是自己不开心
you end up with your tits in a ringer.
你不用担心 证交委员会我心里有数
Do not worry about it. I have the SEC under control.
这些蠢货这是干嘛呢？
What the fuck are these imbeciles doing?
嘿 嘿
Hey! Hey!
你们干嘛呢？
What are you doing? Hey!
证交委员会的人在这呢
We got the SEC in here.
证交委员会派来两名律师
The Securities and Exchange Commission
审查我们的文件
sent two lawyers down to review our files.
于是我安排他们坐在会议室里
So I set them up in our conference room
并安上窃听器
and I had it bugged
空调拧到暴大
and the air conditioning turned up so high
里面感觉就跟南极一样
that it felt like Antarctica in there.
你们这一直都这么冷吗？
Is it always this cold in here?
我不知道
I don't know.
他们还在里面找
Then,while they were looking
枪管留下的烟
for a smoking gun in that room...
克里弗公司着火了
Arncliffe International is on fire.
我这边已经要发射火箭了
I was gonna fire off a bazooka in here,
准备开始最新的公开募股
offering up our latest IPO.
IPO就是初次公开募股
An IPO is an initial public offering.
股票第一次开放给公众交易
It's the first time a stock is offered for sale to the general population.
我们把股票开放给公众买卖之后
Now,as the firm taking the company public,
设定最初的价格
we set the initial sales price
然后把股票卖回给自己的朋友们
then sold those shares right back to our friends. The...
你看
Look.
我知道你们不懂我在说什么 对吧？
I know you're not following what I'm saying anyway,right?
没关系 这无所谓
That's okay. That doesn't matter.
真正的问题在于
The real question is this.
这一切都合法吗？
"Was all this legal?"
当然不是了
Absolutely fucking not.
但这挣的钱多到我们都不知道要怎么花
But we were making more money than we knew what to do with.
当你挣的钱多到不知道
And what do you do when you're making
怎么花的时候你会怎么办？
more money than you know what to do with?
我的天哪
Oh,my God!
你愿意嫁给我吗？
Will you marry me?
我的天哪
Oh,my God.
这是在说"好"吗？
Is that a yes?
你确定吗？
Are you sure?
当然 我确定
Yeah,I'm sure. Yeah,I'm sure.
- 你确定吗？- 嗯
- Are you sure? - Yeah.
我在拉斯维加斯的迷拉吉酒店 办了单身派对
I held my bachelor party at the Mirage in Las Vegas.
过去的飞机上就是酒池肉林
The flight there alone was a bacchanal.
在人生稳定下来之前
One last blowout for the gods
最后再放纵一把
before I settled down for good.
一百名斯特拉顿员工
A hundred Strattonites,
五十个妓女 等落地之后还有另外五十个等着
50 hookers,plus 50 more waiting once we landed.
噢 当然还少不了药片
Oh,and the drugs.
这么说吧 这架飞机简直就是 会飞的药店
I mean,I tell you,our plane was like a pharmacy with wings.
总共 这个周末花了我两百万
All told,the weekend cost me 2 million bucks,
包括翻修整个酒店28楼的价钱
including the cost of refurbishing the entire 28th floor.
可以吻新娘了
Kiss the bride.
啊 但是婚礼
Ah! But the wedding
真的跟童话一般
was something out of a fairy tale.
娜奥米 我的公爵夫人
With Naomi,my Duchess,
我 她帅气的公爵
me,her handsome Duke,
城堡是巴哈马群岛的海滨俱乐部
and The Bahamas Ocean Club,our castle.
当然 在单身派对之后
Of course,after the bachelor party,me,the Duke,
公爵 也就是我 需要打几针青霉素
needed a few penicillin shots so he could
以安全健康地结婚
safely consummate the marriage.
嘿 我是巴里·克雷曼 负责婚礼摄像
Hey! Barry Kleinman,filming the wedding.
请为你儿子说几句吧
A few words for your son?
乔丹 记住我告诉你的话
Jordan. Remember what I told you.
这件事需要你的下半身和她的下半身一起完成
It involves your penis and her vagina.
你知道的 你很清楚 你能做到的 乔丹
And you know,you know what you can do,Jordy.
我的天哪
Oh,my God!
艾玛阿姨
Aunt Emma?
天哪 你来了
I can't believe you came!
乔丹 乔丹 看看是谁来了
Jordan! Jordan! Look who came!
艾玛阿姨来了
It's Aunt Emma.
艾玛阿姨
Aunt Emma.
- 亲爱的乔丹 真好啊 - 嘿 你好吗？
- Oh,Jordan,dear,how lovely. - Hey,how you doing?
真高兴终于见到真人了
It's a pleasure to finally meet you in person.
满面红光嘛
Into the donuts,I see.
噢 我
Oh,I... I...
好吧
Well...
我也是从60年代走过来的
I lived through the '60s,my dear.
好好享受这一天吧
Enjoy the day.
这完全是惊喜 我都不知道
She surprised me. I didn't even know.
只需要你一个步骤 你们准备好了吗？
Just one more step. Are you ready?
- 我们这是去哪？- 闭上你的眼睛
- Where are we going? - Keep your eyes closed.
一 二 三
One,two,three!
这是什么？
What is this?
给你的新婚礼物
It's your wedding present.
什么？
What?
新婚礼物啊 亲爱的
It's your wedding present,sweetheart.
什么？
What?
- 你这是认真的？- 是的
- Are you serious? - I'm serious.
游艇？
A fucking yacht?
这就是百万富翁们的船
For millionaires whose ships have come in,
昂贵的游船提供最好的航行体验
pricey pleasure boats are for the most fun afloat.
这艘150尺长的游艇
It's no coincidence that it's 150 feet of green hull
钢材质 闪耀着金钱的光芒 出发
is the color of cash. Anchors aweigh!
噢 我的天哪 宝贝
Oh,my God! Baby!
- 你喜欢吗？- 你疯了
- I think you like it? - You're crazy.
- 喜欢吗？- 当然
- You like it? - Yes!
三个礼拜的时间 我们驾驶着娜奥米号 穿越加勒比海
For three weeks,we sailed the Naomi through the Caribbean,
最终驶回长岛
eventually taking her home to Long Island,
我们在那里买了房子
where we bought a house.
在长岛的黄金海岸 占地7英亩
Seven acres on the Gold Coast of Long Island.
世界上最贵的房产
The most expensive real estate in the world.
有女佣 厨师 园艺师 要什么有什么
With maids,cooks,landscapers,you name it.
我们甚至请了两个保安轮岗值班
We even had two guards who worked in shifts.
两个人名字都叫洛克
Both named Rocco.
简直是人间天堂
It was heaven on earth.
快醒醒 你这混账
Wake-up,you piece of shit!
- 哦 - 威尼斯是谁？
- Ow! - Who's Venice?
- 哈？- 谁？
- Huh? - "Who?"
谁啊？谁？
Who? Who?
谁？叫什么叫 你猫头鹰啊
"Who?" What are you,a fucking owl?
她是谁？
Who is she?
昨晚你又上了哪个妓女？
Some little hooker you were fucking last night?
你说什么呢？不
What the fuck are you talking about? No.
不可能的
No way,baby,no!
你做梦还叫着她的名字
You were calling her name in your sleep!
你这是疯了吗？
Are you out of your fucking mind? I don't...
我都不知道威尼斯是谁
I don't even know who Venice is.
这个词什么意思啊？威尼斯
What the fuck does that even mean? Venice.
这简直是我这辈子听过最蠢的话
That's the stupidest shit I've ever heard in my fucking life!
威尼斯
Venice...
威尼斯 宝贝你在哪？
Venice,baby,where are you?
威尼斯？
Venice!
你去哪里了？
Where'd you go?
宝贝儿 你要来硬的啊？
Oh,baby. Oh,you're gonna play rough,huh?
- 啊 老天爷啊 - 你喜欢这里？
- Oh,Jesus Christ! - You like that?
我喜欢 我喜欢
I like it. I like it. Ow.
小狼 小狼
Wolfie,Wolfie,Wolfie,Wolfie.
什么狼？
Wolfie?
那是我的"安全"词 "安全"词
Yeah,it's my safe word,baby. It's my safe word.
我才不管什么安全不安全
I don't give a fuck about your safe word!
- 快点- 他妈的给我闭嘴
- Come on! - Shut the fuck up!
- 啊 - 闭嘴 你这小贱人
- Ahh! - Shut up,you little bitch!
你这肮脏的小贱人
You're a fucking dirty little birdy!
啊
Owie!
对了
That's right.
对了 是我忘了
That's right! I forgot.
是我忘了
I forgot,baby.
丹尼和我
Donnie and I were investing
我们在威尼斯投资了公寓楼
in a condominium complex in Venice.
所以才有了这些误会
That's why all this confusion.
你在意大利又有投资了？
Oh,you're investing in Italy?
不是意大利 是加州
Not Italy. California.
- 哦 加州？- 是啊
- Oh,California? - Yeah.
你这满口谎话的混蛋
You're a lying piece of shit!
我的女爵 宝贝 快点
Duchess,baby,come on.
别他妈叫我女爵
Don't you fucking "Duchess" me.
别叫我女爵
Don't you "Duchess" me!
你真以为我不知道你在干什么吗？
Do you really think that I don't know what you're up to?
- 你现在也是孩子他爹了 - 是啊
- You're a father now,Jordan. - Yeah.
- 你都当爹的人了 - 我知道
- You're a father now. - I know...
还跟小孩子一样
And you're still acting like an infant!
真该死
God damn it!
亲爱的 你知道吗 你实在有点易怒的问题啊
Baby,you know,you got real anger issues.
是谁开个飞机回家
Who is the one who flew in here
夜里三点还开直升飞机
at 3:00 in the morning on their stupid helicopter
把斯凯勒吵醒了是你？弄明白了吗？
and woke up Skylar? That was you!
噢 斯凯勒 他妈的废话
Oh,Skylar! Oh,fucking bullshit!
你根本就无所谓吧
Does it even matter to you
我刚刚才修理好车道
that I just had that driving range
铺好百慕大进口的草皮 乔丹
sodded with Bermuda grass,Jordan,
- 你现在全给毁了 - 噢 我的老天
- and now you fucking wrecked it! - Oh,my God... Bermuda grass.
你根本就没花时间研究过
No,you didn't research the whole thing
花时间跟高尔夫球场的人谈事
and deal with the fucking golf course people!
我的天啊
Oh,my God,
你还要见那些球场的人
you had to deal with the golf course people,too!
太悲剧了好辛苦啊 我的天
What a Greek tragedy,honey! Oh,my God!
你或许还不得不亲手付他们现金吧
You probably had to pay them in cash with your hands!
真是巨大的负担
What a fucking burden.
每天除了刷爆我的信用卡
And actually do some work besides swiping
能不能实实在在做点事啊？
my fucking credit card all day,huh?
因为我真是跟不上你的职业变化节奏啊
Because I can't keep track of your professions,honey.
上个月你是品酒专家
Cause last month you were a wine connoisseur.
现在你又是个抱负满满的园艺建筑师？
Now you're an aspiring landscape architect!
- 让我理理顺啊 - 滚粗儿
- Let me get that right... No! - Fuck you!
你胆敢把水泼我脸上
Don't fucking dare throw that
你他妈胆敢这样
fucking water at me. Don't you fucking dare.
行吗 亲爱的？
All right,honey?
现在你只是
Now will you just...
我们好好谈谈解决此事吧
We could talk this out,all right?
动口不动手 怎样？
We just use our words. You know?
要交流
Communicate.
好了
Okay?
亲爱的
Come on,sweetheart.
跟我聊聊
Talk to me. Talk to me.
不要再鼓你的肌肉了 乔丹
Stop flexing your muscles,Jordan.
看着跟个弱智一样
You look like a fucking imbecile.
宝贝 拜托啊
Babe,come on.
你该高兴的 你老公
You should feel happy you got a husband
身材这么好
who's in such great shape like this,huh?
过来
Come here.
来 给我亲一口
Come on,give me a kiss.
你现在看上去美呆了
You look so beautiful right now.
- 来嘛 - 亲你？
- Come on. - Kiss you?
- 你看起来真漂亮 - 亲你？
- You look so beautiful... - Kiss you?
是啊 让我
Yeah,give me one...
滚蛋
Fuck you!
这就是我的早间仪式
Ah,yes,my morning ritual.
首先 我起床后就会跟娜奥米吵
First I'd get up and fight with Naomi
自己昨晚都干了什么
about whatever it is I did the night before.
然后做个蒸气浴
Next was a steam so I could sweat out
把那些还在身体里的药品出汗排出
the drugs still in my system.
然后评定一下损失程度
Then I'd assess the damage.
润一润眼珠子
Drown out my eyeballs.
吃治疗背痛的药 一天就开始了
Take my "back pills" to get the day started,
然后去找娜奥米求和好
then seek to make up with Naomi.
爸爸早上好
Good morning,Daddy.
给宝贝的亲亲呢？
Where's my kiss?
哇
Whee!
嘿 甜心
Hey,sweetheart.
爸爸能两个小美女都亲一亲吗？
Does Daddy get a kiss from both of his little girls,huh?
噢 这可不行
Oh,no.
爸爸连碰妈妈都允许 想都别想
No,Daddy doesn't even get to touch Mommy
很久很久
for a very,very,
不许碰
very long time.
爸爸对他在隔壁房间讲的话感到非常抱歉了
Daddy's really sorry about what he said in the other room.
他没有一句是认真的
He didn't mean any of it.
爸爸可以不用再浪费时间说什么了
Daddy shouldn't waste his time.
然后 从现在开始
And from now on,
这屋子里我只会
it's gonna be nothing but short,
穿超短超短裙
short skirts around the house.
还有呢 你知道吗
And you know something else,Daddy?
妈妈已经厌烦了要穿内裤这件事
Mommy is just so sick and tired of wearing panties.
- 是吗？- 是啊
- Yeah? - Yeah.
其实
In fact,
她已经决定把内裤都
she's decided to throw them
扔了
all away.
好好看看吧 爸爸
So take a good look,Daddy.
你以后能在家里经常见到的
You're gonna be seeing an awful lot of this around the house.
噢 宝贝
Oh,baby...
妈妈
Yeah,Mommy.
- 耶 - 但是 绝不许碰
- Yeah... - But no touching.
噢 天啊
Oh,gosh.
噢
Ow.
怎么了 爸爸？
What's wrong,Daddy?
嗯 宝贝
Mmm,baby.
天啊
God!
看看这个啊
Look at this shit.
妈妈喜欢和爸爸玩游戏
Okay. Mommy likes to play games with Daddy.
妈妈有没有注意过
Mommy,have you ever noticed
那边的小熊有什么奇怪吗？
anything odd about Mr...
毛茸茸的小熊在哪儿？
Mr. Fuzzy Bear over there?
他的眼睛看上去有点怪啊 是吧？
His eyes seem to be a little bit odd,don't they?
他的眼睛似乎有点不一样呢
Yeah,there's something a little bit different about his eyes.
啊 对 没错 说"嗨 妈妈"
Yes! I think it's true. Say "Hi," Mommy.
跟洛克和洛克说你好啊
Say "Hi" to Rocco and Rocco.
你们好啊
Say "Hi." Hi,fellas.
看见没？
See that,huh?
这么多天里
Of all the fucking days,
她竟然选了今天 让我这么蛋疼
she chooses today to give me blue balls!
今天是斯特拉顿有史以来最重要的一天
I mean,today was the biggest day in Stratton's history,
我得思路清晰
and I needed to be thinking straight.
嘿 乔丹
Hey,Jordan!
- 欢迎啊 - 史蒂夫来了嘛？
- Welcome. - Steve here yet?
今天是我们给史蒂夫·马登 开始IPO的日子
This was the day that we launched the Steve Madden IPO.
人都到齐了 大家都团结一心十分激动
Troops are all here,everyone's all rallied,excited.
一切必须井井有条
Everything had to run tight.
必须做到完美
It had to be perfect.
那个小屁孩在干嘛？
What the fuck is that kid doing?
干嘛呢他？
What's he doing?
公司史上规模最大的IPO今天开始
The biggest IPO in this firm's history.
这他妈的在干吗啊他？
What the fuck is he doing?
他是戴了领结吗？
Is he... Is he wearing a bow tie?
嗨
Hi.
你还好么
How're you doing?
挺好
Good.
你在清鱼缸啊？
You cleaning the fish bowl?
我只是 刚好有点空
I just... I had a minute and...
你有空啊
You had a minute.
今天你必须洗鱼缸么？今天？
And today you needed to clean the fish bowl? Today?
我把文书工作都做完了 刚好有两分钟空闲
I had finished my paperwork and I had a couple of minutes.
好吧 幸会啊
Okay. Nice to meet you.
在有新业务的今天？
On new issue day?
他妈的 今天开新IPO啊？
On cocksucking,motherfucking new issue day?
你就干这个啊？
This is what you do?
嘿 大家伙 听好了
Hey,everybody,listen up!
在新业务开始的时候如果你还敢玩宠物 结果就是这样
This is what happens when you fuck with your pets on new issue day!
拿好你的领结和你的东西
Take your little bow tie,get your shit,
滚出我的办公室 知道了吗？
and get the fuck out of my office! You understand?
他妈的滚出去
Get the fuck out!
所有人归位
Everybody on point!
我们是挣钱来的 所有人归位
We are here to make money. Everybody on point.
一个真正的狼窝啊 正是如此我才这么喜欢
A real wolf pit,which is exactly how I liked it.
乔丹 看看我在走廊逮着谁了 逮着个天才啊
Jordan,look what I caught in the lobby. I caught a genius.
进来的这位就是史蒂夫·马登
Enter Steve Madden.
美国伟大的鞋匠
The great American cobbler.
炙手可热的女鞋界掌门人
Red-hot ladies footwear Impresario.
多谢丹尼 我们能把公司股票对公众出售了
And thanks to Donnie,we were taking his company public.
斯特拉顿·奥克蒙已经爬出了挣扎阶段
Stratton Oakmont was crawling out of the primordial ooze.
再不是池塘里的烂泥了
Pond scum no more.
所以他们才需要见见你啊
That's why they gotta see your face.
你给他们鼓劲 他们才能努力把股价抬高啊
You get them fired up so they push the shit out of this stock. Okay?
并且不仅如此 丹尼和我秘密地持有了
And not only that,Donnie and I secretly owned
85%的史蒂夫·马登鞋股票
85% of Steve Madden Shoes,
法律上来说当然是不行
which legally speaking was a big no-no,
但如果员工们够努力的话 我们可会变成巨富
but we'd get filthy fucking rich if our troops got behind it.
我们就是要负责保证他们努力工作
Our job was to get them worked up.
- 但也不用太努力 - 嘘
- But not too worked up. - Shh.
大家好 如果
Hello. If,uh...
你们有人还不认识我的话
For those of you who don't know me,uh...
我叫史蒂夫·马登
My name's Steve Madden.
我们都认识你
Yeah,we know who you are.
鞋盒上写着你的名字呢
Your name is on the box.
鞋子 给他们看看鞋子
Get the shoes. Show them the shoes.
- 这鞋挺酷的吧 - 当然
- Show them the shoes. - Okay. Yeah.
这鞋是挺酷的
Anyway,you know,this shoe is pretty cool.
这鞋叫"玛丽·露" 是这鞋让我一举成名的
This is the Mary Lou,which is really the shoe that put me on the map.
没有它 我今天就不会在这
Without it,I wouldn't be here.
那是胖女人穿的吧
It's a fat girls' shoe!
不管你们信不信 不管你们信不信吧
Believe it or not... Believe it or not though,
"玛丽·露"和
the Mary Lou is actually the same
"玛丽·珍"是一样的 只不过它是黑色皮质的
as the Mary Jane,but it's black leather.
哇哦
Whoa,whoa,whoa!
来呀 你在哪儿？
Fight back! Come on! Where you at? Where you at?
好了
All right!
掌声献给史蒂夫·马登和他的"玛丽·露"皮鞋
Let's give it up for Steve Madden and his awesome Mary Lou!
举起来 举起来 骄傲地举起来
Hold that up. Hold that up. Hold that up proud!
接受掌声
Give him a round of applause!
嗑的药都排出去了吧？
You guys got that out of your systems,huh?
今天下午过得怎么样？
You having a good afternoon or what?
我想利用一点时间来告诉你们
I wanna take a moment and tell you why Steve here is so
为什么史蒂夫·马登这么强
absolutely off the fucking wall.
因为这家伙是个
It's because this man
创意方面的天才
is a creative genius.
史蒂夫的这种能力
This ability,this gift
天赋
that Steve has,
不仅仅是
it goes beyond just
察觉到最新的鞋子设计走向
spotting the hottest shoe trends.
他强大在 自己创造潮流
Steve's power is that he creates trends.
明白了吗？
You understand?
史蒂夫这样的艺术家 十年才能出一个
Artists like Steve come along once every decade.
像乔治·阿玛尼 詹尼·范思哲 可可·香奈儿
I'm talking Giorgio Armani,Gianni Versace,Coco Chanel,
伊夫·圣·罗兰
Yves Saint Laurent.
史蒂夫 过来一下
Steve,come over here for a second.
我觉得你们都不清楚
I don't think you all realize
史蒂夫·马登
that Steve Madden
现在是当下最红的女鞋产业第一人
is the hottest person in the women's shoe industry,
北美洲每家百货商场
with orders going through the roof
给他鞋子的订单都堆到天花板
at every department store in North America right now.
而他本人现在就在我们办公室里
We have him here in our office!
我们该感谢幸运星 让他过来
We should thank our fucking lucky stars this man is here!
我们现在该五体投地 赶紧跪下吧
We should be on our hands and knees right now,
准备好给他吹箫
getting ready to suck this guy off!
像这样的
Like this! Okay?
我想帮你吹啊 史蒂夫
I wanna suck you off,Steve!
所有人都该帮你吹
Everyone's gonna suck you off!
他就是我们进入
This is our Golden ticket
巧克力工厂的金色门票
to the fucking chocolate factory right here!
我十分想见到
And I wanna meet
威利·王卡 好吗？
Willy fucking Wonka,okay?
我要跟王卡一起跳 像这样的
I wanna be with the fucking Oompa Loompas like this!
好了 下台去吧 走吧你
All right,get off this fucking stage! Get out of here.
好了 我需要你们集中一下注意力
All right,I want you all to focus for a second.
看见这些黑色的小盒子吗？
See those little black boxes?
这些盒子 叫电话
They're called telephones.
告诉你们一个关于电话的小秘密吧
I'm gonna let you in on a little secret about these telephones.
它们不会自己拨号出去
They're not gonna dial themselves. Okay?
没有你们 它们只是一堆好看的废塑料
Without you,they're just worthless hunks of plastic.
就像上了膛的M16枪 却没有训练有素的军人来扣扳机
Like a loaded M16 without a trained Marine to pull the trigger.
对于电话来说
And in the case of the telephone,
这就靠你们每一个人了
it's up to each and every one of you,
我训练有素的斯特拉顿人
my highly-trained Strattonites.
我的杀手们
My killers!
我的杀手们 从不接受"不"作为回答
My killers,who will not take no for an answer!
我的战士们
My fucking warriors,
是绝不会主动挂电话的
who will not hang up the phone
客户要么买
until their client either buys
要么就死
or fucking dies!
告诉你们吧
Let me tell you something.
贫穷绝无高尚可言
There is no nobility in poverty.
我既享有万贯家财 又体验过贫困潦倒
I have been a rich man and I have been a poor man.
而每次 我都选择去做有钱人
And I choose rich every fucking time.
因为 作为一个有钱人
Because at least as a rich man,
至少每次遇见什么问题
when I have to face my problems,
都可以乘着辆加长豪华车
I show up in the back of a limo,
穿两千块一套的西装
wearing a $2,000 suit
戴着四万块的金表去解决问题
and a $40,000 gold fucking watch!
一决高下
Duke it out! Hit him!
他妈的放开我
Get the fuck off me!
如果现在这里有人觉得我太肤浅粗俗
And if anyone here thinks I'm superficial
太过物质至上
or materialistic,
那就赶紧滚 去麦当劳找份工作吧
go get a job at fucking McDonald's,
因为那他妈的才是你的家
cause that's where you fucking belong!
但 在你们带着成功 离开这间办公室之前
But before you depart this room full of winners,
我希望你们好好看看
I want you to take a good look
自己身边的人
at the person next to you. Go on.
因为就在不久的将来
Because sometime in the not-so-distant future,
你开着破旧的福特
you're gonna be pulling up to a red light
平托停在红灯的路口
in your beat-up old fucking Pinto,
那个人会停在你隔壁车道
and that person's gonna be pulling up right alongside you
开着崭新的保时捷
in their brand new Porsche
旁边坐着年轻漂亮的老婆
with their beautiful wife by their side,
胸前大波荡漾
who's got big voluptuous tits.
而你身边坐着的呢？
And who're you gonna be sitting next to?
穿着无袖衫脏得跟
Some disgusting wildebeest
三天没刮脸似的老女人
with three days of razor-stubble,
恶心的老母牛
in a sleeveless muumuu,
一身肥肉挤在你身边
crammed in next to you in a carload full of groceries
车里还塞满了超市的打折食物
from the fucking Price Club!
那就是你旁边坐着的人
That's who you're gonna be sitting next to!
所以 听我说 好好听着
So you listen to me and you listen well.
你们的信用卡账单是不是得还了？
Are you behind on your credit card bills?
很好 拿起电话 开始拨号吧
Good! Pick up the phone and start dialing!
你们的房东是不是要踢你出去？
Is your landlord ready to evict you? Good!
很好 拿起电话 给我拨号
Pick up the phone and start dialing!
你的女朋友是不是觉得你是个废物？
Does your girlfriend think you're a fucking worthless loser?
很好 拿起电话 拨号
Good! Pick up the phone and start dialing!
我希望你们挣了大笔的钱
I want you to deal with your problems
用钱去解决问题
by becoming rich!
你们今天需要做的
All you have to do today
只是拿起电话
is pick up that phone
说那些我教过你们的话
and speak the words that I have taught you.
然后我会把你变得
And I will make you richer
比全美最有权势的总裁们还要有钱
than the most powerful CEO in the United States of fucking America!
好
Yeah!
Fuck,yeah!
我需要你们去
I want you to go out there
把这支
and I want you to ram
史蒂夫·马登的股票塞到客户喉咙里
Steve Madden stock down your clients' throats
塞到他们噎住为止
until they fucking choke on it!
直到他们噎住然后买个十万股
Till they choke on it and they buy
这就是我想看到的
100,000 shares! That's what I want.
我想要做的就是这个
Yeah! Fuck,yeah.
要勇猛
You be ferocious!
- 你要凶狠 - 是
- You be relentless! - Yeah!
要成为电话那头的恐怖分子
You be telephone fucking terrorists!
那现在我们正式开始吧
Now let's knock this motherfucker out of the park!
下午一点我们正式开始出售股票 价钱是4.5元
At 1:00 P.M.,we opened the stock for sale at $4.50 a share.
到了1点3分 已经涨到了18块
By 1:03,it was over $18.
甚至那些超大型华尔街公司都来买了
Even the big Wall Street firms were buying.
公开募股的两百万股中
Of the two million shares offered for sale,
有一百万股是我的 藏在我那几位朋友的"老鼠洞"里
a million belonged to me,held in phony accounts by my ratholes.
现在股价已经接近二十
Now once the price hit the high teens...
你知道这个？谁他妈管这个啊？
You know what? Who gives a shit?
一如既往的 重点是
As always,the point is this.
3小时卖出了2200万美元
$22 million in three fucking hours!
你相信吗
Can you believe this shit?
- 我他妈喜欢这个 宝贝 - 太疯狂了
- I fucking love this,baby! - It's amazing!
乔丹
Jordan!
"未来影像"的巴里·克雷曼
Barry Kleinman's on the phone
- 在电话那头 - 谁？
- from Future Video. - Who?
我不知道 是他拍的你婚礼录像
I don't know. He shot at your wedding.
他说是要紧事
He says it's urgent.
要紧事？巴里·克雷曼算老几啊
Urgent? Who the fuck is Barry Kleinman?
噢 天哪 你要嫁给我？
Oh,my God,you wanna marry me?
你爱上我了？
You're in love with me?
回家操你表妹去吧
Yeah. Go fuck your cousin!
巴里 什么事？
Hey,Barry,what's up?
我接到一张传票
Listen,I got this subpoena.
传票？你在说什么啊？
Subpoena? What the fuck are you talking about?
FBI需要一份你
Yeah,the FBI,they want a copy
婚礼录像的拷贝
of your wedding video.
FBI？
The fucking FBI?
- 你他妈是开玩笑么？- 听我说
- You fucking kidding me? - Listen to me.
那人叫丹纳
His name is Denham.
是FBI纽约办公室的探员
He's an agent with the New York office.
他什么毛病啊？
What's his problem?
他是童子军出身 他觉得你是戈登·盖柯
He's a Boy Scout. He thinks you're fucking Gordon Gekko.
他要看我婚礼录像带干嘛？
What does he want with my wedding video?
这是侵犯我个人隐私啊
It's like an invasion of my privacy.
你知道吧
You know what I'm saying? It's like...
绝对是侵犯隐私
It's intrusive,you know.
你那小圈子里的人是谁 他早就知道了
He's got pictures of your whole inner fucking circle.
照片 姓名
Pictures,names of the people.
你知道他想干什么的？
You know what he's trying to do?
他已经上手做了 看看你自己
Exactly what he's doing. Look at yourself.
他这是要震慑你
He's trying to rattle you,
还吓唬你老妈
he's trying to rattle your old lady,
然后她就会成了证人了
so she nags you until you become a fucking witness.
他想要我自己招了啊？
He wants me to rat on myself?
想要我提供自己的信息？
He wants me to give information about my...
好消息是
Listen. The good fucking news is,
你也知道 那帮政府的人我都认识
you know I know everybody downtown,
我给律政司 缉毒局打了电话
I call up the Justice Department,the DEA,
压根没人知道你的存在 所以安心吧
nobody even knows you fucking exist,so calm down!
他们不知道我？
They don't know I exist?
- 完全不知 - 那就好
- No. - That's good.
但是你
But you...
你知道他是谁对吧？
You know who he is,right?
- 是啊 - 如果我想要知道进一步的消息
- Yeah. - So,if I just wanted to get
了解一下他现在掌握了什么
some more information,just find out what he knows,
你可以偷偷进去他家里 对吧？
you could go to his house,right?
窃听一下他的电话
Tap his phones a little bit,bug him.
溜进去 搞点消息出来
You could get some information...
他们这帮人你是不能惹的
You don't fuck with these guys like that.
他是探员啊你惹他？
You don't fuck with them like that.
你是疯了吗？
What are you,nuts or something?
你不就是干这个的吗 不然我雇你干嘛来的
This is what you fucking do. What do I pay you for?
我做私家侦探也是有执照的 这是我的饭碗
I have a fucking P.I. license,you know? I make a living at this.
我已经不是警察了
I'm not a cop anymore.
他们会吊销我的执照啊 好吗？
They'll take my fucking license away from me,all right?
好吧
Okay.
好吧 如果这样不行
Okay,if I can't do that,can I just...
那我能不能给他打个电话？
Can I give the guy a call?
- 你干嘛 - 乔丹
- Why? Is that... - Jordan. Jordan.
帮帮忙啊
Do me a favor?
唯一能给这家伙打电话的只有你的律师
The only one who calls this guy is your fucking lawyer.
我不能打给他
I can't call him,right?
- 这是违反规定的？- 我告诉你了
- It's against the rules? - I told you,
不管你跟他说什么
whatever the fuck you say to him,
他都会用来当做证据的 你还不懂？
he's gonna use against you. Don't you understand?
他是聪明人 你是蠢货
He's smart,you're dumb.
胡说八道
Fucking bullshit.
连个电话都不让打
Are we fucking talking tonight,
你今晚是想好好谈的吗？
or are you gonna get schwacked?
上一次你吃这些药的时候
The last time you took these fucking pills,
你整个人都疯了好吗 快别吃了
you put your head in the fucking macaroni. I had to pick it up.
好吧
All right.
我不会打给他的
Okay,I won't call him.
嘿 二位 上船来吧
Hey,fellas! Come on board.
登船在那边就是
The plank's right around there.
欢迎啊
Welcome!
喔 今个天气真不错
Whoo! What a nice day.
嘿
Hey.
欢迎登船
Welcome aboard.
我是乔丹 欢迎你们来娜奥米号
Jordan. Welcome aboard the Naomi.
幸会二位
Pleasure to meet you.
我是探员丹纳 这位是探员休斯
Agent Denham. This is Agent Hughes.
你们好啊
Hi,how are you?
我来给你们介绍 这两位是妮可和海蒂 过来吧 别害羞
Let me introduce you. This is Nicole,Heidi. Come on. Don't be shy.
你们这是害羞什么呢？别害怕
What are you guys all shy for? Don't be scared.
她们是我们斯特拉顿公司的朋友
These are friends of Stratton.
- 幸会 - 你们好
- It's a pleasure. - Hello.
额
Um...
你之前跟我们说的是 想要私下谈谈
Your message said that you wanted to speak privately.
没错 我的确是想私下谈的
Right. I do want to speak privately.
让我们单独聊一会儿 女士们
Give us a minute,huh,ladies?
有什么需要告诉我
Let me know if I can get you anything.
我很乐意服务
We'd be happy to help.
你们饿了吗？
You guys hungry?
如果想吃东西
Want something to eat?
这里有意面 虾 龙虾
Got some pasta,shrimp,lobster.
我这还有威士忌 想喝什么都有
I got whiskey. Any kind of booze you want.
其实吧 局里不让
You know what? The Bureau doesn't allow us
我们在工作时饮酒
to drink while we're at sea.
搞忘了 当然
Duh! Of course.
以前乘过这种游艇吗？
Ever been on one of these before?
船吗？
A boat?
我六岁的时候学着一起出海
I learned how to sail when I was six.
不会吧 真的吗
No shit. Is that right? Really?
但像这样一艘船啊
On one like this,though?
我把船的前部加长了 好停直升机
I had the whole front extended in order to fit the chopper up there.
看见没
See that?
总之呢 这个是给你的
Anyway,this is for you.
这是出席我婚礼的全部人员名单
It's a complete list of every person that was at my wedding.
我明白你们想要完整的婚礼录像
I understand you wanted the whole wedding video.
我觉得这样能提高你们的工作效率 对吧
Figured this would help expedite the whole process,right?
- 的确 - 听着
- There you go. - Look,
我想说的是
my point is that
我知道你在调查斯特拉顿
I know you're investigating Stratton.
但就我看来 我完全不明白为什么
But for the life of me,I can't figure out why.
我知道我们公司不那么传统 不同于他人
I know we're a little unorthodox,we're a little
做事情有点高调
loud in the way we do things. But you gotta understand,
不过你们要理解
we're the new guys on the block,you know,
我们属于新人 这是在打响名声
we're trying to make a name for ourselves.
但你们必须知道的是 我们不做
But I want you to understand,we don't
任何违法的事
do anything illegal.
无论如何都不会
Whatsoever.
你可以去找证监会
I mean,you could talk to the SEC.
他们过去半年内来我们公司有15次了吧
They were at my office 15 times over the last six months.
我没有什么好隐瞒的
I mean,I got... I got nothing to hide.
你也知道证监会属于民间监管组织
Well,you know the SEC is a civil regulatory agency.
我们查的是刑事犯罪
We pursue criminal activities.
没错 你们抓的是真正的罪犯啊
Exactly! You go after real criminals,which
我就更想知道了 你们在调查我什么？
makes me wonder what the hell you're investigating me for?
说真的
I mean,honestly...
你觉得我都干什么了？我不懂啊
What is it that you think that we did or do? I don't get it.
这个
Well,I...
乔丹 我不能透露正在进行的案子的信息
Look,Jordan,I can't discuss an ongoing investigation.
这我明白 我懂
No,I get that. No,I understand.
既然说到这了
With that said...
这案子是别人丢到我桌上的
This case got dumped on my desk...
- 谁干的 - 你知道的 我的上级
- Did it? - You know,by a higher-up
想要通过调查
who needs to make a show
新兴的公司来展示工作成果
of looking into the new company on the block,
- 我有压力 诸如此类的 - 太招摇的人
- with all the press and everything. - New loud guys.
最后就轮到我这傻子
And then I end up being the schmuck
来做具体的调查了 就是这样
who does the looking. Exactly.
只是这件事还是很烦人啊
It's just,you know... It bothers me.
我们是新人 我们是
We're the new guy. We're the one
属于敲门想进去华尔街的
that's banging on Wall Street's door. I mean,you should...
你应该去查更大的公司
You should see what's going on at the bigger firms.
所以信息我都知道
I mean,I know all the information.
真的 高盛 雷曼兄弟 美林
It's true! Goldman,Lehman Brothers,Merrill...
债务抵押证券？
Collateralized debt obligations?
网络公司股票 什么破烂？
This Internet stock bullshit?
简直是搞笑啊
I mean,it's a fucking travesty.
我可以一步步带你了解
I could take you step-by-step
具体都发生了些什么
through what exactly is occurring.
只要你开口问
All you have to do is ask.
我有的是时间
I'm available.
- 这话正是我想听到的 - 嗯
- That's exactly what I wanted to hear. - Mmm-hmm.
这样一起坐下谈谈多好啊
I don't see why a little sitdown like this
对双方都大有好处
can't be profitable for the both of us.
就该如此不是吗？就该对双方都有好处
It should. Right? It should profit the both of us.
- 没错 - 你瞧
- It should. - Look.
我把私人的电话号码给你
I'm gonna give you my personal line.
一礼拜五天你随便打
Five days a week,you just call me,feel free.
- 我会的 - 那好
- I'll do that. - Great.
你们确定不要喝点什么吗？
Are you sure you guys don't want something to drink?
也不饿吗？什么都不要？
You're not hungry? Nothing?
- 不用了 - 是吗？
- Nothing? No? - Oh,no.
我想问问啊
Let me ask you,
如果问题问得太过分太私人了
and if you don't wanna get too personal,
- 你可以随时让我闭嘴 - 噢
- just tell me to shut up at any time. - Oh.
你以前是不是考过股票经纪人执照？
Did you try to get your broker's license at one time?
我的消息准确吗？当时是不是打算在华尔街试试？
Did I hear that right? Were you trying to take a stab at Wall Street?
- 不？- 你都问了谁？
- No? - Who you been talking to?
谁告诉你的
Who the fuck you been talking to?
你这不是在调查我嘛
Well,you're investigating me.
我也有自己的消息源啊
I hear things.
你明白吧
You know what I mean?
你有没有想过 当时考上会怎样
You ever think about what would've happened
如果 你继续从事这一行
if you would have stayed the course?
你知道吗 我每天回家搭地铁
You know what? When I'm riding home on the subway
热得蛋都在流汗
and my balls are fucking sweating,
连续三天穿同一套西装
I'm wearing the same suit three days in a row...
我当然是想过
Yeah,you bet I do.
以前的确想过 谁不会呢
I've thought about it before. Who wouldn't,right?
没错 谁不想啊
Right,who fucking wouldn't?
我还有
What do you get...
另外一个私人问题
Another personal question,no need to answer...
你不必回答的 乔丹
No,that's all right,Jordan.
你工资如何？一年差不多五六万吧？
What do you pull in? 50,60K? Something like that?
- 一年？在球场？- 噢
- A year? In the ballpark? - Oh.
好吧 我
Well,I...
这么说吧
Let's put it this way.
进局里工作
You get a free handgun
会给你免费的手枪
when you sign up for the Bureau.
没错 但这太让我火大了 你懂的 想想看吧
No,but it fucking pisses me off. You know what I mean?
一手建立起这个国家的人
You think about the people that built this country,
勤劳实干的人们 像你这样的
hardworking people like you.
比如消防员啊 教师啊 FBI探员啊
Firefighters,teachers,FBI agents.
累死累活的 工资却这么低
End of the day,you guys get fucking skinned alive financially.
太他妈的令人生气了
It fucking makes me angry.
所以华尔街和这市场的意义就在于
Now the one thing about Wall Street and this market is,
对我来说
for me,I feel
能回馈社会是很好的
it's good to give back. You know,there's...
在很多情况下 我都可以回馈
There are situations where I can
对人们的生活进行改善
make those situations better for people. You know?
你明白吧
You know what I mean.
机遇
Opportunity
就是一切
is everything.
没错
Exactly.
比如 我认识这样一个小孩
Take for example,I got this one kid,right?
大学念的专业是环境科学之类的吧
Went to school for environmental science,something like that.
学生贷款让他生活很艰难
He was bogged down by student loans.
结果他母亲又需要做三次心脏搭桥手术
Turns out,his mother needed triple bypass surgery.
- 老天 - 遭遇太不幸了
- Jesus. - Right. Horrible situation.
当然
Sure.
但是我们就让他在正确的时候
But we got him into the market
进入到这个市场选择了正确的股票
at the right time and chose the right stock.
给了他正确的指导
We gave him the right guidance.
嘭 一夜之间 整个人生都改变了
Boom! Overnight,changed his entire life.
他可以送妈妈
Got to put his mother into
去全纽约最好的医院治疗
the best hospital in New York City.
虽然最后还是没能成功
It didn't work out for her,
很不幸她去世了
granted,she passed away,unfortunately.
但是 我们给了他这个机会
But we gave him that opportunity.
你懂我的意思吧？
You know what I'm saying?
只要选择正确的合作团队
It's just about setting up the right team,
一夜之间就可以改变命运
and then overnight your life can change.
那这样的
What does... What does an intern...
这样的实习生 可以挣多少钱
What does an intern make in a deal like that?
这种情况的话
Well,in that situation,
就单单这笔交易
in that particular trade,and it was one trade,
五十万美元往上
north of half a million dollars.
并且不论是谁我都愿意这样做
And I'd do that for anybody,you know,
任何需要正确指导的人
anybody that needs the proper guidance.
能再说一遍吗？
Can you say that again,
像你刚才那样 再说一遍
just the way you said it?
跟刚才一样说
Just the same way.
噢
Oh.
我不明白你的意思
I don't know what you're talking about.
拜托 你很清楚我在说什么
Oh,come on! You know what I'm talking about.
再说一遍吧 我觉得 乔当刚才是在
I think what Jordan just did is he...
- 如果我理解得没错的话 - 不
- If I'm not mistaken... - No.
你刚才在试图贿赂联邦探员啊
You just tried to bribe a federal officer.
不 确切地说 我没有贿赂任何人
No,technically I didn't bribe anybody.
不 不 这不是我听到的 乔丹
No,no,that's not the conversation I heard,Jordan.
不 不 根据美国的刑法
No,no,according to the U.S. criminal code,
需要用切实的金钱
there needs to be an exact dollar figure
- 来收买对方 - 噢
- for the exchange of services. - Oh!
这样子法律是不会承认的
That would not hold up in a court of law.
他不是听到的
Nah,it's not howl heard it.
不 不 事实就是这样 但是 这么告诉你吧
No,no,no,that's the truth. But I want to tell you this.
说
Yeah.
告诉我你要
The same gentleman that told me
考执照的那个人
that you tried to get your broker's license
还告诉我 你是个正直的人
also told me that you are a straight arrow.
他竟然还去查我的背景了
He ran a security check on me.
好吧
Well...
我人在江湖 小人到处都是
Yeah,when you sail on a boat fit for a Bond villain,
有时候身不由己啊 对吧？
sometimes you need to play the part. Right?
我看是时候请你们滚了
I think it's time you both get the fuck off my boat.
你们看呢？
What do you say? Hmm?
你知道吗 乔丹 这么告诉你吧
You know,Jordan,I'll tell you something.
大多数我教训过的华尔街混蛋们
Most of the Wall Street jackasses that I bust,
他们天生就是如此
they're to the manor born.
- 是吗？- 是
- Is that right? - Yeah.
他们的老爸们就已经是混蛋
Their fathers are douchebags,
老爸的老爸也一样
just like their fathers before them.
但是你
But you...
你 乔丹 你完全靠自己爬上来的
You,Jordan,you got this way all on your own.
是吗？
Did I?
- 不错啊 你这小人 - 小人？
- Good for you,little man. - Little man?
真不错
Good for you.
我是小人啊？
Me,the little man?
这么说吧
And let me tell you something.
我再告诉你一件事
Let me tell you something else.
说真的 我可没胡说
Honestly,I'm not bullshitting here,
这是我搭过的最好的船
this is one of the nicest boats
- 这个必须承认 - 那是肯定
- that I've ever been on,I gotta tell you. - I bet it is.
而且你知道我在想什么吗
And you know what I was just thinking,too?
等案子查完 我得成大英雄啊
The fucking hero that I'm gonna be back at the office
等局里把你的船收走
when the Bureau seizes this fucking boat.
我终于是把乔丹给操翻了啊
Because,I mean,fuckety-fuck-fuck,Jordan,
看看这个东西
look at this thing!
太美了
It's beautiful!
船上还有美女啊 简直太棒了
And you got the beautiful girls there. It's wonderful.
好了 滚出我的船
All right,get the fuck off my boat.
我敢肯定我们很快
I'm sure we'll be seeing each other
- 会再见面的 - 那是
- real soon. - I'm sure.
祝回家搭地铁好运啊
Good luck on that subway ride home
滚回你们那丑八怪老婆身边吧
to your miserable,ugly fucking wives.
我一会儿让海蒂把鱼子酱舔我蛋蛋上
I'm gonna have Heidi lick some caviar off my balls in the meantime.
嘿你们俩回家路上要带点龙虾吗？
Hey,you guys want to take some lobsters for your ride home?
可悲的傻逼们 我知道你们买不起
Fucking miserable pricks,I know you can't afford them!
操你妈的
Fucking cheap fucks.
可悲的傻逼
Fucking miserable pricks.
嘿两位 看我口袋里找到什么
Hey,fellas! Look what I found in my pocket! Look!
你们俩一年的工资
A year's salary right here.
知道我叫这什么吗？欢乐打折券
You know what I call them? Fun coupons!
看
See that!
欢乐打折券
They're fun coupons!
瑞士？去瑞士干嘛
Switzerland? What the fuck is in Switzerland?
当然是因为瑞士有银行啊
Swiss fucking banks,that's what.
现在得擦干净屁股 我得把钱藏起来
It was ass-covering time. I had to hide my money.
于是有请光头
Enter Rugrat.
他在法学院的时候认识了个瑞士银行家
He knew this Swiss banker from law school.
但那人在日内瓦
But he was in Geneva.
而我是没可能清醒地坐这么久的飞机
And there was no way I was gonna make that flight sober.
所以我知道如果我把握好量
So I knew if I took my drugs right,
可以整个飞行都在睡觉
I could sleep through the entire flight.
但这个量 就一定要准确
But I had to take them just right.
下午4点我吃了几片安眠酮
At 4:00 P.M.,I popped a few more ludes,
开完销售会议之后
which started kicking in by the time.
药劲就上来了
I finished my sales meeting.
进入了兴奋阶段
My tingle phase.
晚饭时候又吃了几颗
By dinner,I popped a few more
就着几杯鸡尾酒 还有一两片安定
on top of some cocktails and a Valium or two.
这叫说话含糊阶段
My slur phase.
到了八点半 我又再吃了几片
By 8:30,I took a few more ludes
连动作都做不了了
and pretty much lost all my motor skills.
这叫口水横流阶段
This was the drool phase.
等到了十点 我都不知道自己是谁了
And by 10:00,I didn't know who or what the fuck I was.
记忆缺失阶段
The amnesia phase.
午夜之前我们登机了
We boarded the plane just before midnight.
哇 看看你啊
Wow! Look at you!
- 多漂亮啊 - 打扰了 先生
- You're beautiful. - Excuse me,Sir.
是安眠药 他没事
His sleeping pills just kicked in. He's all right.
能看你下你的登机牌吗 先生
May I see your boarding passes,Sir?
登机牌我们有
We have the boarding passes.
天哪 我要上她
Jesus Christ,I wanna fuck her.
嘿 放松点
Hey! Fucking relax.
天啊 你他妈摸我下面干嘛
Oh,my God! You got your hand on my fucking cock!
我不知道 别说了
I don't. Cut it out.
他又摸我鸡鸡了
He's got his hand on my dick again.
我只是想给你把它弄掉
I'm just trying to buckle you up.
你又摸他干嘛
You got your hand on his dick?
公共场合还是别这样了以后
You gotta stop doing that in public places.
天啊 假发脱掉
Oh,my God. Take it off!
脱掉啊
Take it off!
我听说假发下面有藏宝图
I heard there's a treasure map under here.
- 住手 我知道了 - 打扰了 先生
- Stop! I know,miss. - Excuse me,Sir.
请坐下
Please sit down.
- 看着他 - 请回自己的位置上
- Watch it. - Go back to your seat,please.
- 你生什么气 - 请回自己的位置上
- What are you upset about? - Please go back to your seat.
不然我只能通知机长了
I will have to call the captain.
先生 请坐下
Please,Sir,please,Sir. Sit down.
- 请坐下 - 哦
- Please sit down! - Ow!
- 我走了 - 好吧 抱歉
- I'm going! Stop. - Okay,sorry.
我们很抱歉 我要睡觉了
We apologize. We're gonna go to sleep.
我有个问题要问
Question. I wanna ask you a question.
请系上安全带
Fasten your seat belt,Sir.
不系安全带我们不能起飞
We cannot take off if you haven't fastened
- 你的安全带 - 我很好色
- your seat belt. - I'm really horny,too.
坐下 系好
Sit down. Fasten it.
- 不然我帮你系 - 我帮你系
- Right. Okay,I'll sit down... - I will do it for you.
- 什么？- 我可以帮你系
- What? - I'll do it for you.
你得说英语
You gotta speak English.
你说的语言我们听不懂
We don't understand this language you're speaking.
我来帮你系上
I will help him with his seat belt.
- 我得把他放在右边 - 坐好 坐好
- You gotta put it on right. - Sit back. Sit back,Sir.
- 好了 坐好了- 好了
- There you go. - All right. I'll just Lean back...
比特 费尔希
Bitte,Hilfe!
天啊
Jesus Christ!
他妈的
Fuck!
丹尼
Donnie...
丹尼 这不好玩 快给我松绑
Donnie,this isn't funny. You gotta untie me,buddy.
我可不能给你松绑
I can't untie you.
是机长绑的
The captain tied you up.
他差点都拿电击枪电你了
He almost fucking tasered you.
为什么？
Why?
啊
Ah!
你朝别人嚷嚷
You were screaming at people.
不会吧
Oh,fuck off.
你躺在地上滚来滚去
You were on the floor rolling around and shit.
哦 老天爷
Oh,Jesus.
你还骂机长是黑鬼
You called the captain the N-word.
我喊机长是黑鬼？
I called the captain the N-word?
- 是啊 他可生气了 - 真的吗？
- Yeah,he was very upset. - Really?
- 还好我们坐的头等舱啊 - 天啊
- Luckily we're in first class. - Jesus.
老天爷 我觉得你这嗑药是嗑出毛病了
Jesus Christ,I think you have a fucking drug problem.
安眠酮在哪？
Where are the ludes?
我的安眠酮呢？
屁眼里塞着呢 不用担心
They're up my ass. Don't worry about it.
- 我拿着呢 - 好吧
- I got it. - Okay.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
天啊 等到了瑞士
Jesus Christ,what are we gonna do
可怎么办
when we get to Switzerland,buddy?
情况不太好啊
This is bad.
这带子勒住了我胸口 我不能呼吸了
Fucking things are against my chest. I can't breathe.
快做点什么让我冷静下来
Come on,do something to calm me down. Please.
好吧 闭嘴啊 快闭嘴
Okay,shut the fuck up. Shut the fuck up.
好啊 嘘 嘘
Okay. Shh! Shh!
没事了 睡吧
That's good.
- 去睡觉 - 用力点摸
- Go to sleep. - Rub it harder,buddy.
你没事
You're all right.
我们都爱你 给我闭嘴
We all love you. Shut the fuck up!
贝尔福特先生
Mr. Belfort,
你可以走了
you're free to go.
真的？
Really?
哇哦
Whoo!
- 嘿丹尼 - 在
- Hey,Donnie. - Yeah?
等我们到了那 可别再这样了好么
When we get out there,try not to act like yourself.
让日内瓦成为"混账丹尼禁区"如何
Okay? Let's make Geneva an asshole-free Donnie zone,all right?
你这么针对我干嘛？
What are you fucking coming at me for?
嘿 听着 你现在能坐在这豪车里
Hey,listen. The only reason you're sitting in this limo
而不是蹲在瑞士的大牢 那都是因为我的朋友 好吗
and not in a Swiss jail is because of my friend. Okay?
希尔费
Hilfe!
我们到了
We're here. We're here. Everyone calm down.
乔丹·贝尔福特
Jordan Belfort!
终于见面了
At last.
尼古拉斯老向我提起你
Nicholas has told me so much about you.
乔丹 这位是雅克·苏瑞尔
Jordan,Jean Jacques Saurel.
- 很高兴认识你 - 幸会
- Pleasure to make your acquaintance. - Nice to meet you.
真是搞笑
It's a joke.
明白我们在说什么吧
You'll understand when you're in the fucking seat.
拿沙发当桌子使
You need a bigger couch. For guests.
不好意思 我不懂啊
Yeah. Yeah,yeah. I don't understand. I'm sorry.
我比较好奇你们这里的银行保密法
I'm curious about your bank secrecy laws here.
额 等等 抱歉 乔丹
Uh... Wait. Yes. Excusez-moi,Jordan.
瑞士的传统是 需要十分钟的
Swiss custom requires 10 minutes of...
等等
Blah,blah,blah.
- 闲聊 - 闲聊 谢谢
- Chit chat. - Yeah,chit chat,thank you.
之后再谈生意
Before business can be discussed.
耶
Yeah.
当然了
Of course.
我们还是开门见山吧 你想知道些什么？
Let's get down to it. What would you like to know?
在什么情况下
Under what circumstances would you be obligated
才会有义务必须跟FBI合作
to cooperate with an FBI
或者美国司法部的调查？
or a U.S. Justice Department investigation,for example?
看情况
Ca depend.
看情况？
Ca depend?
是
Oui.
看具体什么？
Ca depend on what,exactly?
要看美国人会不会在接下来
Whether America plans to invade Switzerland
几个月入侵瑞士
in the coming months.
看看坦克是不是已经开到下面克洛伊大道了
Shall I check if tanks are rolling down the Rue de la Croy?
- 是克洛瓦 - 克洛瓦
- Yes. Rue de la Croix. - Croix. Croix.
不是克洛伊 也不是什么克洛伊大道 就叫克洛瓦
Not Croy. Not Rue de la Croy. It's Croix.
我们以前在法学院就是这样 香槟不念香槟
See,this is what he used to do back in law school. Check me.
- "香槟" - 没错
- Champagne. Champagne. - Yeah.
是啊 薯条还是"法式薯条"
Yeah,yeah. French fries,pommes frites.
- 这种的之类的吧 - 真是搞笑
- And that kind of stuff. - That's funny.
我想问的是 你这瑞士混蛋
What I'm asking,you Swiss dick,
会不会把我的事搞砸了
is are you going to fuck me over?
我当然明白你的意思 美国草包
I understand perfectly,you American shit.
日内瓦皇家银行如果必须
The only way the Banque Réal de Genéve
和外国的法律单位合作
would cooperate with a foreign legal body
只能是他们查的案子在瑞士
is if the crime being pursued
也触犯了法律
is also a crime in Switzerland.
但瑞士很少有适用于你们的法律条文
But there are very few Swiss laws which apply to your practices.
所以从经济这方面考虑
From a financial standpoint,
你们现在身处
you are now
天堂啊
in heaven.
看吧 跟你说了他很赞吧
See,I told you he was fantastic,right?
如果美国司法部门给我们发来传票
If the U.S. Justice Department sent us a subpoena,it would become
那只会被用来当厕纸
papier toilette.
我们会用它来擦屁股
We would wipe our ass with it.
不过除非 他们调查的是
Unless,of course,it was an investigation
股票欺诈
into stock fraud,
如果我没弄错的话 这在瑞士也是犯罪
which is a crime here in Switzerland,if I'm correct.
那样就必须是"合作"了
Then there would have to be coopération on your part,
- 如果我没弄错 - 是
- if I'm not mistaken. - Yes.
那的确
Yes,we would. Mmm-hmm.
如果这账户是在名下的话
Assuming the account is under your name.
如果
If it were
是别人的名字
another name,
朋友啊
a friend's,camarade...
表亲啊？
Cousin?
- 亲戚 - 没错
- Relative? - Yeah.
额
Hmm.
刚才他是说腹语了吗
Was that yodeling I just heard
他是不是真说了我听到的那句？
or did you just say what I thought you said?
没错
Yes. Yes.
他是在告诉我 应该用"老鼠洞"
He's telling me to use a fucking rathole.
但美国的老鼠洞没法把
But a U.S. rathole would never get
那么多钱弄来瑞士
into Switzerland with all that money.
我需要一个欧洲护照开的老鼠洞
What I needed was a rathole with a European passport.
乔丹
Jordan.
嘿 我最亲爱的阿姨 你好吗
Hey. How's my favorite aunt,huh?
欢迎呀 交通是不是很糟糕
Welcome. Was the traffic terrible?
没一点也不
Oh,no,not at all.
乔丹 进来
Jordan,come in.
谢天谢地 艾玛阿姨并不难说服
Thank God Aunt Emma didn't need too much convincing.
结果呢 英国人和瑞士人也差不多
Turned out the British weren't too different from the Swiss.
有钱开口 没钱滚蛋
Money talks and bullshit takes the bus.
英国人是怎么说"老鼠洞"的啊
How do you say "rathole" in British?
如果你碰到任何麻烦
If you get into any trouble whatsoever,
我会马上过来 说是我骗了你
I'll come forth immediately. I'll say that I duped you.
这个我保证
That I promise.
是冒险让我们更年轻的 对吗 亲爱的
Risk is what keeps us young,isn't it,darling?
有时候我想
Sometimes I wonder
你是不是完全被金钱控制住了
if you let money get the best of you,my love.
当然
Among
还有其他的东西
other substances.
噢
Oh.
那么明显吗
It's that obvious,huh?
天这么冷 你还一直冒汗珠子
It's chilly,darling,and you're sweating bullets.
怎么说呢
What can I say? I'm...
我吸毒上瘾
I'm a drug addict.
真的
I really am.
可卡因 各种药片
Cocaine,pills.
不管什么我都吃
Whatever it is,I'll fucking do it.
就是这样
Now that's the truth.
还有
I mean...
我还有性瘾
I'm a sex addict,too.
有比性瘾更严重的事
Well,there are worse things to be addicted to than sex.
天哪 我为什么要告诉你这些
Jesus,why am I telling you all this? Why am I...
真对不起
I'm sorry.
因为我通情达理
Because I'm very easy to talk to.
- 的确 非常善解人意 - 嗯
- You are. You are easy to talk to. - Mmm.
我觉得
I suppose it's...
只是因为我的工作
Just my job,you know.
这些人都指望着我
All these people dependent on me.
几千万美元命悬一线的
Tens of millions of dollars at stake,you know.
有时候我会觉得
Sometimes I feel like I...
实在是一下吃太多 力不从心
I've bitten off more than I can chew,you know.
你是个胃口很大的人
You're a man with large appetites.
是
Yeah.
她这是在勾引我吗？
Is she fucking hitting on me?
是啊
Yeah.
我是
Yeah,I am.
我想 这都是我自找的 对吧？
I suppose I put that on myself though,right?
自己的决定
My decision.
这很艰难
It's just hard to...
有时候 真的很难学着控制焦虑
Hard to learn to control the anxiety sometimes,you know?
你知道的
You know,to...
放轻松 学着放手
Learn to relax and let go and...
释放压力
To release the tension.
她绝对是在勾引我
She is hitting on me.
我靠
Holy shit!
是啊 释放压力
Yeah,to release the tension.
我觉得我们 额
I suppose we,uh...
我们都需要学着去
We all just need to learn,uh...
学着顺其自然
Learn to do what comes naturally in life,you know?
他这是在勾引我？
Is he fucking hitting on me?
稳住 亲爱的
Stability,dear.
我们是亲戚
Family.
把我的外甥女照顾好
You take care of my niece,my love.
这边的就我来照顾
I'll take care of everything over here.
一言为定
Deal.
来呀 你去哪里
Come on! There you go.
哇哦
Whoo!
我们确确实实有整车的钞票
We had,literally,a fuckload of money.
艾玛阿姨绝不可能一个人带走
Aunt Emma could never carry all this by herself.
所以我想啊 谁还有欧洲的护照
So I thought to myself,who else has a European passport?
好了布拉德 你绑太紧了
Brad,you're making this too fucking tight!
布拉德作为一名成功的毒贩
Now Brad,as a successful drug dealer,
之前冬天在法国南部度假
spent his winters in the South of France,
在那里他认识了自己的老婆 香特尔
which is where he met his wife,Chantalle,
斯洛文尼亚裔的脱衣女郎
a stripper of Slovenian origin
还恰好出生在
born,in of all places,
瑞士
Switzerland.
操 不行啊
Well,this is fucked.
绝对不行
Oh. No shit.
而且就这样也得飞50次吧
Like,this will take her like 50 trips.
我知道
I know.
那样是自杀啊
Let me ask you something?
但 她还有家里人啊 对吧
What about her family? Right?
他们都有瑞士护照 对吧？
I mean,they all got Swiss passports,fight.
她有父母 哥哥
She's got parents,she's got a brother,right?
还有兄嫂 那就一共五个人了
The brother's got a wife. That's five fucking people.
六七次不就搞定了？
Six,seven trips,boom,right?
一群愚蠢的瑞士人
They're all fucking Swiss nitwits like her.
- 完全可行 - 我们能做到这一点
- They'll do it. - We could do that.
至少我还有家人啊 你这丑男蠢货
At least I have a family,you crooked-nose fuck!
嘿 别忘了还有我的钱
Hey,uh,don't forget about my money.
抱歉 你说啥？
I'm sorry,what's that?
嘿 我忘了告诉你了
Yeah,I forgot to tell you. He's got some...
- 他也有点钱要运 - 我的钱
- He's got some money. - My money.
下个礼拜有两百万过来
I got a couple of mil coming in like a week.
等到了我给你打电话 你过来拿
When it gets in,I'll give you a call,you come pick it up.
你给我打电话？
You give me a call?
等钱到了 我会给你打电话 你就过来取
When it gets here,I'll give you a call and you'll come pick it up.
尼玛 我们又不是给你打工的
Well,we don't fucking work for you,man!
亲爱的
Sweetheart,
你的咪咪上绑的那都是我的钞票
you have my money taped to your tits.
严格说来你就是给我打工的
Okay? Technically,you do work for me.
乔丹 我们得谈谈
Hey,Jordan,we're gonna need to talk.
如果我要做这事 那现在就得告诉你
If I fucking do this,I'm telling you right now,
我是不会给他做的
I ain't going to him,okay.
- 我又不是跑腿小弟 - 我知道了
- I'm not a fucking shvartze. - I got it.
才不会"过来拿" 好吗？
I don't do fucking pickups,all right?
- 听我说 如果这要这么干 - 我会打点好一切
- I got it. - Well,listen to me.
我必须说 你去告诉那混蛋东西
We meet someplace that I fucking say.
你去告诉那狗东西
And you tell that fucking piece of shit,
- 他必须好好说话 - 我会的
- he comes correct. - I will.
他要再这样我可要发火了
He comes in all fucking loopy and fucked up,I swear to God
我发誓打得他满地找牙
I'll mash that douchebag's teeth in.
我听到了 谁满地找牙？
You're gonna mash whose fucking teeth in?
谁满地找牙？
Whose fucking teeth are you gonna mash in?
那满桌的钱都是我挣的 不是你
I put the money on that fucking table! Not you!
没有我哪来这运钱的事
I'm the reason we have this whole fucking deal!
- 他有枪 你这蠢货 - 去他的枪吧
- He's got a gun,you fucking idiot! - Fuck his gun!
我已经说过了
I put that money in there!
你不就是个贩毒的吗
You know what? You're a fucking pill dealer.
你这样的我还认识其他五个
I got five more just like you,bro.
继续说啊 你这蠢货
Keep talking,you fucking piece of shit!
你知道么 你穿得都是什么狗屎啊
You know what else? You dress like shit!
操你妈的
So fuck you!
- 我操你妈的 - 噢 天啊
- Fucking motherfucker! - Oh! Jesus!
这样喜欢了吗 基佬？谁才是基佬啊？
How about that,faggot? Who's a faggot?
屁放够了没有
You okay? Hey,pal.
第二天 艾玛阿姨飞去了日内瓦
The next day,Aunt Emma flew to Geneva.
登机箱里装了两百万现金
Two million in cash in her carry-on,
但整个看来
which in the big picture
那只是海中一瓢而已
was a drop in the Swiss bucket.
因为接下来一个月
'Cause the following month,
一共六次来回
over the course of six round trips,
香特尔的家人和她的朋友们
Chantalle's family and friends
走私了两千万现金
smuggled in over 20 million in cash
嗝都没打一个
without even a hiccup.
- 我这还有一些 - 是吗？
- And I have some more. - Really?
- 给 - 哦谢谢
- Here. - Oh,thank you.
还有
And here.
欢迎啊
Welcome.
欢迎
- 好了 一共四个包 - 噢
- Yeah,like four bags of it. - Ooh!
你是斯洛伐克裔还是斯洛文尼亚裔？
Are you Swiss-Slovakian or Swiss-Slovenian?
- 斯洛文尼亚 - 斯洛文尼亚
- Slovenian. - Slovenian?
谁在乎你是金发
Who cares. You're blonde.
别这样
Oh,stop.
该死
Shit.
把车停好啊 你这蠢货
Just put the fucking car in park,you dumb fucking idiot!
包都扣不上了
I can't close this briefcase.
哪怕一天
One fucking day.
你就不能保持清醒哪怕一天吗？
One fucking day,you couldn't keep it together?
我不行了 布拉德
I'm fucked up,Brad.
- 开玩笑呢吧 - 不行了
- Gotta be fucking kidding me. - Fucked up.
- 我开玩笑呢 - 开玩笑？
- It's a joke. - It's a joke?
- 我清醒得很 - 老天爷
- I'm sober. - Jesus fucking Christ!
你他妈的开玩笑
It's a fucking joke.
- 我开玩笑的 我又不傻 - 就你还不傻？
- Are you fucking stupid? - I'm not stupid.
你刚才开车跟个疯子似的
You fucking drive in here like a fucking maniac,
知道有多少人注意到了吗？
you know the attention that that fucking draws?
- 你知道吗 我可不傻 - 你聪明？
- I'm not stupid. I'm smart. - Smart?
- 我做的都是百万美元的生意 - 行吧
- I make million-dollar deals. - That right?
我们是高智商重要人物
With smart important people,unlike you.
不像你 吓坏了
People who don't sucker-punch people
你这种人心虚害怕了就知道打人
when they're scared. Okay?
- 我害怕？- 哦还有啊
- I'm scared,huh? - And by the way,
我还没收到你的道歉
I haven't gotten an apology yet for that.
道歉？行吧
You want an apology,okay.
我每天都查语音信箱
I check my fucking messages every day
- 每天下班都查 - 是吗？
- when I come home from work. - Did you?
- 我的答录机 - 没收到啊
- My answering machine. Zero. - Didn't get one,huh?
零个留言 答录机闪啊闪的
I got a blinking light,
因为里面没有你的留言
because I don't have shit from you.
是啊没错
You know what,you got a big fucking mouth,okay?
怎么讲话的 我让我老婆
I got my wife checking the messages
每45分钟就查一次留言 打给我办公室
every 45 minutes calling the office,saying,
我问"布拉德道歉了吗？"
"Has Brad apologized yet?"
"答录机上有道歉留言吗？"
"Is there an apology message on the machine?"
你知道吗 什么狗屁都没收到
I don't have Jack shit. You know what?
你可不能这样对待我
That's not how you treat people.
你这人讲话实在是
You got a big fucking mouth,you know.
我不跟你计较了 赶紧把包给我
I'm gonna give you a fucking pass. Just give me the case.
哦 你不跟我计较？
You're gonna give me a pass?
我不想跟你屁话
Look,it's a figure of fucking speech.
天哪 你真是狐狸镇的国王
Oh,my gosh. The Emperor of Fucksville
把公文包给我 从狐狸镇跑过来
came down from Fucksville to give me a pass!
不跟我计较了
From Fucksville,huh?
狐狸镇的国王不在家
Hey,what are the citizens of Fucksville doing today
镇上的人们该怎么办啊
when their Emperor's gone?
我真求你了
Is it mayhem?
会奸淫掳掠吗？
Are people looting and raping?
这群混账都会干嘛呢？
What are all the little fuckheads doing while you're here?
你他妈来干嘛啊？给我的袋子
Go fuck yourself! Give me the bag.
你这混蛋
You back the fuck up.
你给我退后点
I'll 'cause the biggest fucking scene
如果再让我见到你
that I've ever caused in my life
你再敢打我
if you come at me again.
- 小点声啊 - 你知道吗
- You know what? - Just fucking keep it down.
我明白了
I got...
我也不想躲着什么
I don't wanna be out of line or anything,
但我觉得你是喜欢我吧
but I think you like,like me. Like you...
你冲我来的时候
Like when you come at me...
你看我的眼神 你这人什么毛病啊
What's the matter with you? What the fuck is...
我刚才发现 你好像
and you look at me. I swear I just noticed it.
你他妈的好像
You have like a fucking,like...
朝我抛媚眼啊 你眨眼了
Like a twinkle. You have like a twinkle.
你是想亲我吗？
Are you trying to kiss me,bro?
老天爷啊
Jesus fucking Christ.
- 你什么毛病啊？- 我也不知道
- What's with you? - I have a... I don't know.
- 我之前说过恐同的话 - 行吧
- It's not a homophobic thing. - All right...
你真不是我喜欢的型
You're just not the one for me,pal.
明白我的意思吗？我不喜欢
You know what I mean? It's not...
- 只是你不合适我 - 我受够了
- it's not about that for me,you know. - I've heard enough.
明白了吗 我听够了 求你了
Please,I'm begging,give me the fucking case.
- 我求你了 把包给我 - 包我会给你的
- I'm gonna give you the case. - Give me the case.
- 把包给我 - 你得帮我个忙
- You gotta do me one favor. - What's that?
你拿着这个包
You gotta take this case,
直接开车回家去
you gotta drive straight home,
把包打开
need you to open up the briefcase,
把每一张钞票都拿出来
and you take out every single dollar.
不要留哪怕一张在里面
Don't leave one dollar inside the briefcase.
然后把钞票
And once you have it all
整齐叠好放在包旁边
neatly organized outside the briefcase,
然后拿着钞票全部拿去塞到
I need you to take it and I need you to shove it right up
你那斯洛文尼亚的老婆的逼里
your wife's Latvian cunt,you understand?
- 你敢说我老婆？- 冷静点
- My fucking wife! - Chill! Chill,bro.
冷静点啊 你这狗娘养的混账
Fuck. You motherfucking piece of shit!
给你点颜色
How about now?
- 放手 放手 - 混蛋
- Go,go! - Fuck!
混蛋 操你妈的
Motherfuck! You're fucking dead!
停下 不许动 不许动
Stop! Don't move! Don't move!
不然开枪打你的腿了
Stop,or I will blow you the fuck away!
不然开枪打腿了 把包放下 举起手来
Drop the case! Put your hands in the air!
跪下
Get down.
快跪下 跪下
Get down on your knees! Get down on your knees!
混蛋
Motherfucker!
乔丹 我有个惊喜给你
Jordan,do I have a surprise for you!
什么？
What's that?
20片正宗的"柠檬片"
Twenty real Lemmons.
我有个退休的药剂师朋友
Retired pharmacist's client of mine,
这在他保险箱里藏了15年了
they've been in the safe for 15 years.
没开玩笑吧？柠檬片？
Are you fucking kidding me? Lemmons?
哈哈
Ha-ha!
这玩意能嗨上天了
They're gonna knock us on our fucking heads.
在安眠酮界
When it comes to Quaaludes,
说到714号柠檬片 那可是圣杯啊
the Lemmon 714 was the Holy Grail.
- 你能相信吗 - 天啊
- Can you believe it? - Oh,my God.
我还以为这不过是个传说
I thought they were like a myth.
我以为它们只是传说啊比现在能买到的
Three times as powerful as anything available today.
任何药都要强三倍
Look at these babies.
看看这些小宝贝
Boy,Donnie really knew how to celebrate.
他说他留着这些是给特殊场合的
He said he was saving these for a special occasion.
比如生日或者鼓掌庆祝
Like a birthday,or being clap free,
或者 我们的钱成功到达瑞士的时候
or our money arriving safely in Switzerland.
所以那天晚上
So that night,
我把其他事推了个干净
I cleared my schedule and I rid my body
全身上下清了个遍 以防任何东西影响兴致
of anything that could fuck with my high.
是庆祝的时候了
It was celebration time.
好
Okay.
先吃一片 看看效果？
Start off with one,see how it goes?
我朋友说一片就够了
My guy says all we'll need is one.
来
Here you go.
- 干杯 - 干
- Salud! - Cheers.
或许我再拉一下 就会降落了
Maybe if I pull it again,it'll go down.
史蒂夫
Steve! Steve!
我要下去
I gotta get out of here!
不 我明白怎么做了
Carl,I think I got it figured out.
肯定是拉一下上升 拉两下下降
It must be one pull for up and two pulls for down.
好吧
Okay.
有感觉吗你？
Do you feel anything?
没
No.
已经35分钟了
It's been 35 minutes.
嗯
Hmm.
可能我们已经有抵抗力了
Maybe we've built up a tolerance
这么多年吃下来 对吧？
after all these years,huh?
嗯
Hmm.
扯淡啊
This is bullshit!
我新陈代谢这么旺盛 都什么感觉都没有
My metabolism's pumping. I can't feel shit!
放了那么久
They're old.
你认为他们失去了功能 是吗？
You think they lost their potency,huh?
看看瓶子
Check the bottle!
81年1月
January '81.
居然过期了
They're fucking duds.
真是的
Fuck!
那我们再 嗯
Let's take,uh...
那我们再来两片
Let's take two more each.
- 乔丹 - 你还醒着啊 宝贝
- Jordan. - Yeah,baby.
你们两个弱智在干嘛啊？
What are you two retards doing?
我们在锻炼身体呢 亲爱的
We're working out,honey.
哎 鲍·迪特打电话来了
Well,Bo Dietl's on the phone.
是的
Okay.
- 好？- 知道了
- Okay? - Okay.
嘿 鲍 什么事？
Hey,Bo,what's going on?
乔丹 仔细听我说
Jordan,listen to me clearly.
我不能跟你在这部电话上说 但现在必须跟你谈谈
I cannot talk to you on this phone,
我必须和你谈谈
I have to talk to you.
- 离开这里 - 发生什么事了？
- Get out of here. - What's going on?
听我说 赶紧离开那房子 乔丹
Listen to me! Leave the fucking house,Jordan,
然后找个公用电话打给我 我真的不是开玩笑
and then call me from a pay phone.
这真不是开玩笑的 乔丹
This is not a fucking joke,Jordan.
是啊 行 好
Yeah,yeah. Yeah.
- 靠 - 怎么回事 他说什么
- Shit. - What'd he say?
我真不知道到底发生了什么
I don't know what the fuck's going on.
-我得走了 -没事吧 乔丹？
- I gotta go! - Is everything okay,Jordan?
离家最近的投币电话
The closest pay phone I could get to
在布鲁克威尔乡村俱乐部
was at the Brookville Country Club.
真正的上流社会场所
It was a real WASP stronghold,
离我家就一英里远
just a mile down the road from my house.
嘿 鲍 怎么了？是我 怎么回事？
Hey,Bo,what's up,it's me. What's going on?
我用的是公用电话 发生什么事啦？
I'm at a pay phone. What's going on?
你仔细听我说
Listen to me carefully.
快说 你的好伙伴 布拉德
Please. Your little friend there,Brad,
他进局子了
your little buddy,he's in jail.
他怎么就被关了？
What the fuck's he in jail for?
- 他干嘛了？- 我也不知道
- What'd he do? - I don't know what he did.
我在长岛的一个朋友告诉我
My friends in Long Island told me
他是在一个商场门口被抓的
he got picked up in some fucking shopping mall.
现在关在
He got locked up by...
等等 等等 你说 你说一个商场？
Wait,wait. Did you... Did you say a shopping mall?
- 是啊 - 他当时跟丹尼在一起
- Yeah. - He was with Donnie.
他应该是去送钱给布拉德啊
He was supposed to deliver some money,
- 这蠢货死胖子 - 听我说
- then that fucking fat piece of shit... - Listen to me!
我马上去杀了他
I gotta go fucking talk to him right now!
听我说 不要去 听我说
Listen to me! Don't go! Listen to me.
那个FBI的家伙 丹纳
That guy Denham,that FBI agent guy,
有人告诉我他窃听了
somebody told me he's got your phones tapped.
你家里和办公室的电话
Your office and your home.
别再用那些电话了
Don't talk on the motherfucking phone!
好 我该死 我知道了 懂啦
Okay. Fuck! I got it. I got it. I got it.
乔丹
Jordan.
你之前没试图贿赂这探员 对吧？
You didn't try to bribe this fucking FBI agent,did you?
是的 我才没有要贿赂他
No,I didn't try to bribe an FBI agent.
你觉得我那么蠢吗？才没有
You think I'm that fucking stupid? No.
你说什么？我听不懂
What the fuck did you say? I can't understand you.
再说一遍
Say that again.
我都说了不会的
I said...
你到底说什么？
What the fuck are you saying?
我是说
I said...
你是嗑高了吗？
Are you fucking high?
乔丹 你是嗑高了吗？
Jordan,are you fucking high?
乔丹 帮我个忙吧 呆在那别动
Jordan,do me a favor,stay where you are.
千万别开车
Don't get behind the wheel of the car.
我马上过去接你
I'm gonna send Rocco over to pick you up.
乔丹 乔丹
Jordan! Jordan!
存放了15年之后
After 15 years in storage,
这柠檬片药效来得有点慢
the Lemmons had developed a delayed fuse.
花了一个半小时他妈的才开始发作
It took 90 minutes for these little fuckers to kick in.
但一旦开始
But once they did...
嘭
Pow!
我是说 直接跳过耳鸣阶段了
I mean,I had skipped the tingle phase
开始流口水
and went straight to the drool phase.
告诉我你在哪 千万别开车
Tell me where you are! Don't fucking drive...
这些药片劲可真大
These little bastards were so strong,
我完全进入了新阶段
I discovered a whole new phase.
脑梗塞瘫痪阶段
The cerebral palsy phase.
赶紧的 站起来
Come on,stand up!
好吧 走不了了
Okay,walking's out.
好吧 想想 再想想 还能怎么办？
All right,think,think. What else is there?
对了 我可以爬 像斯凯勒一样爬
Yes! I can crawl. I can crawl like Skylar!
该死 那小妮子爬起来怎么那么容易啊
Fuck! The kid makes it look so goddamn easy!
想想 你混蛋 好好想想
Think,you motherfucker,think!
对
Yes!
我知道了 我想到主意啦
I got it! I've got it!
我可以用滚的 可以滚
I can roll! I can roll!
乔丹
Jordan.
哦 老天啊 你在哪？
Oh,Jesus. Where are you?
我在乡村俱乐部
I'm at a country club!
什么
What?
在乡村俱乐部
I'm at a country club!
我完全听不懂你说什么
I don't know what the fuck you're saying.
不过你得赶紧回来
Look,you need to get home.
丹尼完全失控了 他在打电话
Donnie is out of control! He's on the other line
和一个瑞士人 我不知道
with some Swiss guy. I don't know...
什么？
What?
赶紧让他挂电话
Get him off the phone!
我听不懂你说什么
I can't understand you!
让他
Get him
挂了
off
电话
the phone!
你说什么啊 乔丹
I don't know what the fuck you're saying,Jordan.
赶紧回家来啊？快点
Can you just get home? Hurry!
我离家不到一英里远
I was less than a mile from home.
我尽可能地慢慢开
I drove as slow as I fucking could.
蜗牛都爬得比这快吧
I'd seen Jell-O move faster.
我真的没法给他两百万啊
I was gonna give you 2 million.
我的钱会晚点到
I's gonna be lates.
你吃掉两百万？
You ate 2 million?
晚几天
Later.
快把电话挂了
Get off the phone.
快挂掉电话 白痴
Get off the fucking phone! Idiot!
别挡道 混蛋
Get out of the way,asshole!
你讨厌两百万？
You hate 2 million?
不 你可不会讨厌两百万的 丹尼
No,you don't hate 2 million,Donnie.
奇迹般地 我活着到家了
By some miracle,I made it home alive,
我和车都毫发无损
not a scratch on me or the car.
乔丹？
Jordan?
我该死 天哪
Jesus fucking Christ!
你都吃了什么？
What did you take?
怎么回事啊你？
What's wrong with you?
乔丹
Jor!
这药真是超爽啊 对吧
It's fucking good,right?
搞砸了吧
Fucked up!
把电话放下
Get off the phone!
你搞什么 乔丹？
What the fuck,Jordan?
你可是在自己家里嗑药啊
Your daughter's in the house!
你明白么
I hope you know that!
你竟敢在自己家里嗑药
Your fucking daughter's in the house!
是的 这是真他妈的弱智 丹尼
Yeah,it's real fucking funny,Donnie.
电话快挂了
Get off the phone!
老天啊 乔丹
Jesus Christ,Jordan.
FBI在听
The FBI!
嘿
Hey!
快挂啦
I'm on phone!
快把该死的电话挂掉
Get off the fucking phone!
- 给我 - 电话
- Come here! - ...the phone.
来 我们上楼去 好吧
Come on. We're gonna go upstairs,all right.
噢
Ow!
我正在打电话
I'm on the phone!
打电话
On the phone!
你都干什么了？
I know what you did,
你这人渣
you piece of shit!
什么？什么？
What? What?
布拉德
Brad!
嗯？
Huh?
布拉德
Brad!
你这混账东西
You fucking cocksucker!
你都干什么了
What did you do,
你这人渣？
you piece of shit?
该死
Fuck you!
我真是忍不住了
I wanna fucking kill you!
我真想杀了你
给我回来
I got you!
怎么回事？
What the fuck happened?
噢 该死
Oh,shit!
乔丹？乔丹 你没事吧？
Jordan? Jordan,are you all right?
丹尼？丹尼？
Donnie? Donnie?
丹尼？
Donnie?
乔丹 没有呼吸了
Jordan,he's not breathing.
哦 真该死 怎么办啊
Oh,fuck,I don't know what to do.
乔丹 我不知道该怎么办了
Jordan,I don't know what the fuck to do!
我该怎样救他 哦 我的上帝 乔丹
I can't help him! Oh,my God. Jordan.
天哪 我觉得他是噎住了 乔丹 做点什么啊
Oh,my God,I think he's choking,Jordan. Do something.
- 快帮帮我 - 宝贝 我来了
- Oh,God. - Baby,I got you!
他没有呼吸了 乔丹 快做点什么啊
He's not breathing,Jordan. You gotta do something!
该死 我的天 天哪
Shit! Oh,my God! Oh,my God!
哦
Ah!
我来了
I got you.
哦
Oh!
站开
Step aside!
哦 我的天啊
Oh,God!
哦 天哪
让开点 宝贝
Move aside,baby.
看着我 振作点
Come on! Come on!
赶紧振作点
Come on!
乔丹 他没有呼吸了 你得赶紧做点什么
Jordan,he's not breathing. You gotta do something.
乔丹 他是个父亲啊 有小孩的
Jordan,he's a father! He's got fucking kids!
- 赶紧做点什么啊 - 好的
- Do something! - Yeah?
洛克 快过来吧
Rocco,you gotta get over here.
- 快来 - 叫救护车
- Come on. - Call an ambulance!
我真不知道该怎么办
I don't fucking know!
别折腾了 打911报警
Just get over here! Call 911.
好吧
Yeah.
你没事吧？他还好吧
You all right? He's all right.
贝尔福特先生？
Mr. Belfort?
- 你们来我家干什么？- 该死
- Get the fuck out of here. - Fuck.
先生 我们有几个问题要问你
Sir,we need to ask you some questions.
没开玩笑吧？去你妈的
Are you fucking kidding me? Fuck you.
起来 赶紧起来
Come on,get up.
赶紧滚出我家
Get the fuck out of my house.
- 快走吧 - 我整晚都在家
- Let's go. - I've been here all night.
我整晚都坐在这里啊
I been sitting here all night.
你们说什么呢？
What the fuck are you talking about?
- 你们凭什么带他走？- 凭什么带我走？
- Where you taking him? - Where you taking me?
为什么要带走他？
Where you taking him?
你们根本就没有证据
You ain't got no warrant.
你们怎么能随便闯人家家里
Just come up in people's house like that!
你今晚开了这辆车吗 贝尔福特先生？
Did you drive your car tonight,Mr. Belfort?
嗯？
Huh?
Well?
哇
Wow!
可能之前到家不是那么顺利
Maybe I hadn't made it home okay.
他妈的别挡路
Get out of the fucking way!
傻逼
Fuck!
你今晚
Did you drive
有没有开那辆车？
that car tonight?
- 有吧 - 是的 有
- Yeah. - Yeah,right.
我是有家室的人
I'm a family man!
有家庭 亲爱的
Family man. Honey!
我没被撞死真是奇迹
It was a miracle I wasn't killed,
我没撞死任何人
or that I didn't kill anybody else.
警察把我带走询问
The cops took me in for questioning,
但他们没法起诉我
but they couldn't charge me.
他们甚至都无法证明我当晚开了车
They had no proof I was even behind the wheel.
与此同时
Meanwhile,
布拉德在牢里关了三个月
Brad did three months in jail for contempt
罪名是藐视法庭因为他不肯供出丹尼
because he wouldn't rat Donnie out.
结果呢
The result,
我无罪释放
I was soot-free.
但我被前所未有地紧盯着了
But I had eyes on me like never before.
乔丹 你这幸运的家伙
You're a lucky man,Jordan.
你能活着都是走运 别谈坐牢不坐牢了
You're lucky to be alive,let alone not in jail.
可是我从不相信运气什么的 不是吗？
You know I don't believe in luck,right?
但 是时候了
But it's time.
拜托 让我给证监会打个电话拟个协议
Please,let me call the SEC and cut a deal
在你用光你的运气之前
before your luck runs out.
给爸爸挥挥手
Wave to Daddy.
嘿
Hey.
嘿 亲爱的
Hey,sweetie.
那具体需要什么条件如果我
What kind of terms would you be talking about if I...
我不知道
I don't know.
你有好几次违反证券交易法的行为
You plead guilty to a handful of securities violations,
该死纵股价 施压销售
stock manipulation,high-pressure sales tactics.
各种假冒伪劣行为吧 你知道的
Ticky-tack shit like that,you know.
你付个两百万罚金
You pay a couple million dollars in fines,
作为交换 证监会就再也不会来找你了
in exchange,the SEC fucks off till the end of time.
那斯特拉顿要怎么办？
And Stratton?
斯特拉顿怎么啦？
What happens to Stratton?
那个嘛就没办法了 我是说 你必须退下来 好吗？
There's no way... I mean... You got to walk away. Right?
让丹尼接手
Let Donnie be in charge.
好吧 丹尼
Right. Donnie.
FBI又是另一件头疼事了
Now the FBI is another animal completely.
他们还是会追查你的刑事犯罪
They'll still be pursuing you for criminal wrongdoing.
但是 如果你自愿下台
However,with you stepping down voluntarily,
我猜呢 你那好朋友丹纳
my guess is that your best friend Agent Denham
只能在一边干瞪眼了 玩儿蛋去吧
will be standing around with his dick in his hand.
乔丹
Jordan.
你还有什么要考虑的？
What do you have to think about?
你打败他们了啊
You beat them.
你赢了啊
You won!
老天爷啊 你这辈子都不用再工作了
God knows you never have to work again.
你还想怎样？下半辈子都蹲牢里吗？
What're you gonna do? Spend the rest of your life in jail?
- 你想这样？- 不
- Is that what you want? - No.
- 当然不 - 那好
- Of course not. - Okay.
行了 你把这世上能挣的钱都挣了
Okay! You got all the money in the world.
还想把其他所有人的钱都抢走啊？
You need everybody else's money?
- 当然不是了 - 所以呢？
- Of course not,Pops. - Well?
- 它是我一手建立的 - 这我知道
- You know,I built it. - I know you built it.
你建立的 现在该保护它了
You built it,so now preserve it.
你们知道
You know,
五年前 当我和丹尼
five years ago,when I started Stratton Oakmont
创办斯特拉顿·奥克蒙的时候 我已知道
with Donnie Azoff,I knew the day
总会有自己要离开的一天
would eventually come where I'd have to be moving on.
所以今天我怀着无比沉重的心情
And it's truly with a heavy heart
在此宣布
that I'm here to say that...
那一天终于到了
That that day is finally here.
我想要 谢谢你们
I wanna... I want to thank you all for your...
这么多年来的忠诚和爱戴
Your years of loyalty and admiration.
但是 重要的是
But the point is this.
在丹尼的领导下
Under Donnie's leadership,
另外还有尼基·科斯科夫 罗比·费伯格
along with Nicky Koskoff and Robbie Feinberg
他们会是主要的领导层 这里真的是
moving into key management positions,this place really
或者说肯定会是变得更加无以伦比
is gonna be better than ever!
这我可以向你们保证 好吗？
That I promise you. Okay?
给他们一个热烈的掌声 来吧
Give them a round of applause. Come on.
这里就是埃利斯岛 朋友们
This is Ellis Island here,people.
不管你是谁 从哪里来
I don't care who you are,where you're from,
你的家人从哪里来 从五月花号来
whether your relatives came over on the fucking Mayflower
还是坐的从海地来的走私船
or on an inner tube from Haiti,
这里就是机遇之国
this right here is the land of opportunity.
斯特拉顿·奥克蒙就是美国
Stratton Oakmont is America!
你们都认识金米·贝尔泽 对吧？
All of you know Kimmie Belzer,right?
是的 我们都认识
Yes,we do.
去你的
Fuck you.
别这样 阿金
Come on,Kimmie.
你们所不知的是
What you probably didn't know is,
阿金是经纪人之一
Kimmie was one of the first brokers here,
斯特拉顿最初的20个
one of Stratton's original 20.
你们大多数人认识的是
Now most of you met Kimmie,
今天的阿金 漂亮的精英女性
the beautiful sophisticated woman that she is today.
穿着三千块的阿玛尼套装
A woman that wears $3,000 Armani suits.
开着崭新的奔驰车
Who drives a brand-new Mercedes-Benz.
度假
A woman who spends
冬天去巴哈马
her winters in the Bahamas
夏天去安普顿
and summers in the Hamptons!
而我当年认识的阿金可不是这样
That's not the Kimmie that I met.
当时的她 一贫如洗 身上硬币都没有俩
The Kimmie that I met didn't have two nickels to rub together.
她当时是个走投无路的单身母亲
She was a single mom on the balls of her ass
还带着带着8岁儿子
with an 8-year-old son.
是的 房租欠了三个月了
Okay? She was three months behind on her rent.
她来找到我 请求给她一份工作
And when she came to me and asked me for a job,
以及预付五千块工资
she asked for a $5,000 advance
来付儿子的学费
just so she could pay her son's tuition.
阿金 我做了什么？
And what'd I do,Kimmie?
告诉他们吧
Go on,tell them.
你写了张支票给我
You wrote me a check
两万五千块的
for $25,000.
没错
That's right.
谢谢
Thank you.
你们知道我为什么这样做吗？
And you know why that is?
那是因为我相信你
It's because I believed in you.
因为我相信你 阿金
It's because I believed in you,Kimmie,
就像今天的我
just like I believe in each
信任你们每一个人
and every one of you here today.
- 我爱死你了 乔丹 - 我也爱死你了
- I fucking love you,Jordan! - I fucking love you.
我爱死你了 我爱你
I fucking love you! I love you.
- 我爱你 - 我也爱你
- I fucking love you,too! - I fucking love you,too!
爱你们所有人
And I love all of you!
我打心底爱你们每一个人
And I love all of you from the bottom of my heart.
- 我爱你 乔丹 - 真心的
- I fucking love you,too. - I mean that.
你滚开 你快滚开
You are the shit. You are the fucking shit.
说来羞愧 你知道原因的
It's a shame,you know.
这么多年来 我一直告诉你们
For years,I've been telling you guys
绝不接受"不"作为回答 是的
never to take no for an answer,right?
这样才能步步逼近 永不主动挂电话
You know,to keep pushing,to never hang up the phone
直到达到自己的目的
until you get what you want.
因为这都是你们理应得到的
Because you all deserve it.
我马上要签个该死蛋的协议
You know,this fucking deal that I'm about to sign
禁止我再参与证券行业
barring me from the securities industry,
以及在斯特拉顿的生意
barring me from Stratton,
我的家
my home.
这他妈的算怎么回事啊 你说呢
What the fuck is that,you know?
我这么说吧 这是
I'll tell you what it is. It's...
简直是让我接受"不行"这样的回答 你知道的
It's me taking no for an answer,you know.
是他们
It's them...
是他们卖东西给我 而不是我卖给他们
It's them selling me,not the other way around.
我简直是伪君子
It's me being a hypocrite is what it is.
所以
So...
知道吗
You know what?
我不走了
I'm not leaving.
我真不走了
I'm not fucking leaving!
你没有想到一个好的促销策略
You're not getting a fucking promotion!
表演会继续
The show goes on!
这里是我家
This is my home!
他们得派强拆队
They're gonna need a fucking wrecking ball
才能把我弄走
to take me out of here!
他们得派国民警卫队
They're gonna need to send in the National Guard
或者特警队来
or fucking SWAT team
因为我哪里都不去
'cause I ain't going nowhere!
该死的他们
Fuck them!
乔丹 乔丹
Jordy! Jordy!
乔丹 回来
Jordy! Get back here!
嘿
Hey!
给我
Give me that.
这都什么乱七八糟的
What is this?
老天爷啊 这是上帝的想法吗？
Ramar of the Jungle,for Christ sake?
你看看 他简直是在款待你啊
Paddy D,mazel tov,you Irishman.
他拒绝了证监会的交易
Jordan Belfort just welched on his deal with the SEC.
大鱼回来了 打猎愉快啊
He is back in the ocean. Happy hunting.
是时候开场盛大的派对了
It was our time to party big.
与此同时布拉德也期满释放
And just as Brad was released from jail,too.
我向他道歉 甚至提出用金钱弥补
I apologized,even offered to pay him
他的牢狱时间
for his time in the can.
但他拒绝了 他出狱以后
But he said no,that he was out.
再也不想跟我们有瓜葛
He didn't want any part of us.
不幸的是
Sad thing was,
两年后
two years later
他就死了
he was dead.
心脏病发 才35岁
Massive heart attack. Thirty-five.
莫扎特也是这年纪死的吧
Same age Mozart died.
这并不是说两个人有什么共同点啊 但
Not that they have a hell of a lot in common,but...
我也不知道自己怎么突然就想到了这个
Anyway,I don't know why that came to mind.
没过几天
Within days,
传票就满天飞了
subpoenas started flying.
通知我们提供文件 出席传唤 什么都来
Notices to produce documents,depositions,you name it.
丹尼为此真是喝了太多的水
Donnie couldn't drink water fast enough.
你们说 收到传票怎么办
United States government wants to give me a subpoena?
打搅我们赚钱的传票就这下场
Here's what we do with subpoenas at Stratton Oakmont!
去死吧 美国 混蛋
Fuck you,USA! Fuck you!
去死 去死
Fuck you! Fuck you!
去死
Fuck you!
哦
Oh!
乔丹·贝尔福特
Jordan Belfort.
奥登 好名字
Alden. That's a nice name.
多谢
Thank you very much for that.
- 这算什么名字？- 我的名字
- What kind of name is that? - That is my name.
我不记得
I do not recall that.
真的不记得 好的
I do not recall that. Okay?
明先生 谢谢你今天来一趟
Mr. Ming,thank you for coming in today.
我能吃点丹麦酥皮糕吗？
Are you gonna finish the rest of that Danish?
- 介意我吃吗？- 不 不 请
- Can I have that Danish? - No,no,go ahead.
他们盘问了每一个人
They interrogated everybody.
我思考的时候容易低血糖
I got a low blood sugar,thyroid thing.
调查持续了好几个月
It went on for months.
这简直是骚扰
It was a total fucking harassment.
告诉他继续这问题
Tell him to proceed with the questions.
但没有一个斯特拉顿人招供
But not a single Strattonite cracked.
格拉迪斯·卡瑞拉
Gladys Carrera?
没印象
Doesn't ring a bell.
对不起 我想不起来有这个
Sorry,I have no recommendation of that.
不
No.
不知道
No idea.
我不记得有这笔交易 你们这有牛奶吗？
I don't recall that transaction. You guys have any milk?
绝对不是
Absolutely not.
到最后 你们打了那么多次电话
Francis Sortigi you called so many times
我以为你会记得吧
I just thought you might remember that.
这些你记得吗
Would you remember any of those?
- 一点印象都没有 - 这个阿布杜
- I do not recall any of that. - This Abdul...
我不记得 不 记不起来了
I do not... No,I don't recall.
这个电话打了很久 我只是
It was a long phone call.
想知道你有没有留下点印象
I just wondered if you have any memory of that.
好了 你也知道
Okay. You know we've talked to several
我们跟公司里一些员工谈过
of the employees at this firm
没人记得
and nobody can recall anything
史蒂夫·马登的IPO
about this Steve Madden IPO.
我觉得很奇怪
I think it's Odd.
记得吗？
Do you recall.
卡内基集团？
Cartage Corporation?
嗯
Mmm.
你想起来了？
You do recall it?
不 一点都不记得了
No,I don't recall that at all.
抱歉 我想问问 你那是真头发吗？
Excuse me. I have to ask. Is that your real hair?
这你有什么意见吗
Are you gonna say anything about that?
你是要评论我的头发？
Are you gonna comment on my hair?
我们来这是干这个的？ 这属于私人问题吧？
Is that how we're doing... Is this personal questions?
我只是想你为什么要戴这种假发
I'm just wondering why you would wear something like that.
我敢肯定我什么都不记得
Sorry. I don't recall that company.
还要来点什么吗 先生们
Can I get you anything else,gentlemen?
是的 亲爱的 我身子情况特殊
Yes. Sweetheart,I have a rare condition
需要来一杯
which requires me to drink one of those
每15分钟 请
every 15 minutes,please.
我们被特别奉劝说不要离开美国
We were specifically advised not to leave the country.
所以 我们带着各自老婆去了意大利
So,we took our wives to Italy.
我们觉得在国外更安全
We figured we were safer working from overseas
远程给光头下指示
giving orders to Rugrat.
没人能来抓我们 更没人能证明
Nobody could arrest us and nobody could prove.
我在游艇上管理斯特拉顿
I was still running Stratton from a yacht.
嘿 光头
Hey,Rugrat.
- 嘿 - 你好啊
- Oh! - Bonjour.
你这炸弹头 还好吗
You bald-headed eagle,how you doing?
丹尼 丹尼 听着
Donnie,Donnie,listen!
我们有麻烦了 是的
We have a problem,okay.
你的朋友 史蒂夫·马登正在抛售股票
Your friend,Steve Madden,is unloading shares.
你说什么？谁告诉你的？
What are you saying? Who told you that?
- 怎么回事 - 真的 丹尼
- What's going on? - He's doing it,Donnie!
他说史蒂夫·马登在卖股票
He said that Steve Madden's unloading shares.
谁告诉你的？扯淡
Who told you that? It's bullshit!
电话给我
Give me that goddamn phone.
怎么回事？
What's going on?
乔丹 我正看着电脑屏幕呢
Jordan,look. I'm watching the screen
有大量的史蒂夫·马登股票被卖了
and huge chunks of Steve Madden are being sold,okay.
不是我们在卖 那只能是史蒂夫了
It's not coming from us,so it's gotta be Steve.
只有他持有这么多股
He's the only person with that many shares.
我是丹尼 记得回我电话
It's Donnie. Call me back,all right.
丹尼 你那朋友
Donnie,your little friend
这是要坑我呢 你知道吗？
is trying to fuck me,you know that.
你那朋友竟敢坑我
Your little friend is trying to fuck me right in the ass.
- 赶紧打电话给他 - 我们不知道任何事
- Get him on the phone now! - We don't know anything yet.
我们不要急于下结论
Let's not jump to conclusions.
虽然我持有85%
Even though I owned 85%
史蒂夫·马登蛋公司的股票
of Steve-cocksucking- motherfucking-Madden Shoes,
股份都在他名下
the shares were in his fucking name.
这个贱货知道我被FBI查着
This motherfucker knew I was in trouble with the feds
就趁机占我便宜
and was trying to take advantage.
丹尼 说话啊 你打算怎么办
Talk to me,man. How do you wanna play this?
小淘 你赶紧给所有的客户打电话
I want you to get all our clients on the phone right now
让他们开始卖史蒂夫·马登的股票
and have them start selling Steve Madden.
把股价压下来 知道了吗
We're gonna drive that fucking price down!
你听到我吗？你闭嘴
Do you hear me? Shut the fuck up!
这人他妈的是你的高中同学
This is your fucking friend from high school.
他们这是吓唬我呢啊
If that little fucking prick thinks he can fuck with me,
这是要把整个公司都变成细价股 你懂了吗
we'll turn his company into a Penny stock! You hear me?
- 知道了吗？- 知道了
- You got it? - Yes. I got it!
先别下结论啊
Let's just not jump to conclusions
情况都还不了解呢
before we know what's going on.
船长 泰德
Captain Ted!
电话都挂掉 所有人 挂电话
Hang up your phones! Everybody,hey!
掉头 我们回家了
Turn the boat around! We're going home!
宝贝 宝贝 怎么了？
Baby! Baby,what happened?
我刚刚
I just...
亲爱的 怎么回事？
Sweetheart,what's going on?
艾玛阿姨
Aunt Emma...
等一下
Just wait.
我
I can't...
怎么回事？你为什么哭了
What's going on? Why you crying?
- 她去世了 - 谁？
- She's dead! - Who? Who's dead?
我刚才接到表姐贝蒂的电话
I just got a call from my cousin Betty.
嗯？
Yeah?
艾玛阿姨去世了
Aunt Emma is dead.
- 真没开玩笑吧？- 没有
- Are you fucking kidding me? - No.
真的啊？
You're serious?
哦 我的天哪 宝贝 这
Oh,my God! Baby,that's...
哦 真伤心
Oh,fuck!
哦 亲爱的 这简直
Oh,sweetheart,that's just...
他妈的竟然发心脏病
Fucking heart attack!
嘭 人就没了
Boom,snap,gone.
离开人世的同时
Shuffled off her mortal coil.
还抛下了瑞士银行账户里的两千万
And $20 million stuck in a Swiss bank account.
她之前还好好的
The last time I talked to her she was fine!
- 这真是太不幸了 - 哦 天哪 宝贝 哦 我的上帝
- She's not that old. - Oh,God! Baby,oh,God!
真是太不幸了
That's so fucking terrible!
哦 真伤心
Oh,fuck!
太糟糕啦
It is terrible.
你的阿姨她那么优雅 有魅力
Your aunt was such an elegant,attractive woman.
向你和你的家人表示哀悼
My condolences to you and your family.
是啊 我们被打击得一蹶不振了
Yes. We're absolutely devastated.
感谢你的致哀
Thank you so much for your condolences.
那现在怎么办
Now where does that leave us
那个账户？
in regard to her account exactly?
要转移去遗嘱认证什么的吗？
Does it go into probate or what?
别担心 乔丹 不用担心
Not to worry,Jordan. Not to worry.
你的阿姨去世之前
Your aunt,before she died,
签署了一份文件 指定你是继承人
signed a document naming you as her successor.
是吗
She did?
太好了 那这是好消息啊
Fantastic! Well,that's good news!
其实 还没有
Well,not as of yet.
等等 还没有是什么意思
What does that mean? Not as of yet?
我听不清啊
I can't seem to hear you.
信号不好 你是在说英语吗？
I must have bad reception. Are you speaking English?
- 现在你得赶快 - 赶快？
- Very... Now. Fast. Very fast. - Fast?
赶快？我得现在赶去瑞士？
I have to get to Switzerland now?
说英语啊 他妈的说英语
Speak English! Fucking speak English!
嘿 嘿 闭嘴
Whoa! Hey,hey,hey. Hey! Quiet,okay?
带上西装 带上鸡巴 好吧
Take your suit,take your dick,okay,
- 赶紧过来 求你了 - 好吧
- and move your ass! Please. - Okay.
好 马上出发
Move my ass! Yes!
必须承认 这些瑞士人真是偷偷摸摸的混蛋啊
I gotta say,these Swiss were some sneaky motherfuckers.
几分钟之内他就安排好了
Within minutes,he had me set up with a forger
找人伪造了艾玛阿姨的签名
who could fake Aunt Emma's signature.
你这美国人渣
You American shit!
我需要明天到瑞士
I just had to get there by tomorrow,
否则直接损失两千万
or lose $20 million.
我们现在去摩纳哥
We're going to Monaco!
- 摩纳哥？现在？-是的 孩子
- Monaco? Now? - Yes,baby.
我们现在去摩纳哥 好接下来去瑞士 好吗？
We're going to Monaco,so then we can go to Switzerland,okay?
- 但她阿姨刚刚去世了啊 - 我知道
- But her aunt just died. - I realize that.
但我在瑞士还有生意
But I have business in Switzerland.
并且现在必须过去
I need to go to Switzerland right now.
没得商量 抱歉
Bottom line. Sorry.
我们必须去伦敦啊
We gotta get to London.
为什么？为什么？
Why? Why?
葬礼啊
The funeral!
是啊 但宝贝 你瞧
Yeah,but babe. Look,look...
我很爱你阿姨 全世界我最爱她了
I loved your aunt more than anyone in the entire world.
真的
I really did.
但她现在已经死了 亲爱的
But she's dead now,sweetie.
死人是哪里也去不了的
She's dead and she's not going anywhere.
她还是会是死的
She'll still be dead by the time
等我们到伦敦 是吗？
we get to London,okay?
泰德船长 泰德船长 好吧 看看
Captain Ted! Captain Ted,all right,look.
我们现在得马上去摩纳哥 好吗？
We're going to Monaco. Monaco now,okay?
摩纳哥 是吗
Monaco,right.
我们去摩纳哥然后就可以开车去瑞士
We're going to Monaco so that we can drive to Switzerland
就不用折腾过境的事
so they don't stamp our passports.
可以直接去办事 然后开车回摩纳哥
Take care of business here,we'll drive back to Monaco,
搭飞机去伦敦参加葬礼
take a flight over to London to catch the funeral
三个工作日之内回到纽约
and be in New York in three fucking business days!
就这么定了
That's the fucking plan.
我只想先提醒你一下 可能会遇上大浪
I just want you to know that we might run into some chop.
海浪吗？我们可以开过去
Chop? We can fucking handle chop,right?
这可是170尺的船啊
I mean,it's a 170-foot yacht.
不行 不行 不行 我们不会去任何地方
No,no,no. We're not going anywhere
等他说安全我们才能走
unless he says it's safe,all right.
- 很安全的 - 别担心海浪
- Don't worry about the chop. - It's safe.
海浪你屁都不懂
You don't know shit about chop.
哦 是吗？那你懂啊？你成专家了
Oh,really? And you do? You're a fucking expert on that.
我懂怎么把你信用卡剪了 怎么样？
I'll chop your fucking credit card in half. How about that?
海浪没事 相信我 没事对吧 船长
Chop is fine. Trust me. Chop is fine.
海浪没事 船长
Is chop fine,Captain Ted?
嗯
Uh...
是啊 我是说 如果我们慢点开
Yeah. I mean,if we take it slow.
没错 我们慢点开
Yeah,we're gonna take it slow.
会有点不舒服但告诉她们这很安全
It's a little uncomfortable. Tell them it's safe.
会安全的 因为
It's gonna be safe.
我们关上舱门
We'll batten down the hatches
确保甲板安全
and secure the deck.
我们看一些 可能会摔坏一些盘子
And we're looking at a few... Maybe a few broken dishes.
几个盘子
Few broken dishes.
才打坏几个盘子而已
What's a few broken dishes?
听上去是不是太赞了
Does that sound fucking awesome or what?
不 才没有
No. Not really.
这下要玩得爽了
We're gonna have a fucking good time!
我们走去摩纳哥
Let's go to fucking Monaco now!
赶紧的 走了
Let's fucking move! Let's go!
抓紧了
Hold On!
这他妈的怎么回事
What the fuck is going on out here?
摩托艇刚才掉水里了
The Jet Skis just went overboard!
哦 老天爷啊 亲爱的 你还好吧？
Oh,Jesus Christ! Honey,you okay?
大风警告 大风警告
Gale warning! Gale warning!
海浪有20尺高吧
The waves are 20 feet high and building!
掉头 我们走其他路线
Turn around,let's go the other fucking way.
- 不行啊 - 走啊
- We can't! - Go!
那样容易翻船 那就彻底完了
We'll get broad-sided. It'll tip over!
我是高级潜水员 你们知道吗
I am a master diver. You hear that?
我是高级潜水员
I'm a master diver!
今天没人会死
No one's gonna fucking die!
有我呢 宝贝 有我在 相信我 好吗？
I got you,baby. I got you. Trust me,okay?
我爱你
I love you.
我爱你 宝贝 抓紧了
I love you,baby. Just hold on tight.
好的
Okay.
丹尼
Donnie!
抓紧了 宝贝
Hold on,baby!
丹尼
Donnie!
- 干嘛？- 抓紧了 宝贝
- What? - Hold on,baby.
去拿安眠酮
Get the fucking ludes.
我不要淹死 乔丹
I don't wanna die,Jordan!
我干了太多坏事了 现在要下地狱了 乔丹
I did a lot of bad shit. I'm going to hell,Jordan!
搞砸了 全完了
I fucked up! I fucked up so bad!
去拿安眠酮 在楼下
Get the ludes! Downstairs!
你说什么？
What are you saying?
见鬼
Fuck!
去拿安眠酮啊
Get the ludes!
我不能下去 乔丹 在甲板下面啊
I can't go down there,Jordan. It's flooded.
那里水已经三尺深了
It's three feet of water down there!
我可不能清醒着死掉
I will not die sober!
快去拿安眠酮
Get those fucking ludes!
好吧
Okay!
- 快去 - 好的
- Go! - Okay.
他去哪？我不知道
Where's he going? Hold on,baby!
丹尼 他疯了吗？
Donnie! Is he fucking crazy?
他只是警告大家
He's just warning everybody!
老天啊
Jesus Christ!
抓紧了
Hold on!
离窗户远点
Get away from the window!
我们要被吹翻了
Rogue wave!
五月天
Mayday!
我是泰德·比查船长 娜奥米号需要紧急救援
This is Captain Ted Beecham aboard the yacht Naomi!
- 我们要紧急求救 - 我拿到了
- We are going down! - I got 'em!
我拿到了
I got 'em!
给我
Give me one for the nerves!
我们要紧急求救
We're going down!
这是五月天号游艇
This is a fucking Mayday!
紧急求助
We require immediate assistance!
挺住
Hold on!
小心
Watch out!
被意大利人救起来的好处是
The nice thing about getting rescued by Italians
他们给你好吃的 还有红酒喝
is that they feed you,make you drink red wine,
还能跳舞
then you get to dance.
看见了吗？
Did you see that?
那是我本来安排好来接我们的飞机
That was the plane I sent to come get us.
真不是骗人 它爆了
I shit you not,it exploded
有一只海鸥飞到了引擎里
when a seagull flew into the engine.
三人死亡
Three people killed.
好比一直在等上帝有所指示
You want a sign from God?
发生了这一切之后我终于是懂了
Well,after all this,I finally got the message.
新的梦想 你希望变得经济独立
Do you dream of becoming financially independent
但每个月都在为各种账单挣扎
but struggle every month just to pay your bills?
想要这样的房子吗？
Would you like to own a home like this,
而你都快付不起房租了
but can barely afford to pay your rent?
我是乔丹·贝尔福特
My name is Jordan Belfort,
想创造财富是没有秘密的
and there's no secret to wealth creation.
不管你是谁
No matter who you are,
从哪里来
no matter where you came from,
你也可以变得经济独立
you too can become financially independent
在短短的几个月内
in just a matter of months.
只需好的谋略
All you need is a strategy.
我24岁的时候
When I was 24 years old,
做了个决定不仅仅要活着 还要活得漂亮
I made a decision not just to survive,but to thrive.
一开始我觉得这种事是不可能的
At first I didn't feel like deals like these were possible.
但我们现在有了房子 还挣了三万三千块
But we have the house and we have a $33,000 profit.
现在我完全相信了
I certainly believe now.
我想了想
Think about it for a second.
如果你不敢拨打乔丹·贝尔福特的直线
If you don't have the guts to attend Jordan Belfort's.
参加他们的研讨会
Straight Line Persuasion System seminar,
那你想怎么挣钱
then how do you expect to make any money?
你以后想有一天成为百万富翁
If you want to be a millionaire someday,
那就拿点胆量出来 做点决定
have some guts. Make a decision.
乔丹·贝尔福特说这对我有用
Jordan Belfort's setup worked for me
因为是我努力得来的
because I worked hard for it.
如果对你没用
And if it doesn't work for you,
说明你很懒
it's because you're lazy.
你应该去麦当劳打工
And you should get a job at McDonald's.
没有人能阻止你经济上的自由
There's nobody holding you back from financial freedom.
也没有人能阻止你挣好几百万
And there's nobody stopping you from making millions.
别坐家里
Don't just sit at home,
否则梦想的生活就要擦肩而过
or the life of your dreams will sail right past you.
我改变了这些人的生活
I changed all these people's lives
也能改变你的
and I can change yours,too!
参加我的研讨会
So come to my seminar!
你梦想的生活
The life of your dreams is only...
乔丹 好久不见
Good to see you again,Jordan.
你被捕了
You're under arrest!
开玩笑吧
You gotta be joking!
别开玩笑
You're kidding me.
嘿 让他妈的远离我
Hey,get the fuck away from me!
把摄像机关了
Turn that camera off.
我在拍广告片
I'm fucking shooting a fucking infomercial here,
该死你妈的你这混蛋
you fucking cocksucker!
- 去你妈的 你混蛋 - 关掉该死的相机
- Fuck you,you motherfucker! - Shut the fucking camera off.
你不要欺骗我 听到我没
You don't got shit on me,you hear me!
你这人渣
Go fuck yourself!
我挣得是良心钱 你个人渣
I'm making an honest living,you fucking piece of shit!
嘿 乔丹
Hey,Jordan,
你有权保持沉默
let me give you a little legal advice.
闭上你的嘴
Shut the fuck up!
哦 去你妈的 你混蛋
Oh,fuck you,you fucking prick
我挣得是良心钱 你混蛋
I'm making an honest living,you motherfucker!
我已行为检点
I clean up my act.
进行了康复治疗 现在是电视名人
I did rehab. I'm a TV personality.
已经两年没吸毒 结果发生这破事
I'm sober for two years. And this happens!
光头在迈阿密被捕了
Rugrat goes and gets busted down in Miami.
我是瑞士 我不是共产主义者
I'm Swiss,I'm not communist.
猜猜谁一起被捕了？苏瑞尔
And guess who the fuck with? Saurel.
- 你要打我？- 不 先生
- You gonna beat me? - No,Sir.
是的 我知道你的国家 你会打我
Yeah,I know your country. You're gonna beat me.
这几率是怎么回事啊？
I mean,what are the fucking odds?
日内瓦银行家都有上万个吧
There had to be 10,000 Swiss bankers in Geneva,
光头这蠢货竟然
and Rugrat gets the one dumb enough
让自己在美国被抓了
to get himself arrested on U. S. soil.
我知道
I know.
对不起
I'm so sorry.
更该死蛋的是
Even more fucked
他被抓的理由
was that he got busted.
跟我一点关系都没有
for shit that had nothing to do with me.
该死 跟我一点关系都没有
It had nothing to fucking do with me.
是有人贩毒要洗钱
Something about laundering drug money
靠搞什么海上赛艇 一个叫青木洛基的人
through offshore boat racing and a guy named Rocky Aoki,
就是那个开日式铁板烧连锁店"红花"的
you know,the founder of Benihana.
红花？
Benihana.
该死的红花
Beni-fucking-Hana!
为什么？
Why?
为什么 为什么啊 上天对我不公
Why,why,God?
你干嘛这么残酷啊
Why would you be so cruel
找一家烤肉店来
as to choose a chain of fucking hibachi restaurants
拖我下水？
to take me down?
长话短说就是 苏瑞尔供出了我
Long story short. Saurel rats me out.
但先供出的是布拉德的老婆 香特尔
But not before he rats out Brad's wife,Chantalle,
谁 原来一直跟他
who,it turns out,he'd been fucking
她每次去瑞士
every time she went to Switzerland!
- 不 不 不 这是不可能的 - 是的 是的 是的
- No,no,no,it's impossible. - Oui,oui,oui.
- 好吧 - 啊
- All right! - Ah!
罪名：合谋证券欺诈一项
One count engaging in conspiracy to commit securities fraud.
两项证券诈骗
Two counts securities fraud.
合谋参与洗钱一项
One count engaging in conspiracy to commit money laundering.
21项洗钱
Twenty-one counts money laundering.
还有一次干扰司法
One count obstruction of justice.
保释金一千万美元
Bail is set at $10 million.
丹尼叔叔来了
Uncle Donnie's here!
洛基 你好吗
Rocky. How you doing?
我真是讨厌那条狗
Woof. I hate that fucking dog.
是啊 它年纪大了
Yeah,he's getting old and decrepit.
又开始在家里随便拉屎了
Starting to shit in the house again.
- 我也是 - 过来
- Me,too. - Come here,buddy.
哦 真是的
Ah,fuck.
- 很高兴见到你 朋友 - 是的 我也是
- It's good to see you,pal. - Yeah,you,too.
见到你真好
Good to see you.
坐下吧 哦 伙计
Sit down. Oh,man.
你还好吗 老兄
How you doing,brother?
你知道的
You know.
烂透了 朋友
Shitty,pal.
但我坚持着呢
But I'm hanging in there.
瞧瞧我的新首饰
My new piece of jewelry. Check that out.
不能离开家门半步
Can't leave the house,you know?
这玩意会报警
Starting to get cabin fever already.
该死的光头
Fucking Rugrat.
这戴假发的基佬
That wig-wearing faggot.
真不敢相信他怎么还没死啊
I can't believe that fucking guy. I wanna kill him.
等他放出来我有他好看
Swear to God,I want to choke him to death.
不负责任的傻逼
Irresponsible little prick.
我这么告诉你吧
I'll tell you one thing.
我再也不会去吃红花烧烤了
I'm never eating at Benihana again.
才不管是谁过生日
I don't care whose birthday it is.
娜奥米怎么样了？
Where's Naomi? How's she doing?
她在家呢 就在那
That's her in the house there.
你可以打个招呼 她八成不会理你
You could say hi,but she probably won't wave back.
娜奥米 亲爱的
Naomi,sweetheart!
怎么回事
What's up her ass?
- 她生我的气干嘛？- 没有 她就这样
- Is she mad at me? - No,you know...
我们大概得把房子抵押了
We probably have to mortgage the house
才能付得起保释金
in order to make bail.
可能还要卖点东西
Probably end up selling the thing
来付律师费
in order to pay for all the lawyers.
真的是噩梦啊 实话实说
It's been a nightmare,buddy,to tell you the truth.
你要做什么 对吗？
What are you gonna do,right?
斯特拉顿 怎样了？这才是重点
Anyway,how's Stratton? That's more important.
大家情绪如何？
How's morale?
是不是气坏了 现在只能合法地挣钱了
They all pissed off 'cause they have to make money legally now?
- 乔丹 - 嗯
- Jordan. - Hmm?
我召集了创始合伙人
I got the founding partners together.
把这些事都告诉了他们
I talked to them about everything.
你有我呢
And I got you.
什么意思？
What do you mean,you got me?
房子和钱的事你不必担心 有我呢
The house,money,don't worry about it. I got you.
好的
All right.
我真爱你 兄弟
I love you,buddy.
- 你知道是我也会这样做 对吧？- 我知道？
- You know I'd do it for you,right? - I know.
- 你知道 对吗？- 我知道
- You know that,right? - I know.
真想亲你
I could fucking kiss you all over.
好了 行了 行了
All right,enough,enough.
想喝啤酒吗？
You want a beer,pal?
你在喝什么？
What are you drinking?
我有这个无酒精的东西
I got this non-alcoholic shit.
这什么啊？
What's that?
无酒精啤酒 里面不含酒精的
A non-alcoholic beer. It's got no alcohol.
- 这是啤酒？- 是啊 只不过没有酒精
- It's a beer? - Yeah,with no alcohol.
但如果喝得够多 还是能喝高吧
But if you drink enough,
如果你喝很多 还是能喝高吧？
if you drink a lot,they get you fucked up?
不会啊 它没酒精不是吗 只有一点点
No,there's no alcohol. That's the fucking point.
我又不是科学家
I'm not a scientist.
不懂这个不知道你们在说什么
I don't know what the fuck you're talking about.
不过如果你想喝我可以给你弄来
I can get you a beer if you want a fucking beer.
我知道 但我不喝了 你记得的
I know,but I don't drink. You remember?
我已经戒酒了
I don't drink anymore.
哦 你想进去
Oh,you wanna go inside
还要进去抽点石灰？
and blow some lines of baking powder?
吸点烘焙粉什么的
Or baking soda...
真不敢想象这不胡搞的日子
Can't imagine ever not enjoying getting fucked up.
- 是啊 - 真是爱死了
- Yeah. - I love it.
但我也已经不沾了
How's being sober?
- 真不爽啊 - 无聊 对吧
- Fucking sucks. - Boring,right?
太无聊了 都想自杀了
So boring. I wanna kill myself.
有个词语 我们平时不太喜欢用的
There's a term,and we don't like to use it
除非情况适用
unless circumstances dictate,
我觉得现在这个案子就很合适
and I think they do dictate in this case,
这个词叫格林纳达
and the term is "Grenada."
听说过吗
Have you ever heard of Grenada?
没有 没有 没听说过
No. No,I haven't.
格林纳达非常有趣因为
Grenada very interesting because
它是一个小国家
it is a small island nation
过曾被美国在1983年入侵
that was invaded by the United States of America in 1983.
人口一共九万
It's about 90,000 people.
这个词的意思 就是
And essentially,it means
这个案子我们没可能输
this case is unloseable.
好的
Okay?
所以 你懂得 就算我们把裤子拖了
So,you know,we can come in,
全裸着走来走去
we can have our dick hanging out of our pants.
也没人管
Nobody gives a fuck.
我们肯定赢
I'm gonna win.
而你 先生
You,Sir.
就是我们提到的
Are what's known
格林纳达
as a Grenada.
嗯
Hmm.
你要面临真正的牢狱之灾了
You're looking at real prison time.
嗯
Hmm.
洗钱至多可以判到20年
Money laundering can get you as much as 20 years.
而且如果不小心还发现你在床底下塞了钱
And our case couldn't be stronger if we caught you
那会判得更多了
shoving cash in your mattress.
是吗
Is that right?
嘿 乔丹 乔丹
Hey,Jordan. Jordan.
你要烂在牢里了 两小孩大学毕了业你都出不来
Your rotting away in jail till your kids get out of college,
我们目的不是这个
that's not our ambition here.
还有其他涉案人员
There's other people involved in this,too.
我们觉得他们也该得到审判
We think they need to see their day in court as well.
我怎么感觉你们是在提供交易条件
Why do I sense there's an offer in the air?
他感觉很灵嘛 你是狗鼻子吗？
Look at him. He's got a sense. What are you,Kreskin?
需我们需要他的全力配合 他必须提供
Full cooperation. He provides us with a comprehensive list
过去七年中详细的涉案人员名单
of all the co-conspirators spanning the last seven years,
以及佩戴窃听器
and he also agrees to wear a wire.
等等
Wait...
你刚才是说窃听器？
Did you just say "wear a wire"?
窃听 是
A wire. Mmm-hmm.
什么意思？
What does that mean?
你这是在说让我当告密的？是吗？
You want me to rat? Is that it?
不 我是让你合作
No,I want you to cooperate.
- 不 你这是让我告密啊 - 没错 就是要你告密
- No. You want me to rat,right? - Yes. We want you to rat.
他妈的就是让你做这个 当叛徒
That's fucking exactly what we want you to do. To rat.
克里斯蒂的派对怎么样？
How was Cristy's party?
挺好
Fine.
那就好
Good.
我今天又跟律师谈过了
Babe,I spoke to the lawyers again today.
有重大的好消息
I have some really,really great news.
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
他们说这件事跟你完全没关系
Turns out you're completely off the hook,honey.
我已经知道了
I know that already.
没错 完全正确
Right. Exactly.
你从来都没做错过什么事 对吗？
You never did anything wrong in the first place,right?
原来 FBI只是
It turns out,all the FBI really
想要我的 嗯
wants from me is to,uh,
合作
to cooperate.
你知道什么？
You know?
我掌握了很多信息
Turns out I have so much information
关于股市 华尔街的
about the stock market and Wall Street,
我可以给政府
I could save the government
省下好几年的头痛
years of heartache,not to mention
- 更别提省多少钱了 - 嗯
- countless dollars. - Mmm-hmm.
还有更好的呢
But it gets even better,babe.
因为如果我真的签字合作
Because if I do decide to cooperate,
我可能只要坐四年牢
I might only be looking at four short years,
因为这件事 你知道的
in which case,you know,
这样的话我们可以重头开始 或许可以把房子卖了
we could start fresh,maybe sell the house.
那些罚金都可以
And any fines that I'd have to pay
等到坐完牢再交
wouldn't be due till after I serve my term,
所以我们还是可以留下不少钱的
so we'd still have plenty of money left over,you know?
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
只是这样做还是让我有点不舒服
The only thing that of course bummed me out a little bit
这是整个的想法吗
is this whole idea of having to
告我朋友们的密
give information about my friends.
你也说过 华尔街里没朋友 对吧？
Like you said,"There's no friends on Wall Street." Right?
没错 没错 全是
Right. Right. Exactly.
所以这真是不幸中的万幸了
There's a silver lining to that,too,honey.
因为他们也说
Because they said eventually...
最后不管是谁都要对这案子开口
Eventually everyone's gonna have to give information on this case.
所以到了最后 这很可能都不算什么事
So,at the end of the day,it might not even be a factor. You know?
不错 那的确是好消息啊 对吗？
Well,that's good news. Right?
是啊 是啊
Yeah,yeah.
真的为你高兴
I'm really happy for you.
什么叫为我高兴？
What do you mean,happy for me,sweetheart?
你该为我们俩高兴的吧 是啊？
You should be happy for the both of us. Right?
- 是啊 这才对 - 好的
- Yeah,right. - All right.
过来 宝贝
Come here,baby.
让我亲亲 亲爱的
Give me a kiss,sweetheart.
乔丹
Jordan...
哦 快来 宝贝
Oh,come on,baby.
我们还就没有亲热了 求你了
I haven't made love to you in so long. Please.
- 不行 乔丹 住手 - 快点啊 亲爱的 求你啦
- No. Jordan,stop it. - Come on,honey,please.
不行 乔丹 住手
No! Jordan,stop it!
我爱你因为我看到你的那一刻
I've loved you since the moment I saw you.
我恨死你了 乔丹
I fucking hate you,Jordan.
- 滚开 - 宝贝 别这样
- Get off me! - Baby... Don't do that.
你知道我有多爱你的？
You know how much I love you,right?
别这样 求你了
Stop that,sweetie. Please.
你这么想该干我吗 乔丹？
You wanna fuck me,Jordan?
这么想干我？
You wanna fuck me?
好的
Good.
来吧
Go ahead.
来啊 来吧
Go ahead and fuck me.
你狠狠来吧
I want you to fuck me real hard.
像这是最后一次一样狠狠地来吧
I want you to fuck me like it's the last fucking time.
- 为什么你要这样 -来吧
- Why are you moving like that? - Come on.
- 来吧宝贝 为我射吧 - 噢 我喜欢
Please hold still.
因为我喜欢你为我高潮
'Cause I want you to come for me,baby.
为我高潮吧
Come on,babe.
来看我了 宝贝
Come for me,baby.
我希望你能来给我
I want you to come for me
像这是最后一次一样
like it's the last fucking time.
- 爽吧？- 爽
- Yeah? - Yeah.
来吧 宝贝 来找我 来看我了 宝贝
Come on,baby. Come for me. Come for me,baby.
来吧 宝贝
Come on,baby.
- 好吧？- 来吧
- Yeah? - Yeah.
- 是啊 宝贝 来 - 你想让我来吗？
- Yeah,baby,come. - You want me to come for you?
好的
Yeah.
- 你想让我来吗？- 是的
- You want me to come for you? - Yeah!
嗯？你要我来吗？
Huh? You want me to come for you?
哦 上帝 宝贝 是啊
Oh,God,baby. Yeah!
哦 上帝 哦 上帝
Oh,God. Oh,God.
哦 上帝
Oh,God.
上帝
Jesus.
哦 宝贝
Oh,baby.
刚才真是太棒了
That was so fucking great!
哦 天呢
Oh,God!
刚才那是最后一次了
That was the last time.
这话什么意思？
What do you mean,baby?
我是说刚才那是我们最后一次做爱
I mean that was the last time we ever have sex.
你在说什么呢？
What are you talking about?
我要离婚
I want a divorce.
什么意思 你要离婚？
What do you mean,you want a divorce?
什么意思 离婚？
What's that supposed to mean,you want a divorce?
放开 我要离婚
Get off me! I want a divorce.
你才刚跟我做完
You just made love to me.
这是怎么回事？
What the fuck is wrong with you?
我已经不爱你了 乔丹
I don't love you anymore,Jordan!
哦 你不爱我？
Oh,you don't love me?
你不爱我了 嗯？
You don't love me anymore,huh?
找这借口还真方便啊
Well,isn't that just fucking convenient for you!
我现在被联邦起诉
Now that I'm under federal indictment,
脚脖子还绑着电子锁
with an electronic bracelet around my ankle,
然后你就决定不再爱我了
now you decide you don't fucking love me anymore.
- 是吧？- 不 不
- Is that right? - No,no.
你是怎样一个人啊？告诉我
What kind of person are you? Tell me.
你不是娶了我吗
You married me!
这他妈的什么意思
What the fuck is that supposed to mean?
乔丹 接下来是这样
Jordan,this is how it's gonna go.
孩子监护权归我
I'm gonna take custody of the kids.
如果你答应马上离婚
If you agree to the divorce right now,
我可以允许你来探望
I will allow visitation.
- 好吧？别跟我争 - 哦 我的天呢
- Okay? Don't try to fight it. - Oh,my God.
这能给我们省一大笔钱
It'll save us both a lot of money
我觉得你会很需要钱的
and I got a feeling you're gonna need it.
你可不能带走我的孩子 听见没有？
You're not taking my kids,sweetheart. You hear me?
我已经跟律师谈过了
I've already talked to the lawyer.
他说如果你罪名成立
He said even if you don't get convicted,
我有很大机会拿到监护权
I've got a good chance of getting them.
那我也有消息要告诉你
I got news for you.
你别想带走我的孩子
You're not fucking taking my children,
你这恶毒臭女人 你
you vicious fucking cunt,you!
该死的臭婊子
Fuck you,you fucking bitch!
你不许带走我的孩子
You're not fucking taking my goddamn fucking kids!
听见没有？该死
You hear me? Fuck you!
不许带走我的孩子
You're not fucking taking my fucking kids!
贱货
Fucking bitch!
婊子
Fucking whore!
贱货 人渣 婊子
Fucking bitch! Piece of shit fucking whore!
看看你自己 乔丹
Look at yourself,Jordan.
恶心
You're sick!
你这恶心的家伙
You're a sick man!
混蛋 告诉你了 不许带走我的孩子
Fuck you! I told you,you're not taking my fucking kids!
你以为我会让我的孩子靠近你？
You think I would let my kids near you?
看看你自己
Look at yourself!
你知道我的律师说什么吗？
You know what my lawyer said?
我的律师说你要坐20年的牢
My lawyer said that you're going to prison for 20 years,Jordan.
20年啊 你永远见不到你的小孩了
Twenty fucking years! You're never gonna see the kids again!
你觉得我永远见不到她们了
You don't think I'm not gonna see my...
我绝不让你接近她们
No,I'm not fucking letting you near my kids!
你完全没听懂我说什么吧？
You don't think I'm gonna see my fucking kids again,huh?
你胆敢碰她试试
Don't you fucking touch them!
别碰我
Don't you fucking touch me!
亲爱的 跟爸爸一起出门去
Sweetheart? You're coming on a trip with Daddy,all right?
没事 爸爸在呢
You're coming on a trip with Daddy.
不许你碰她 乔丹
Don't you fucking touch her,Jordan.
我发誓我会杀了你的
I swear to God,I will fucking kill you!
好了宝贝
It's all right,baby.
跟爸爸一起出门玩
You and Daddy are gonna go
一起出门玩 好的
on a little trip together,okay?
- 一个小一起旅行 - 紫罗兰
- A little trip together. - Violet!
紫罗兰
Violet!
- 去拿钥匙 去拿钥匙 - 我拿了
- Get the key! Get the key! - I got it!
乔丹 你打开这该死的门
Jordan,you open this fucking door
- 坐好 把安全带系上 - 腿放进去
- right now! Open the door! - Put your seat belt on.
那就这样吧放好你得腿
There you go. Get your legs in.
我要带她走
I'm taking her with me!
告诉你吧 我要带她走
I told you I'm taking her with me,
你这贱货
you fucking bitch!
你没法阻止我 你没法阻止我
You're not gonna stop me! You're not gonna stop me!
一起出门去 亲爱的
We're going on a little trip,honey.
不要 不要
No! No!
你给我滚开
Get the hell out of here!
别管 宝贝
Leave that baby alone!
把门关上
Violet! Garage door! Close it!
妈妈
Mommy!
- 滚啊 - 把门打开
- Get out of here! - Open the fucking door!
妈妈
Mommy!
不
No!
哦 上帝 哦 我的天
Oh,Lord! Oh,my heavens...
宝贝
Get the baby!
娜奥米 宝贝
Naomi,get the baby!
- 妈妈 - 亲爱的 没事了
- Mommy. - Honey,it's okay.
它会没事的
It's gonna be okay.
哦 先生 乔丹已经失去了他的理智
Oh,Mr. Jordan has lost his mind.
- 宝贝 - 没关系 亲爱的
- Baby... - It's all right,honey.
没事吧？
She all right?
没事了
Is she all right?
你这人到底怎么回事
What's the matter with you?
她没事吧
Is she all right?
第一
Paragraph 1.
被告人需
The defendant shall plead guilty
对纽约东区法庭
to all counts of the indictment
对被控告的几项罪名
currently pending against him
完全认罪
in the United States District Court
纽约的东部地区
for the Eastern District of New York.
第二
Paragraph 2.
说话正常就行
Talk normally.
被告人需参与秘密
The defendant shall participate
卧底行动
in undercover activities...
正常呼吸
Breathe normally.
佩带录音设备
Including wearing a recording device,
也就是窃听器
also known as a wire...
五分钟后 你就会忘了自己带着它
After five minutes,you'll forget you even have it on.
结合调查
In conjunction with the investigation...
协助调查
Fucking brutal.
放弃吧
Quit your bitching.
第四被告人不得有犯罪
Paragraph 4. The defendant must not commit,
或试图犯罪的行为
or attempt to commit,any further crimes.
拜托了 让我把字签了吧 行了吧
Please. Let me just sign the fucking thing already.
谢谢
Thank you.
这儿吗？
Just here?
没错
That'd be good.
谢谢
Thank you.
我甚至都没得选
It wasn't even a choice.
接下来的6小时 我拟了一份名单
For the next six hours,I came up with a list.
朋友 敌人 生意伙伴
Friends,enemies,business associates.
任何在股票行业认识我的人
Anybody who 'd ever known me
或采取股票的小费
or taken so much as a stock tip.
华尔街之狼 华尔街之狼 华尔街之狼
Wolfie! Wolfie! Wolfie!
名单上第一个人就是丹尼
The first name on the list was Donnie.
乔丹 你知道
Jordan,do you know how good it is
你这回来是多好的事吗
to have you back in this office?
你不在这里完全不一样了
It's not the same when you're gone.
难过的时候 你明白吗？这就像
It's sad,you understand? It's like...
那个该死的史蒂夫·马登 嗯？
That fucking Steve Madden,huh?
这我不能
I can't...
我现在想都不能想这事
Swear to God,I can't even think about it.
每次想到都火气往上窜
Every time I think about him,my blood boils.
我都没法提这人名字
I can't even say his name.
- 我知道 - 看起来 好恶心啊
- I know. - It's,like,disgusting.
我还跟他一起长大的 然后他这样背叛我
I grew up with this guy and he betrays me like that.
啊
Ugh!
他会回到你身边 嗯
He ever get back to you about that,um...
那个账户
About that account?
你记得的
You remember.
差不多四五百万吧 对吧？
It was like 4 or 5 mil,something like that,right?
差不多是有那么多吧？
He was supposed to kick back 4 or 5 mil,was it?
其实 我
Actually,I was...
我搞砸了 乔丹
I was fucked up,Jordan,
- 我都不记得了 - 是的
- so I don't really remember. - Yeah.
是啊 好吧 蠢死了
Yeah,right. Stupid.
嗯 如果他打电话来
Well,if he calls you,
记得联系我啊 好吧？
you make sure and contact me,okay?
- 好 那是当然 - 好
- Yeah. Of course. - Yeah.
当然 好的 不 当然不
Of course,yeah. No,of course.
你那最后一块还吃不吃 巴德？
You gonna eat that last piece of yellowtail,bud?
不 归你了
No,it's all yours.
那我拿走了？
Can I get this?
所以 那其他的事呢
So,what else is...
娜奥米怎么样了？
Well,how's Naomi and everything?
你知道的
You know how it is.
她恨死我了
She hates my fucking guts.
海蒂呢？还好吗？
How's Hildy? Good?
她还活着
She's still alive,so
我的日子还是很这么槽糕 你说呢？
my life is fucked,you know?
好吧
Yeah.
乔丹先生
Mr. Jordan.
嗯
Mmm?
乔丹先生 有人找
Mr. Jordan,you got a visitor.
什么事
What?
有客人找
You've got a visitor.
你得去把衣服穿上
I need you to get dressed.
为什么？怎么回事？
Why? What the fuck's going on?
你坐牢去吧
You're going to jail.
好的
All right.
我去穿衣服
I'll get some clothes on.
我们这有人帮你
We'll give you a hand with that.
好吧
Okay.
联邦调查局
FBI!
所有人坐好 手举起来
Everybody sit down. Put your hands
可以看到 统统闭嘴
where they can be seen,and shut up!
不要碰我
Don't you fucking touch me.
把你的手拿开
Get your fucking hands off me!
不要离开你的座位
Don't get out of your seats!
这是该死的香奈儿
It's fucking Chanel!
我供出了所有人
I gave up everyone.
作为回报
And in return,
我得在内华达州一个 鸟不拉屎的地方关三年
I got three years in some hellhole in Nevada I'd never even heard of.
就像我老爸 疯狂的麦克斯说的
Like my pops,Mad Max,had said,
母鸡最后还是要找公鸡（做了坏事就必须承担后果）
"The chickens had come home to roost."
我不懂这什么意思
Whatever the fuck that means.
我希望你能同意
I hope Your Honor would agree
贝尔福特先生通过合作
that Mr. Belfort has distinguished himself
立下了重大功劳
in terms of his cooperation.
他帮助政府
Mr. Belfort has helped the government win convictions
在这一系列案件中定罪了超过20人
of over two dozen serious offenders
并帮忙追回几百万
and helped them recover millions of dollars
以补偿受害者
to be made available for restitution to their victims.
法庭判决
The sentence of the court shall be
被告将在联邦监狱服刑36个月
36 months in federal prison.
被告可以退席
Please remand the defendant.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
好的
That's okay.
斯特拉顿·奥克蒙的贝尔福特被判刑
承认这个也没什么好丢脸的
I'm not ashamed to admit it.
刚到监狱的时候
When we arrived at the prison,
我给吓坏了
I was absolutely terrified.
贝尔福特 起来
Belfort,on your feet.
但其实没什么好怕
But I needn't have been.
有那么短暂的一瞬间
You see,for a brief fleeting moment,
我忘了自己曾经是有钱人
I 'd forgotten I was rich.
自己曾住在一个所有东西都明码标价的地方
And I lived in a place where everything was for sale.
如果你喜欢学着去推销
Wouldn't you like to learn how to sell it?
我这辈子碰到的混蛋可不少
So listen. I've met some bad motherfuckers in my life.
我说的是摇滚明星
I'm talking about rock stars,
职业运动员 黑道中人
professional athletes,gangsters.
我真的告诉你 那些人确实很该死
I'm telling you,some real bad motherfuckers.
但今天这个人 我的好朋友
But this guy,my good friend,
乔丹·贝尔福特先生
Mr. Jordan Belfort,is the single
是我见过最碉堡的混账
baddest motherfucker I have ever met.
所以 我现在想要
So I want you right now
热烈的新西兰式的掌声
to give a warm Auckland,New Zealand welcome
我的好朋友
for my good friend
世界上最好的销售培训专家
and the world's greatest sales trainer,
乔丹·贝尔福特
Mr. Jordan Belfort!
谢谢
Thank you.
把这支笔卖给我
Sell me this pen.
它 嗯
It's,uh...
这是一支很棒的笔
It's an amazing pen.
给专业人士 使用的
For professionals,it's a...
把这支笔卖给我
Sell me this pen.
不错 这支笔真的很好
Well,it's a nice pen.
你可以用笔
You can use the pen
写下自己的想法 就不会忘记了
to write down thoughts from your life so you can...
把这支笔卖给我
Sell me
这支笔
this pen.
不错
Well...
这支笔挺好用 我个人很喜欢
This pen works and I personally love this pen...